<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.480"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.480"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.480/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.480/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.480/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.480/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_56_480">
        <num>56.480</num>
        <content>
          <p>The cabinet may appoint qualified licensed engineers and qualified graduate engineers may be appointed for a period not to exceed one (1) year without obtaining a license, who shall perform duties delegated to them from time to time by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. The cabinet shall prepare necessary plans and specifications, shall investigate and make studies of the comparative need and demand for acquiring lands, or for the construction or reconstruction or structural maintenance of buildings, or the purchase, installation or construction of equipment, facilities or furnishings incidental or pertaining thereto, and shall make the estimates of cost required in connection with or incidental to the development, purchase, acquisition or construction of the foregoing. The engineering staff shall give technical assistance and perform other duties the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet requires. Review of construction plans for conformance with the Uniform State Building Code shall be conducted by the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
