<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.850"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.850"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.850/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.850/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.850/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/56.850/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_56_850">
        <num>56.850</num>
        <content>
          <p>Except as may otherwise be provided by law with respect to the control of real property owned by the state, used by and in the custody of any state agency or institution, the Finance and Administration Cabinet may adopt regulations for the control of vehicular and pedestrian traffic and parking of motor vehicles, bicycles or other vehicles, on, over and across the grounds appurtenant to any building or other facility owned by the state or any state agency. Such regulations may include provisions governing the use and operation of motor vehicles upon such state-owned property, including but not limited to, the establishment of speed limits, parking rules, and for the registration of motor vehicles for parking on real property of the state to which such regulations are applicable. Security officers employed by the cabinet, or by any other state agency or instrumentality authorized by the cabinet to enforce the regulations adopted by the cabinet under this section, shall have authority to remove, or cause to be removed, at the owner’s expense, any motor vehicle parked on the grounds of any state-owned building covered by such regulations, in a manner impeding or disrupting the orderly flow of traffic on such grounds or the movement thereon of an emergency vehicle, or in violation of any traffic control or parking regulation of the cabinet. Moving violations of any traffic control regulation adopted under this section shall be cited and may be prosecuted in the district court of the county in which such violation occurred. Speed limits and parking restrictions established by regulations adopted under this section shall be conspicuously posted on and around the grounds covered by such regulations.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
