<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/58.580"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/58.580"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/58.580/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/58.580/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/58.580/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/58.580/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_58_580">
        <num>58.580</num>
        <content>
          <p>All projects and other property of the authority are hereby declared to be public property devoted to an essential public and governmental function and purpose, and shall be exempt from all taxes and special assessments of the Commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof, provided that the authority shall annually contribute to Louisville, Jefferson County, and the Jefferson County School District an amount equal to the local property taxes Churchill Downs would have paid under private ownership. All bonds or notes issued pursuant to  to are hereby declared to be issued by a body corporate and public of the Commonwealth and for an essential public and governmental purpose and such bonds and notes, and the interest thereon and the income therefrom, and all funds, revenues, income, and other moneys received or to be received by the authority and pledged or available to pay or secure the payment of such bonds or notes, or interest thereon, shall at all times be exempt from taxation except for transfer, inheritance, and estate taxes.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
