<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act name="KentuckyRevisedStatutes"><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title31" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title31" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2023-01" name="publication" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#kyGeneralAssembly" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us-ky" /><akn:FRBRname value="Kentucky Revised Statutes" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title31/eng@2023-01" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title31/eng@2023-01" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2023-01" name="publication" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title31/eng@2023-01.akn" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title31/eng@2023-01.akn" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification><akn:references><akn:TLCOrganization eId="kyGeneralAssembly" href="https://legislature.ky.gov" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly" /><akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" /></akn:references></akn:meta><akn:preface><akn:docTitle>Kentucky Revised Statutes - Title 31: Debtor-Creditor Relations</akn:docTitle></akn:preface><akn:body><akn:title eId="title_31"><akn:num>Title 31</akn:num><akn:heading>Debtor-Creditor Relations</akn:heading><akn:chapter eId="chap_376"><akn:num>Chapter 376</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory Liens</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_376_010"><akn:num>376.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Mechanics’ and materialman’s liens — Filing of statement of amount claimed — Notice to owner or agent — Definitions of “labor” and “supplies.”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_020"><akn:num>376.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien follows property if executory contract for sale is rescinded.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_030"><akn:num>376.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Eviction of owner — Rights of lienholder.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_040"><akn:num>376.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeiture or surrender of lease — Removal of improvements.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_050"><akn:num>376.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage for building or improvement purposes to state facts — Misapplication of proceeds.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_060"><akn:num>376.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale or mortgage of property subject to lien — Proceeds to be applied to payment of lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_070"><akn:num>376.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractor or architect to apply payments to claims — Exception where lien waived.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_075"><akn:num>376.075</akn:num><akn:heading>Engineers’, architects’, landscape architects’, real estate brokers’, and land surveyors’ liens — When lien not required of real estate broker — Filing statement of amount claimed.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_080"><akn:num>376.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien dissolved unless statement filed with county clerk and copy mailed to property owner — Form of statement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_090"><akn:num>376.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on action to enforce lien — Priority of lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_100"><akn:num>376.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of lien by execution of bond.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_110"><akn:num>376.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to enforce lien — Referred to master commissioner — Special commissioner.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_120"><akn:num>376.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to parties of time and place of hearing by commissioner.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_130"><akn:num>376.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Taking of depositions and hearing of evidence by the commissioner — Auditing of accounts and report on claims.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_135"><akn:num>376.135</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on farm crop for service by custom operator.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_140"><akn:num>376.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on gas, oil or other mineral leasehold — Provisions governing such a lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_150"><akn:num>376.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien of employees on property of a mine, railroad, public improvement company, manufacturing establishment or other business — Of persons furnishing supplies for operation of a railroad.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_160"><akn:num>376.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority of liens — Persons not deemed employees.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_170"><akn:num>376.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of income when operation of property is continued.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_180"><akn:num>376.180</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien attaches when business is transferred, suspended or attached — Enforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_190"><akn:num>376.190</akn:num><akn:heading>Joinder of parties — Limitation on action or filing of claim for lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_195"><akn:num>376.195</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 376.195 and 376.210.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_200"><akn:num>376.200</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 376.210 to 376.260.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_205"><akn:num>376.205</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for labor, materials or supplies furnished on public improvement — Assertion, filing and enforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_210"><akn:num>376.210</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for labor, material, or supplies furnished on public improvement — Assertion, filing, and enforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_212"><akn:num>376.212</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond to discharge lien created by KRS 376.210 — Requirements — Liability of obligors on bond.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_220"><akn:num>376.220</akn:num><akn:heading>Limit of amount of lien — Pro rata distribution — Liability for filing claim in excess of amount due.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_230"><akn:num>376.230</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien dissolved unless statement timely filed with county clerk — Form and content of statement — Duties and fees of clerk.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_240"><akn:num>376.240</akn:num><akn:heading>Perfecting a lien on funds due contractor from public authority.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_250"><akn:num>376.250</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding by public authority of funds due contractor and their payment to lien claimant — Protest by contractor — Suit by lien claimant.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_260"><akn:num>376.260</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to enforce lien — Notice — Limitation — Proof of use of materials.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_265"><akn:num>376.265</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on real property for service to retail business by municipal utility — Priority — Statement of lien — Action to enforce — Release of lien by execution of bond.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_268"><akn:num>376.268</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 376.270 and 376.275.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_270"><akn:num>376.270</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on motor vehicle for repairs, storage or accessories — Filing of statement with county clerk.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_272"><akn:num>376.272</akn:num><akn:heading>Marina may enforce lien on boat asserted pursuant to KRS 376.270 by civil action.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_275"><akn:num>376.275</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on motor vehicles and contents for reasonable and applicable charges under KRS 281.920 to 281.936 — Forfeiture and sale of contents — Exempted contents — Limitation of storage or towing company’s liability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_280"><akn:num>376.280</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of boat or motor vehicle for charges — Advertisement of sale — Definition of “boat.”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_281"><akn:num>376.281</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on aircraft for storage, repairs or accessories.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_290"><akn:num>376.290</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on watches and jewelry for repairs — Sale for charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_300"><akn:num>376.300</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien of dry cleaner, launderer, or tailor on article for work done — Sale for charges — Notification and criteria for sale.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_310"><akn:num>376.310</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for storage and services on article prior to storage — Sale for charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_320"><akn:num>376.320</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of sale of article for charges — Distribution of proceeds.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_330"><akn:num>376.330</akn:num><akn:heading>Posting of notices necessary to claim liens.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_340"><akn:num>376.340</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien of keeper of hotel, inn, boarding house or house of private entertainment on personal property of guest for charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_350"><akn:num>376.350</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of lien on property of guest.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_360"><akn:num>376.360</akn:num><akn:heading>Liens on steamboats and other vessels for work and supplies.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_370"><akn:num>376.370</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for damage done by vessel.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_380"><akn:num>376.380</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of lien and liability against vessel.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_390"><akn:num>376.390</akn:num><akn:heading>Joinder of lienholders as plaintiffs — When lien may be enforced against purchaser without notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_400"><akn:num>376.400</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien of keeper of livery stable or agister for care of livestock — Sale of livestock cared for — Conditions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_410"><akn:num>376.410</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of lien for care of livestock.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_420"><akn:num>376.420</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for service fee of stallion, jack, or bull — Enforcement of lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_430"><akn:num>376.430</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on radios, phonographs and other electrical or electronic devices, for repair.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_435"><akn:num>376.435</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on die, mold, form, or pattern — Respective rights of molder and customer.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_440"><akn:num>376.440</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on equipment, machinery and motors for work and supplies — Filing of lien statement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_445"><akn:num>376.445</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of lien statement — Indorsement and filing by county clerk — Fee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_450"><akn:num>376.450</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien inferior to mortgage or sale unless statement filed.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_455"><akn:num>376.455</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of equipment, machinery or motor to pay charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_460"><akn:num>376.460</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney’s lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_470"><akn:num>376.470</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterinarian’s lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_475"><akn:num>376.475</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing requirement — Indexing — Dissolution for nonenforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_480"><akn:num>376.480</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for rent due on space for parking abandoned house trailer or mobile home — Sale of abandoned property.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_990"><akn:num>376.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_010"><akn:num>376.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Mechanics’ and materialman’s liens — Filing of statement of amount claimed — Notice to owner or agent — Definitions of “labor” and “supplies.”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_010__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who performs labor or furnishes materials, for the erection, altering, or repairing of a house or other structure or for any fixture or machinery therein, for the excavation of cellars, cisterns, vaults, wells, or for the improvement in any manner of real property including the furnishing of agricultural lime, fertilizer, concrete pipe or drainage tile, crushed rock, gravel for roads or driveways, and materials used in the construction or maintenance of fences, by contract with, or by the written consent of, the owner, contractor, subcontractor, architect, or authorized agent, shall have a lien thereon, and upon the land upon which the improvements were made or on any interest the owner has therein, to secure the amount thereof with interest as provided in KRS 360.040 and costs. The lien on the land or improvements shall be superior to any mortgage or encumbrance created subsequent to the beginning of the labor or the furnishing of the materials, and the lien, if asserted as hereinafter provided, shall relate back and take effect from the time of the commencement of the labor or the furnishing of the materials. The lien shall not be for a greater amount in the aggregate than the contract price of the original contractor, and should the aggregate amount of the liens exceed the price agreed upon between the original contractor and the owner there shall be a pro rata distribution of the original contract price among the lienholders.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_010__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The lien shall not take precedence over a mortgage or other contract lien or bona fide conveyance for value without notice, duly recorded or lodged for record according to law, unless the person claiming the prior lien shall, before the recording of the mortgage or other contract lien or conveyance, file in the office of the county clerk of the county wherein he has furnished or expects to furnish labor or materials, a statement showing that he has furnished or expects to furnish labor or materials, and the amount in full thereof. The lien shall not, as against the holder of a mortgage or other contract lien or conveyance, exceed the amount of the lien claimed or expected to be claimed as set forth in the statement. The statement shall, in other respects, be in the form prescribed by KRS 376.080.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_010__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No person who has not contracted directly with the owner or his agent shall acquire a lien under this section unless he notifies in writing the owner of the property to be held liable or his authorized agent, within seventy-five (75) days on claims amounting to less than $1,000 and one hundred twenty (120) days on claims in excess of $1,000 after the last item of material or labor is furnished, of his intention to hold the property liable and the amount for which he will claim a lien. It shall be sufficient to prove that the notice was mailed to the last known address of the owner of the property upon which the lien is claimed, or to his duly authorized agent within the county in which the property to be held liable is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_010__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No person who has not contracted directly with the owner or his authorized agent shall acquire a lien under this section on an owner-occupied single or double family dwelling, the appurtenances or additions thereto, or upon other improvements for agricultural or personal use to the real property or real property contiguous thereto and held by the same owner, upon which the owner-occupant’s dwelling is located, unless he notifies in writing the owner of the property to be held liable or his authorized agent not more than seventy-five (75) days after the last item of material or labor is furnished, of the delivery of the material or performance of labor and of his intention to hold the property liable and the amount for which he will claim a lien. It shall be sufficient to prove that the notice was mailed to the last known address of the owner of the property upon which the lien is claimed, or to his duly authorized agent. This notice is in lieu of the notice provided for in subsection (3). Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this subsection, the lien provided for under this section shall not be applicable to the extent that an owner-occupant of a single or double family dwelling or owner of other property as described in this subsection has, prior to receipt of the notice provided for in this subsection, paid the contractor, subcontractor, architect, or authorized agent for work performed or materials furnished prior to such payment. The contractor or subcontractor cannot be the authorized agent under this subsection. This subsection shall apply to the construction of single or double family homes constructed pursuant to a construction contract with a property owner and intended for use as the property owner’s dwelling.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_010__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of this section, “labor” includes but is not limited to all supplies and work done by teams, trucks, machinery, and mechanical equipment, whether the owner furnishes a driver or operator or not.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_010__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)“Supplies” includes small tools and equipment reasonably necessary in performing the work required to be done, including picks, shovels, sledge hammers, axes, pulleys, wire cables, ropes, and other similar items costing not more than fifty dollars ($50) per item, and tires and tubes furnished for use on vehicles engaged in the performance of the work.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)“Supplies” also includes the cost of labor, materials, and repair parts supplied or furnished for keeping all machinery and equipment used in the performance of the work in good operating condition; and shall include the agreed or reasonable rental price of equipment and machinery used in performing the work to be done: 1.The lien for rental equipment or machinery shall not be more than the aggregate sum of six (6) months’ rental, and the aggregate amount of such rental shall not exceed sixty percent (60%) of the agreed value of the machinery or equipment; and 2.The liens for supplies as defined in this subsection are subordinate to the liens for labor, material, and supplies as defined in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_020"><akn:num>376.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien follows property if executory contract for sale is rescinded.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the owner claims by executory contract and for any cause the contract is rescinded or set aside, the lien provided for in KRS 376.010 shall follow the property into the hands of the person to whom the property may come or with whom it may remain by reason of the rescissions, but only to the extent that the actual value of the property is enhanced by the improvements so placed upon it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_030"><akn:num>376.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Eviction of owner — Rights of lienholder.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the owner or claimant of the property is evicted from possession by the judgment of a court, and is entitled to compensation for improvements, the holder of a lien under KRS 376.010 shall, to the extent of the lien, debt and costs, be substituted to the rights of the person evicted and shall have satisfaction of his debt and costs out of the sum adjudged for improvements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_040"><akn:num>376.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeiture or surrender of lease — Removal of improvements.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If labor is performed or materials furnished by contract with the lessee of real property for a term of years, and if before the expiration of the term by lapse of time the lessee’s interest therein shall, from any cause, be forfeited or surrendered to the lessor, and if the lessor refuses to pay for the labor or materials furnished, the person furnishing the labor or materials may remove the same from the premises, if this can be done without material injury to any previous improvement on the premises.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_050"><akn:num>376.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage for building or improvement purposes to state facts — Misapplication of proceeds.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_050__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any mortgage taken to secure a loan made for the purpose of erecting, improving or adding to a building shall state such facts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_050__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No person shall willfully misappropriate or misapply the proceeds received from such a loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_060"><akn:num>376.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale or mortgage of property subject to lien — Proceeds to be applied to payment of lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the owner of any legal or equitable interest in land or improvements thereon contracts for labor or material used in the erection, repair or improvement of any structure thereon under such circumstances that a lien for the payment therefor may attach to the property, and sells or mortgages the property before the expiration of the time provided for the filing and recording of a mechanic’s or materialman’s lien, he shall, on receiving the consideration for the sale or the proceeds of the loan, pay in full any sum owing for the labor and materials, unless released in writing by the person furnishing the labor or materials. If the sum received is insufficient to make such payment in full, the owner shall make pro rata payments on all claims for such labor and materials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_070"><akn:num>376.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractor or architect to apply payments to claims — Exception where lien waived.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_070__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any contractor, architect or other person who builds, repairs or improves the property of another under such circumstances that a mechanic’s or materialman’s lien may be imposed on the property shall, from the proceeds of any payment received from the owner, pay in full all persons who have furnished material or performed labor on the property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_070__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If any payment by the owner to the contractor, architect or other person is not sufficient to pay in full all bills for material and labor, then such claims shall be paid on a pro rata basis to the amount of payments received, unless otherwise agreed between the contractor, architect or other person and the holder of the claim for material or labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_070__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply where persons furnishing material or performing labor have waived in writing their right to file mechanics’ or materialmen’s liens.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_075"><akn:num>376.075</akn:num><akn:heading>Engineers’, architects’, landscape architects’, real estate brokers’, and land surveyors’ liens — When lien not required of real estate broker — Filing statement of amount claimed.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_075__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any professional engineer, licensed architect, licensed landscape architect, real estate broker, or professional land surveyor who performs professional services or services as defined in KRS 322.010(4) for professional engineers, KRS 323.010(3) for architects, KRS 323A.010(3) for landscape architects, KRS 324.010(1) for real estate brokers, and KRS 322.010(10) for professional land surveyors shall have a lien on the building, structure, land, or project relative to which the services were performed, to secure the amount of the charges for services with interest as provided in KRS 360.040 and costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_075__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of KRS 376.010(1) and (2) shall determine when a lien created under this section shall take precedence over a mortgage or other contract lien or bona fide conveyance for value without notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_075__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No person who has not contracted directly with the owner or his agent shall acquire a lien under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_075__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien provided for under this section shall be dissolved unless the claimant, within six (6) months after he ceases to provide services, files in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the property is situated a statement of the amount due the claimant, with all just credits and setoffs known to him, together with a description of the property intended to be covered by the lien sufficiently accurate to identify it, the name of the owner, if known, and whether the services were furnished by contract with the owner or with a contractor or architect. This statement shall be subscribed and sworn to by the person claiming the lien or by someone in his behalf.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_075__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien created under this section shall be dissolved unless an action is brought to enforce the lien within twelve (12) months from the day of filing the statement in the clerk’s office as required by subsection (4) of this section. If the lienholder complies with all filing requirements under this section, and does so within the time fixed, his lien shall be valid and effective against any creditor of, or bona fide or other purchaser from, the owner of the property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_075__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall in no way abridge or conflict with the provisions of KRS 376.210 which provide for liens on public improvements, and any potential lien or valid lien of a professional engineer, architect, landscape architect, real estate broker, or professional land surveyor on a public improvement shall be governed by KRS 376.210.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_075__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No real estate broker shall acquire a lien under this section relative to newly constructed residential real estate unless the purchaser has agreed in writing to directly compensate such broker for performing brokerage services related to the transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_075__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No real estate broker shall acquire a lien under this section unless:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The owner or the owner’s authorized agent: 1.Lists the subject property with the broker under the terms of a written agreement to sell, lease, or otherwise convey any interest in the subject property; or 2.Agrees in a written agreement to pay the broker a fee for his or her services as a buyer’s representative; and (b)The broker or the broker’s affiliated sales associate provides licensed services that result, during the term of a written agreement described in paragraph (a) of this subsection, in the procuring of a person or entity ready, willing, and able to purchase, lease, or otherwise accept a conveyance of the property or any interest in the property: 1.Upon terms contained in a written agreement described in paragraph (a) of this subsection; or 2.Upon terms that are otherwise acceptable to the owner or the owner’s authorized agent as evidenced by a written agreement to convey any interest in the property signed by the owner or the owner’s authorized agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_080"><akn:num>376.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien dissolved unless statement filed with county clerk and copy mailed to property owner — Form of statement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_080__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien provided for in KRS 376.010 shall be dissolved unless the claimant, within six (6) months after he ceases to labor or furnish materials, files in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the building or improvement is situated a statement of the amount due him, with all just credits and set-offs known to him, together with a description of the property intended to be covered by the lien sufficiently accurate to identify it, the name of the owner, if known, and whether the materials were furnished or the labor performed by contract with the owner or with a contractor or subcontractor. Lien statement forms shall require the name and address of the claimant. If the claimant is a corporation, the statement shall require the name and address of the corporation’s process agent, or some other address at which service of process under the Rules of Civil Procedure may be accomplished. If no name and address is included in the statement, service of process in an action involving the real property may be accomplished by serving the person who signs the lien statement. This statement shall be subscribed and sworn to by the person claiming the lien or by someone in his behalf. The claimant shall send by regular mail a copy of the statement to the property owner at his last known address within seven (7) days of filing the statement with the county clerk. Any lien provided for in KRS 376.010 shall be dissolved if a copy of the statement is not sent to the property owner as provided in this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_080__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The county clerk shall endorse upon each statement the date of its filing, and shall make an abstract of the statement in a book to be kept by him for that purpose, properly endorsed and indexed, containing the date of filing, the name of the person seeking to enforce the lien, the amount claimed, the name of the person against whose property the lien is filed, and a description of the property charged with the lien. The clerk shall receive a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012 from the person filing the statement as full compensation, which shall be taxed and collected as other costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_090"><akn:num>376.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on action to enforce lien — Priority of lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_090__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien provided for in KRS 376.010 shall be deemed dissolved unless an action is brought to enforce the lien within twelve (12) months from the day of filing the statement in the clerk’s office, as required by KRS 376.080. If the debtor against whose property the lien is claimed dies before the expiration of the time prescribed for bringing the action, a further period of six (6) months from the date of the qualification of his personal representative shall be allowed within which the action may be brought.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_090__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien provided for in KRS 376.010 shall, if the lienholder complies with the requirements of KRS 376.080 and subsection (1) of this section, and does so within the time therein fixed, be valid and effectual against any creditor of, or bona fide or other purchaser from, the owner of the property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_100"><akn:num>376.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of lien by execution of bond.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The owner or claimant of property against which a lien has been asserted, or any contractor or other person contracting with the owner or claimant of such property for the furnishing of any improvements or services for which a lien is created by this chapter or any subcontractor or other person in privity with the contractor, may, at any time before a judgment is rendered enforcing the lien, execute before the county clerk in which the lien was filed a bond for double the amount of the lien claimed with good sureties to be approved by the clerk, conditioned upon the obligors satisfying any judgment that may be rendered in favor of the person asserting the lien. The bond shall be preserved by the clerk, and upon its execution the lien upon the property shall be discharged. The person asserting the lien may make the obligors in the bond parties to any action to enforce his claim, and any judgment recovered may be against all or any of the obligors on the bond.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_110"><akn:num>376.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to enforce lien — Referred to master commissioner — Special commissioner.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_110__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action to enforce a lien provided for in KRS 376.010 shall be by equitable proceedings, and conducted as other proceedings in equity in similar cases except as otherwise provided. The petition shall allege the facts necessary to secure a lien, and shall describe the property charged and the interest the plaintiff seeks to subject. As many of the lien-holders as wish to do so may unite in the action as plaintiffs, and those who are not plaintiffs shall be made defendants. The debtor or his personal representative or heirs or devisees, and all other persons having liens on or interests in the property sought to be subjected, shall be made defendants. The clerk of the court in which the petition is filed shall issue the proper process against the resident defenders, enter warning orders against the nonresidents and appoint an attorney to defend for them, and appoint guardians for the infants. After the expiration of ten (10) days from the filing of the petition, the clerk of the court in which the petition was filed shall draw up an order referring the action to the master commissioner of the court and file it with the petition, deliver to the commissioner the pleadings and papers of the action, and make a memorandum thereof in his minute book.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_110__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If for any cause it should be improper to refer the case to the master commissioner, he is then directed to select some suitable person to act as commissioner for the occasion and refer the case to him; but before such person shall proceed to act, he shall, before the clerk, take an oath, and execute bond, with sufficient surety, similar in all respects to the bond required to be executed by the master commissioner, which bond shall be preserved by the clerk, and reported to the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_120"><akn:num>376.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to parties of time and place of hearing by commissioner.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_120__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The commissioner shall immediately ascertain the name of each person who has filed a lien against the property sought to be subjected, and fix a time and place at which he will hear proof touching claims against the property. Any person holding a lien against the property, whether arising under the provisions of KRS 376.010 or otherwise, is required to present his claim with the evidence in its support to the commissioner. The owner of the property, or any other person whose interest may be affected by the action, may contest any claim presented.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_120__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person shall be deemed a party to the action, though not made so by the pleadings or by the service of process, who presents to the commissioner a claim against the property sought to be subjected or who appears before the commissioner to contest the claim of another.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_120__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The commissioner shall give reasonable written notice to all parties to the action, and to any other lien-holders known to him or those that reside in the county, or to their attorneys, of the time and place of receiving proof of claims. He shall also post a similar notice on the front door of the courthouse of the county.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_130"><akn:num>376.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Taking of depositions and hearing of evidence by the commissioner — Auditing of accounts and report on claims.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The commissioner shall issue subpoenas for witnesses to appear before him at his sittings, and upon their failure to attend he shall issue attachments as in other cases. The commissioner shall have the same power and authority as an examiner in taking depositions, and shall be governed by the same rules and regulations in respect to the evidence which may be produced before him. He may adjourn from day to day and from time to time, until his duties in the action have been completed and he is ready to report. He shall audit the statements, and make up his report showing the amount due to each claimant, the nature and character of the respective liens, and the evidence upon which each claim was allowed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_135"><akn:num>376.135</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on farm crop for service by custom operator.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_135__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any custom operator who performs a service on a farm, including but not limited to filling of silos, hay baling and crop spraying, by contract with, or by the written consent of the owner or manager of the farm, shall have a lien upon the farm crop involved to secure the cost of the service furnished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_135__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The recording provisions of KRS 376.010 and 376.080 to 376.130 shall apply to the lien provided in subsection (1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_140"><akn:num>376.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on gas, oil or other mineral leasehold — Provisions governing such a lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_140__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who performs labor or furnishes materials, supplies, fixtures, machinery or other things of value to a lessee holding or owning a leasehold, or any right conferred by a lease, relating to oil, gas or other minerals, in the development or improvement of the leasehold, by contract with or by the written consent of the owner or the agent or representative of the owner of the leasehold, shall have a lien on the leasehold or the entire interest of the lessee including oil or gas wells, machinery and equipment, to secure the payment for the labor or things furnished. If the labor or things are furnished at the written request or by the written consent of any contractor or subcontractor, or the agent of either, the lien herein given shall be for the benefit of whoever may furnish any of the labor or things mentioned. The lien herein provided for shall be effective against the leasehold, or the entire interest of the lessee therein, including all improvements thereon belonging to the lessee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_140__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the lessee claims by executory contract, and if for any cause, the contract shall be rescinded or set aside, the lien provided for in subsection (1) of this section shall follow the leasehold into the hands of the person to whom the same may go, or with whom it may remain by reason of the rescission. If by the rescission the interest covered by the lease becomes vested in the lessor, the interest so covered by the lease shall be subject to said lien. If the lessee should be evicted from the possession of the leasehold by the judgment of a court, the lien shall nevertheless be effective against the leasehold and the improvements placed thereon by the lessee or those under whom he claims, while he or they were in possession thereof. If the lease expires or is forfeited, or the lessee in any other way loses his rights thereunder, the lien provided for shall nevertheless be effective against the leasehold, whoever may be the owner thereof, to the extent of the interest held by the lessee at the time the labor was performed or the things mentioned furnished, and this shall be true although the interest of the lessee may revert to the lessor. The lienholder may elect to remove any improvements from the premises if it can be done without material injury to any previous improvements on the leasehold, and when the election is made and improvement is removed the owner of the leasehold shall be given credit by the value of the improvements so removed and the lien-holder may enforce his lien to the extent of any balance remaining unpaid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_140__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of KRS 376.010 and KRS 376.080 to 376.130 shall apply to the lien provided for in subsection (1) of this section. When necessary for the purposes of such application, “owner” shall be construed to mean “lessee” and “property” to mean “leasehold.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_150"><akn:num>376.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien of employees on property of a mine, railroad, public improvement company, manufacturing establishment or other business — Of persons furnishing supplies for operation of a railroad.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_150__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>When the property or effects of any mine, railroad or canal, or other public improvement company, or of any rolling mill, foundry or other manufacturing establishment, or of any other business, whether incorporated or not, are assigned for the benefit of, or are to be distributed among creditors, whether by operation of law or by its own act, the employees of the owner or operator of the business shall have a lien upon the property and effects which have been involved in the business and upon the accessories connected therewith, including any interest in real property used in carrying on the business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_150__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who has furnished materials or supplies for carrying on or operating any railroad shall likewise have a lien upon the property of the company involved in the business and upon the accessories connected therewith, including the interest of the company in the real property used in carrying on the business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_160"><akn:num>376.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority of liens — Persons not deemed employees.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien provided for in KRS 376.150 and 376.180 shall be superior to the lien of any mortgage or other encumbrance thereafter created, and shall be for the whole amount due the employees as such, or due for such materials or supplies. Liens of employees for wages coming due to them within six months before the property or effects shall come to be distributed among the creditors shall be superior to the lien of any mortgage or other encumbrance theretofore or thereafter created. No president or other chief officer, nor any director or stockholder of any such company, shall be deemed an employee within the meaning of KRS 376.150.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_170"><akn:num>376.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of income when operation of property is continued.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the trustee or other person having the administration or distribution of the property or effects continues to operate the business, he shall, at the end of each calendar month, after payment of current expenses and any debt due the United States or this state, distribute the remaining money in his hands pro rata among the persons to whom a lien is given by KRS 376.150 and 376.180, except twenty percent (20%) thereof which he may, if necessary, reserve for contingent expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_180"><akn:num>376.180</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien attaches when business is transferred, suspended or attached — Enforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>When any company or establishment referred to in KRS 376.150 suspends, sells or transfers its business, or when the property or effects engaged in the business are taken in attachment or execution so that the business is stopped or suspended, a lien shall attach as provided in KRS 376.150 and may be enforced by proceedings in equity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_190"><akn:num>376.190</akn:num><akn:heading>Joinder of parties — Limitation on action or filing of claim for lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The plaintiff in an action to enforce a lien given by KRS 376.150 or 376.180 may unite with him as co-plaintiffs any similar lien-holders who consent thereto, and shall make all lien-holders and encumbrancers parties. Where the parties are numerous, any one (1) or more may be designated by the court to prosecute or defend for the same class. Action to enforce the lien shall be filed within sixty (60) days from the date of the assignment, or from the date when the property goes into the hands of a receiver or trustee, or from the date when the business is stopped, suspended or sold; or the claims for which a lien is asserted shall be filed in said time with the person authorized to receive and report claims.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_195"><akn:num>376.195</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 376.195 and 376.210.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section and in subsection (1) of KRS 376.210:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_195__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Labor” includes all work done by teams, trucks, machinery, and mechanical equipment, whether the owner furnishes a driver or operator or not, but it shall not include labor performed by any officer, superintendent or stockholder of any corporation even though he may perform manual labor on the public work;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_195__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Materials” includes all materials of every kind or character used in the public improvement which shall remain as a part of the completed improvement, and all the materials substantially consumed or the value thereof substantially destroyed in making the public improvement, including explosives, gasoline, oil, grease, form lumber and other similar articles; and,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_195__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Supplies” includes small tools and equipment reasonably necessary in performing the work required to be done, including picks, shovels, sledge hammers, axes, pulleys, wire cables, ropes, and other similar items costing not more than fifty dollars ($50) per item, and tires and tubes furnished for use on vehicles engaged in the performance of the work;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_195__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Supplies” also includes the cost of labor, materials, and repair parts supplied or furnished for keeping all machinery and equipment used in the performance of the work in good operating condition; and, shall include the agreed or reasonable rental price of equipment and machinery used in performing the work to be done;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The lien for rental of equipment or machinery shall not be more than the aggregate sum of six (6) months’ rental, and the aggregate amount of such rental shall not exceed sixty percent (60%) of the agreed value of the machinery or equipment; and (b)The liens for supplies as defined in this subsection are subordinate to the liens for labor, material and supplies as defined in subsections (1) to (3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_200"><akn:num>376.200</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 376.210 to 376.260.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_205"><akn:num>376.205</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for labor, materials or supplies furnished on public improvement — Assertion, filing and enforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_210"><akn:num>376.210</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for labor, material, or supplies furnished on public improvement — Assertion, filing, and enforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_210__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person, firm, or corporation who performs labor or furnishes materials or supplies for the construction, maintenance, or improvement of any canal, railroad, bridge, public highway, or other public improvement in this state by contract, express or implied, with the owner thereof or by subcontract thereunder shall have a lien thereon, and upon all the property and the franchises of the owner, except property owned by the state, a subdivision or agency thereof, or by any city, county, urban-county, or charter county government. If the property improved is owned by the state or by any subdivision or agency thereof, or by any city, county, urban-county, or charter county government, the person furnishing the labor, materials, or supplies shall have a lien on the funds due the contractor from the owner of the property improved. Except as provided in KRS 376.195, the lien shall be for the full contract price of the labor, materials, and supplies furnished, and shall be superior to all other liens thereafter created.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_210__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person undertaking or expecting to furnish labor, materials, or supplies as provided in this section may acquire the lien herein provided by filing in the clerk’s office of each county in which he has undertaken to furnish labor, materials, or supplies, except as provided in subsection (3), a statement in writing that he has undertaken and expects to furnish labor, materials, or supplies and the price at which they are to be furnished, and the lien for labor, material, or supplies furnished thereafter shall relate back and take effect from the date of the filing of the statement. In all cases of original construction the liens shall be prior to all liens theretofore or thereafter created on the part so constructed and on no other part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_210__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In all cases where the labor, materials, or supplies are furnished for the improvement of any public highway or other public property owned by the state or by any city, county, urban-county, or charter county government, the statement shall be filed in the county clerk’s office of the county in which is located the seat of government of the owner of the property improved, and the lien shall attach only to any unpaid balance due the contractor for the improvement from the time a copy of the statement, attested by the county clerk, is delivered to the owner or the owner’s authorized agent with whom the contract for improving the public highway or other public property was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_212"><akn:num>376.212</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond to discharge lien created by KRS 376.210 — Requirements — Liability of obligors on bond.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_212__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any contractor or other person contracting with the public authority for the furnishing of any improvements or services for which a lien is created by KRS 376.210 or any person in privity with the contractor or other person may, at any time before a judgment is rendered enforcing the lien, execute before the county clerk in the county in which the lien was filed a bond for double the amount of the lien claimed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_212__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The bond executed under subsection (1) of this section shall be subject to the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The bond shall be approved by the clerk only if the bond is secured by: 1.Cash; 2.A letter of credit from a bank; or 3.Surety insurance as defined by KRS 304.5-060 that is issued by a licensed insurer; and (b)The bond shall require that the obligor satisfy any judgment that may be rendered in favor of the person asserting the lien.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_212__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The bond shall be preserved by the clerk, and upon its execution, the lien provided by KRS 376.210 shall be discharged.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_212__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The person asserting the lien may make the obligors on the bond parties to any action to enforce his claim, and any judgment received may be against any of the obligors on the bond.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_220"><akn:num>376.220</akn:num><akn:heading>Limit of amount of lien — Pro rata distribution — Liability for filing claim in excess of amount due.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_220__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The liens provided for in KRS 376.210 shall not be for a greater amount in the aggregate than the contract price of the original contractor, and should the aggregate amount of liens exceed the price agreed upon between the original contractor and the owner there shall be a pro rata distribution of the original contract price among the lien-holders.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_220__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>On claims for labor, materials or supplies furnished for the improvement of any bridge, public highway or other public property owned by the state or by any county or city, the provisions of this section for a pro rata distribution of the original contract price among lien-holders shall not apply to liens on the unpaid balance due the contractors, except as provided in KRS 376.240.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_220__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If any person files a statement asserting a lien against any contractor on any fund due the contractor, for an amount in excess of the amount actually due, the person filing the lien shall be liable to any person damaged thereby to the extent of such damage, including reasonable court costs and attorney’s fees incurred by the injured parties. Any such claim for damages may be asserted and prosecuted in the county in which the lien statement was filed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_230"><akn:num>376.230</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien dissolved unless statement timely filed with county clerk — Form and content of statement — Duties and fees of clerk.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_230__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The lien provided for in KRS 376.210 shall be dissolved unless the person who furnishes the labor, materials, or supplies shall, whichever is later, within sixty (60) days after the last day of the month in which any labor, materials, or supplies were furnished, or by the date of substantial completion, file in the county clerk’s office of each county in which labor, materials, or supplies were furnished, except as hereinafter provided, a statement in writing verified by affidavit of the claimant or his or her authorized agent or attorney, setting forth the amount due for which the lien is claimed, the date on which labor, materials, or supplies were last furnished and the name of the canal, railroad, bridge, public highway, or other public improvement upon which it is claimed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_230__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In all cases where a lien is claimed for labor, materials, or supplies furnished for the improvement of any bridge, public highway, or other public property owned by the state or by any county, charter county, urban-county, consolidated local government, or city, the statement of lien shall be filed only in the county clerk’s office of the county in which the seat of government of the owner of the property is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_230__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The county clerk, upon the filing of the statement, shall make an abstract and entry thereof as now provided by law in case of mechanics’ liens in the same book used for that purpose, and shall make proper index thereof. The clerk shall be paid by the party filing the claim, and for attesting any copy of the lien statement. If he or she is required to make the copy, he or she may make an additional charge as provided by law. The clerk’s fees shall be determined pursuant to KRS 64.012. All of these charges may be recovered by the lien claimant as costs from the party and out of the fund against which the claim is filed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_240"><akn:num>376.240</akn:num><akn:heading>Perfecting a lien on funds due contractor from public authority.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Upon the filing of the statement of lien provided for in subsection (2) of KRS 376.230 in the county clerk’s office and the delivery of an attested copy thereof to the public authority making the contract for the improvement of any bridge, public highway or other public property owned by the state or any county or city, and the filing with the public authority of a signed copy of a letter addressed to the contractor or subcontractor at his address given in the contract, with a post office receipt showing that an attested copy of the lien statement has been sent by the lien claimant to the contractor or subcontractor by certified mail, return receipt requested or by registered mail, the claimant shall have a lien superior to any lien subsequently perfected on any unpaid balance due the contractor under the contract of improvement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_250"><akn:num>376.250</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding by public authority of funds due contractor and their payment to lien claimant — Protest by contractor — Suit by lien claimant.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_250__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>When an attested copy of the lien statement and proof of the delivery of an attested copy as provided in KRS 376.240 is delivered to any public authority which has contracted for the construction or improvement of any bridge, public highway, or other public property owned by the state, a subdivision or agency thereof, or by any city, county, urban-county, or charter county government, the public authority shall endorse on the attested copy the date of its receipt, file the copy and deduct and withhold the amount thereof, plus pursuant to KRS 64.012 to cover the fee of the county clerk for filing the statement and attesting a copy, from any amount then due the contractor, and if a sufficient amount is not then due the contractor from the next payments which become due.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_250__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Unless the contractor, within thirty (30) days from the date of the delivery of the attested copy, files with the public authority a written protest putting in issue the correctness of the amount due the lien claimant or the liability of the fund for payment thereof, the amount withheld shall be paid by the public authority to the lien claimant and charged to the account of the contractor, which payment shall operate as a pro tanto release of the public authority from any claim of the contractor under the contract for the amount so paid. The filing in the county clerk’s office of the statement of lien provided for in KRS 376.230(2) shall be constructive notice to the contractor of the filing of the claim.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_250__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the contractor files a written protest as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the public authority with whom the protest is filed shall endorse thereon the date of its receipt. The public authority shall promptly send written notice of the protest to the lien claimant by certified mail, return receipt requested and shall not pay over to the lien claimant any of the money withheld from the contractor until authorized to do so by the contractor or until directed to do so by an order or judgment of court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_250__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If suit is not instituted by the lien claimant for the enforcement of the lien and summons in the suit is not served on the public authority or its chairman within thirty (30) days after the written notice of the protest is mailed to the claimant, then the lien shall automatically be released and the funds withheld pursuant to the filing of the lien statement shall be released and promptly paid to the contractor. If suit is filed and summons served within the time provided, the payment of the funds shall be withheld until ordered to be released or paid over by an order or judgment of the court, and then paid as directed by the order or judgment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_250__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>All suits for the enforcement of these liens on public funds shall be instituted in the Circuit Court of the county in which is located the property on which the improvement is made, except where the property is owned by a public university. Where the property is owned by a public university, the suit shall be instituted in the Circuit Court of the county in which is located the main campus of the public university. This court shall have exclusive jurisdiction for the enforcement of liens asserted against the public funds due the contractors, subject to the same rights of appeal as in other civil cases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_260"><akn:num>376.260</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to enforce lien — Notice — Limitation — Proof of use of materials.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_260__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien acquired under KRS 376.210 shall be enforced by proper proceedings in equity, to which other lien-holders shall be made parties. If a court action is filed to enforce a lien acquired under KRS 376.210 and the owner of the property is the state, a subdivision or agency thereof, or any city, county, urban-county, or charter county government, that owner shall be given notice of the court action to enforce the lien, but that owner shall not be required to respond to or participate in the court action. The proceedings shall be begun within six (6) months from the filing of the claim in the county clerk’s office, except as provided in subsection (4) of KRS 376.250.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_260__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If, in any suit brought for the enforcement of a lien, it is shown by evidence that the items embraced in the account were sold and delivered for use on a particular project or public work, that evidence shall make out a prima facie case that those items were used in the performance of the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_265"><akn:num>376.265</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on real property for service to retail business by municipal utility — Priority — Statement of lien — Action to enforce — Release of lien by execution of bond.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)“Charges” means all rates, charges, and other amounts payable for services rendered by a municipal utility, including and without limitation penalties, interest, reasonable attorney’s fees, and other costs of enforcing the lien; (b)“Municipal utility” means any public agency that owns or operates a system or facilities for the provision of gas, electric, sewer, water, or telecommunications service to retail customers; (c)“Public agency” has the same meaning as specified in KRS 65.230; (d)“Retail business ratepayer” means any nonresidential ratepayer of a municipal utility that is in arrears on the utility bill in an amount in excess of ten thousand dollars ($10,000); and (e)“Service” means gas, electric, sewer, or water service provided by the municipal utility.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any municipal utility shall have a lien on the real property of a retail business ratepayer served by the municipal utility. The lien shall be for the collection of rates and charges for retail utility service provided to the retail business ratepayer. In no instance shall this lien attach to the real property of an owner who has leased the property to a retail business ratepayer unless the property owner is responsible for paying the utility charges under the lease agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The lien shall arise and attach as services are provided to the retail business ratepayer and shall remain in place until the rates and charges for the services are paid in full. The lien is deemed a statutory lien within the meaning of 11 U.S.C. sec. 101(53).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The rights to a lien under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Are in addition to any other rights or remedies a municipal utility may have under the law or pursuant to a contract; and (b)Are not intended to impair or alter any of the municipal utility’s other rights or remedies, including the ability to require an additional deposit or to shut off and discontinue service.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The lien may take priority over a mortgage, a contract lien, or a bona fide conveyance for value if:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The municipal utility files notice which is duly recorded or lodged for record according to law; (b)The utility claiming the prior lien files a statement of lien in the office of the county clerk of the county where the service has been furnished before the recording of the mortgage, the contract lien, or the conveyance; and (c)The statement of lien is in the form prescribed in subsections (6) and (7) of this section.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The statement of lien shall be subscribed and sworn to by an authorized representative of the municipal utility and shall identify the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The municipal utility claiming the lien, including an address and a contact person; (b)The property, by legal description, against which the lien is claimed; (c)The nature of the service provided; (d)The contract, if any, pursuant to which the services were provided; and (e)The amounts, if any, due for services provided.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)The statement of lien shall be recorded in the office of the county clerk of the county where the service is furnished or the property or some portion of the property serviced by the municipal utility is situated. The utility shall send a copy of the statement of lien by regular mail, postage prepaid, to the owner of the property at the owner’s last known address or to the address associated with the tax bill for the property. The copy of the statement of lien shall be sent within ten (10) business days of its filing in the office of the county clerk.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)At any time, a municipal utility may supplement the statement of lien by recording the supplement in the same manner as the original statement of lien. Any supplement to the statement of lien shall relate back to the date of the original recording of the statement of lien.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The county clerk shall endorse each statement of lien on the date of its filing and the clerk shall make an abstract of the statement, endorse the abstract, and place it in a book to be kept by the clerk for that purpose. The book shall contain the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The endorsed and indexed abstracts; (b)The date of filing the statement; (c)The name of the municipal utility; (d)The name of the person against whose property the lien is filed; and (e)A description of the property charged with the lien.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The clerk shall receive a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012 from the person filing the statement as full compensation, which shall be taxed and collected as other costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action to enforce the lien under this section shall be by equitable proceedings and conducted as other proceedings in equity in similar cases. The petition shall allege the facts necessary to secure a lien, describe the property charged, and the plaintiff’s interest in enforcing the lien. Lienholders may unite in the action to enforce the lien as plaintiffs, and those who are not plaintiffs shall be made defendants. The debtor or the debtor’s personal representative, heirs, devisees, and all other persons having liens on or interests in the property sought to be subjected shall be made defendants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_11"><akn:num>(11)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The clerk of the court in which the petition is filed shall issue the proper process against the defendants. After the expiration of ten (10) days from the filing of the petition, the clerk of the court in which the petition was filed shall:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Draw up an order referring the action to the master commissioner of the court and file it with the petition; (b)Deliver the pleadings and papers of the action to the commissioner; and (c)Make a memorandum of the action in the minute book.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_12"><akn:num>(12)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If, for any cause, it should be improper to refer the case to the master commissioner, the master commissioner is directed to select some suitable person to act as a new commissioner for the case and refer the case to him or her. However, before proceeding to act on the case, the new commissioner shall take an oath before the clerk and execute bond with sufficient surety. The bond shall be preserved by the clerk and reported to the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_265__point_13"><akn:num>(13)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The owner or claimant of property against which a lien has been asserted may file a bond for double the amount of the lien claimed with the county clerk in the county where the lien was filed. Bond may be asserted at any time before a judgment is rendered enforcing the lien, and the bond shall have good sureties approved by the clerk and be conditioned upon the obligors satisfying any judgment that may be rendered in favor of the person asserting the lien. The bond shall be preserved by the clerk, and upon its execution, the lien upon the property shall be discharged. The person asserting the lien may make the obligors in the bond parties to any action to enforce its claim. Any judgment recovered may be against all or any of the obligors on the bond.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_268"><akn:num>376.268</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 376.270 and 376.275.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 376.270 and 376.275:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_268__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Contents” means personal items located in a motor vehicle, but does not include manufacturer-installed or after-market accessories permanently affixed to the motor vehicle;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_268__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Motor vehicle” includes vessels used or designed for navigation of or operation on waterways, rivers, lakes, and streams, as well as those used or designed for operation on the public highways; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_268__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Reasonable charges” means those charges which are usual and customary, not discriminatory, and which are typical charges for services provided by similar towing or storage companies with similar equipment and facilities operating in the region or comparable-size city or county from which the vehicle was towed or stored.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_270"><akn:num>376.270</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on motor vehicle for repairs, storage or accessories — Filing of statement with county clerk.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person engaged in the business of selling, repairing or furnishing accessories or supplies for motor vehicles shall have a lien on the motor vehicle for the reasonable or agreed charges for repairs, work done or accessories or supplies furnished for the vehicle, and for storing or keeping the vehicle, and may detain any motor vehicle in his possession on which work has been done by him until the reasonable or agreed charge therefor has been paid. The lien shall not be lost by the removal of the motor vehicle from the garage or premises of the person performing labor, repairing or furnishing accessories or supplies therefor, if the lien shall be asserted within six (6) months by filing in the office of the county clerk a statement showing the amount and cost of materials furnished or labor performed on the vehicle. The statement shall be filed in the same manner as provided in the case of a mechanic’s and materialman’s lien, after the removal of the vehicle, unless the owner of the vehicle consents to an additional extension of time, in which event the lien shall extend for the length of time the parties agree upon. The agreement shall be reduced to writing and signed by the parties thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_272"><akn:num>376.272</akn:num><akn:heading>Marina may enforce lien on boat asserted pursuant to KRS 376.270 by civil action.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_272__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any marina asserting a possessory lien pursuant to KRS 376.270 may enforce the lien by filing a civil action in the county in which the boat is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_272__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Prior to filing an action pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, the marina shall send, by certified mail, return receipt requested, notice of intent to enforce the lien to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)All known owners at their last known address; and (b)All secured parties discernible through reasonable effort. For the purposes of this paragraph, “reasonable effort” includes notice to any secured party that has: 1.Properly perfected its security interest in the boat by having its lien indicated on a certificate of title for the boat; 2.Properly perfected its security interest through an unexpired sufficient financing statement filed in the jurisdiction of the boat owner’s residence, as that jurisdiction appears on the certificate of title, or equivalent document, for the boat; or 3.Become a mortgagee of a federally documented vessel by recording a ship mortgage on the vessel pursuant to Chapter 313 of Title 46 of the United States Code. In addition to the notice required in this subsection, the marina shall advertise the notice of intent to enforce the lien at least once per week for two (2) consecutive weeks pursuant to KRS Chapter 424.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_272__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon the marina properly sending notice of its intent to enforce its lien in accordance with subsection (2) of this section, a boat’s owner may not remove the boat from the marina without a court order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_272__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The notice of intent to enforce the lien required by subsection (2) of this section shall include:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The name of the owner of the boat as indicated on the certificate of title, certificate of registration, or certificate of documentation; (b)The owner’s last known address; (c)The make, model, length, and hull identification number of the boat if visually discernable; and (d)A description of any attached outboard motor, including make, horsepower, and serial number if visually discernable.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_272__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any secured party to whom notice was sent pursuant to subsection (2) of this section shall be named as a party in any civil action filed to enforce a marina’s lien under KRS 376.270 and called upon to enter therein and set forth its claim or interest in the boat that is subject to the action, and the secured party shall be served with summons at its address as indicated on the certificate of title, financing statement, or ship mortgage through which its security interest was perfected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_272__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon judgment being entered in favor of a marina pursuant to this section, and subject to any restrictions of the United States Code, or any regulations issued pursuant thereto, regarding federally documented vessels, the court shall order the boat, or any part of the furniture and tackle as may be sufficient, to be sold for the satisfaction of the judgment. The marina shall conduct the sale in conformity with reasonable commercial practices among dealers in the type of boat being sold and in accordance with the court order. The sale shall be advertised in conformity with reasonable commercial practices among dealers for the type of boat being sold and, additionally, shall be advertised at least ten (10) days prior to the sale pursuant to KRS Chapter 424.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_272__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The court shall authorize and direct the county clerk to issue a title to the purchaser of the boat at a sale authorized by and conducted in conformance with this section, and the purchaser shall take title to the boat free of any liens or encumbrances. Any liens or encumbrances attached to the boat shall attach to the proceeds of the sale in the same order of priority that the liens and encumbrances attach to the boat pursuant to applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_275"><akn:num>376.275</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on motor vehicles and contents for reasonable and applicable charges under KRS 281.920 to 281.936 — Forfeiture and sale of contents — Exempted contents — Limitation of storage or towing company’s liability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_275__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)Any person engaged in the business of storing or towing motor vehicles, who has complied with the notification requirements of KRS 281.928, shall have a lien on the motor vehicle and its contents, except as set forth in subsection (2) of this section, for the applicable and reasonable charges assessed in accordance with KRS 281.926 and 281.932, as long as it remains in his or her possession.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)If, after a period of forty-five (45) days, the applicable and reasonable charges assessed in accordance with KRS 281.926 and 281.932 have not been paid, the motor vehicle and its contents, except as set forth in subsection (2) of this section, may be sold to pay the charges after the owner and any lienholder have been notified by certified mail at the addresses specified in KRS 281.928(1), ten (10) days prior to the time and place of the sale. If the proceeds of the sale of any vehicle pursuant to this section are insufficient to satisfy accrued charges, the sale and collection of proceeds shall not constitute a waiver or release of responsibility for payment of unpaid charges by the owner or responsible casualty insurer of the vehicle. A lien on a vehicle under this subsection shall be subject to prior recorded liens, unless released by any existing lienholder pursuant to paragraph (c) of this subsection. (c)A lienholder having a prior recorded lien listed on the title issued by the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall be notified by certified mail within the first ten (10) days of impoundment in accordance with KRS 281.928. Such notification, in addition to the requirements of KRS 281.928 shall include the make, model, license number, vehicle identification number, owner’s name and last known address, and tentative date of sale for the vehicle, and state that the towing company or storage facility seeks to obtain a new title free and clear of any liens, excluding tax liens. If the above-referenced certified letter is not sent within the ten (10) days by the towing and storage company, then only ten (10) days of storage may be charged. The lienholder has the right to take possession of the motor vehicle after showing proof of lien still enforced, and paying the reasonable or agreed towing and storage charges on the motor vehicle. If a lienholder does not exercise the right to take possession of the motor vehicle under this paragraph within forty-five (45) days of notification, and all lienholders agree in writing, the tow company or storage facility may obtain a new title under KRS 186A.145 free and clear of any liens, excluding tax liens. Nothing in this section shall allow the transfer of a vehicle subject to a lien, except as provided in KRS 186A.190. (d)If there are no lienholders required to be notified under KRS 281.920 to 281.936 and 359.230 and this section, and the owner does not exercise the right to take possession of the motor vehicle under this section within forty-five (45) days of notification required under KRS 281.928, the towing company or storage facility may obtain a new title under KRS 186A.145 free and clear of any liens, excluding tax liens.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_275__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to the following contents of a motor vehicle, which shall be released to the vehicle owner or the owner’s designated agent upon request, if the request is made within forty-five (45) days of the date the vehicle was towed:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Prescription medication in its proper container; (b)Personal medical supplies and equipment or records; (c)Educational materials, including but not limited to calculators, books, papers, and school supplies; (d)Documents, files, electronic devices, or equipment which may be able to store personal information or information relating to a person’s employment or business; (e)Firearms and ammunition. Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (3) of this section, firearms and ammunition which are not claimed by the owner of the vehicle within forty-five (45) days of the date the vehicle was towed shall be transferred to the Department of Kentucky State Police for disposition as provided by KRS 16.220; (f)Cargo in the possession of persons engaged in transportation in interstate commerce as registered under KRS 186.020; (g)Cargo in the possession of an integrated intermodal small package carrier as defined by KRS 281.605(12); (h)Child restraint systems or child booster seats; and (i)Checks, checkbooks, debit or credit cards, money orders, stocks, or bonds.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_275__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (2)(e) of this section, any contents exempted under subsection (2)(c), (d), (f), and (g) of this section that are not claimed by the owner of the vehicle within forty-five (45) days of the date the vehicle was towed may be sold or otherwise legally disposed of by the storage or towing company. Any contents exempted under subsection (2)(a), (b), (h), and (i) of this section that are not claimed by the owner of the vehicle within forty-five (45) days of the date the vehicle was towed shall not be sold, but shall be otherwise legally disposed of by the storage or towing company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_275__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The storage or towing company shall not be responsible for contents in a vehicle’s trunk or other locked compartment to which the storage or towing company is without access, unless the towing company intentionally opens the area without the owner’s consent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_275__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply when a local government causes a vehicle to be towed pursuant to KRS 82.605 to 82.640 or if state government causes a vehicle to be towed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_280"><akn:num>376.280</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of boat or motor vehicle for charges — Advertisement of sale — Definition of “boat.”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_280__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any boat or motor vehicle remaining in the possession of a person who has made repairs, performed labor or furnished accessories or supplies therefor and to whom the charges for such repairs, labor, accessories or supplies has been owing for a period of more than thirty (30) days, may be sold to pay such deferred purchase money or charges. The proposed sale shall be advertised pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, and notice thereof shall be sent by certified mail, return receipt requested or by registered mail to the owner of the boat or motor vehicle and to any other person known to have any interest therein, addressed to such persons at their last known addresses, at least ten (10) days before the sale is held.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_280__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The term “boat,” as used in subsection (1) of this section, means any watercraft not enumerated in subsection (1) of KRS 376.360 and sloops having an overall length of forty (40) feet or less.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_281"><akn:num>376.281</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on aircraft for storage, repairs or accessories.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 376.270 and 376.280, “motor vehicle” shall include vehicles used or designed for navigation of or flight in the air, as well as those used or designed for operation on the public highways.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_290"><akn:num>376.290</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on watches and jewelry for repairs — Sale for charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_290__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person performing work upon any watch, clock or jewelry for a price shall have a lien upon that article for the amount due for the work. The lien shall include the value or agreed price of all materials furnished in connection with the work, whether added to the article or not. The lien may be enforced by legal action or as hereafter provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_290__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the account remains unpaid six (6) months after completing the work, the person holding the lien may, upon thirty (30) days’ notice in writing to the owner specifying the amount due and informing the owner that the payment of the amount due within thirty (30) days will entitle him to redeem the property, sell the article at public or bona fide private sale to satisfy the account. The notice may be served by mail directed to the owner’s last known address, or, if the owner or his address is unknown, it may be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_290__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The proceeds of the sale, after paying the expenses thereof, shall be applied in liquidation of the indebtedness secured by the lien, and the balance, if any, shall be held for a period of twelve (12) months for the owner, and if it is not called for in that time it shall be paid into the district school fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_300"><akn:num>376.300</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien of dry cleaner, launderer, or tailor on article for work done — Sale for charges — Notification and criteria for sale.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_300__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who cleans, presses, glazes, launders, alters, or repairs any wearing apparel or household goods shall have a lien on the article remaining in his possession to secure the reasonable or agreed charge for the service. If the charge is not paid within ninety (90) days, the article may be sold to pay the charges and costs of notice, after notice has been given the customer of the time and place of sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_300__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The notice of time and place of sale, when given, shall be by registered letter mailed to the last known address of the customer. The person sending the letter may do so anytime after an article has been held for at least sixty (60) days, and the notice by registered letter shall specify that the article may be sold unless it is redeemed within thirty (30) days from the date of the letter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_300__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any article which is left with any person who cleans, presses, glazes, launders, alters, or repairs any wearing apparel or other household goods and which is not redeemed by the customer within one hundred eighty (180) days shall be considered abandoned. It may, without any liability or responsibility for the article on the part of the person holding it and without notification to the customer, be sold or otherwise disposed of.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_300__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The foregoing provisions shall not apply to property that is to be placed in storage with the person rendering any service mentioned above, but such property shall be subject to the provisions of KRS 376.310.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_310"><akn:num>376.310</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for storage and services on article prior to storage — Sale for charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_310__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who keeps any wearing apparel or household goods in storage, or who has performed any of the services mentioned in KRS 376.300 on such an article and then keeps it in storage, shall have a lien on the article as long as it remains in his possession. If the reasonable or agreed charges have not been paid for a period of twelve (12) months the article may be sold to pay the charges, after the owner has been notified of the time and place of sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_310__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall not apply to any person operating as a warehouseman under KRS Chapter 359.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_320"><akn:num>376.320</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of sale of article for charges — Distribution of proceeds.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_320__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The mailing of a registered letter with the return address marked thereon, addressed to the owner at the address given at the time of delivery of the article to the person rendering any service set out in KRS 376.300 or 376.310, stating the time and place of sale, shall constitute notice of the sale. The notice shall be mailed at least fifteen (15) days before the date of sale. The cost of mailing the letter shall be added to the charges.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_320__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The person to whom the charges are payable shall, from the proceeds of sale, deduct the charges due plus the cost of notifying the owner, and hold the balance, if any, subject to the order of the owner. He shall immediately thereafter mail to the owner at his address, if known, notification of the sale and notice of the balance due him, and at any time within twelve (12) months, upon demand pay to the owner the balance. If the balance is unclaimed after twelve (12) months it shall be paid into the State Treasury, and held for a period of two (2) years subject to the order of the owner or his personal representative upon satisfactory proof of rightful ownership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_330"><akn:num>376.330</akn:num><akn:heading>Posting of notices necessary to claim liens.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No person shall obtain a lien under KRS 376.300 or 376.310 unless at all times he keeps posted in prominent places in his receiving office two (2) notices which shall read as follows: “All articles cleaned, pressed, glazed, laundered, washed, altered or repaired and not called for in 90 days will be sold to pay charges. All articles stored 12 months on which charges have not been paid will be sold to pay charges.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_340"><akn:num>376.340</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien of keeper of hotel, inn, boarding house or house of private entertainment on personal property of guest for charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any keeper of a hotel, inn, boarding house or house of private entertainment shall have a lien on all baggage and other personal property owned and brought in by the person receiving board, nursing, care or attention from the landlord, for the contract price of the service received, or, if no contract price is set, for a reasonable price.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_350"><akn:num>376.350</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of lien on property of guest.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person in whose favor a lien created by KRS 376.340 exists may, before the District Court of the county where the debt was created, by himself, agent or attorney, make affidavit of the amount due him and in arrear for services to the person receiving them and describing, as nearly as possible, the baggage or other personal property owned and brought in by the guest. The court shall then issue a warrant directed to the sheriff or any constable or town marshal of the county, authorizing him to levy upon and seize the property described in the affidavit for the amount due, with interest and costs. If the property has been removed with the consent of the landlord, the lien shall not continue longer than ten (10) days from and after the removal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_360"><akn:num>376.360</akn:num><akn:heading>Liens on steamboats and other vessels for work and supplies.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_360__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any officer or employee, except the captain, employed on board a steamboat, brig, schooner, sloop or model barge shall have a lien on the vessel or on the engine, tackle, furnishing and apparel for their wages, whether contracted for or earned in or out of this state, with priority therefor over any other debt due from the owner of the vessel, and over all other liens thereon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_360__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Mechanics, tradesmen and other persons shall have a like lien to that given by subsection (1) of this section for work, supplies, materials, stores and provisions done or furnished on the building, repairing, fitting, furnishing or equipping the vessel in this state, with priority therefor over any other debt of the owner, except that to the officers and employees, and over all other liens thereafter created. Any mechanic, tradesman or other person who does work or furnishes material or supplies out of this state shall have a like lien therefor, which shall have precedence next after that given when done or furnished in this state; but if done or furnished out of this state, subsequent to that done or furnished in this state, the liens shall be joint and equal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_370"><akn:num>376.370</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for damage done by vessel.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A steamboat or other vessel named in KRS 376.360 and its owner shall be liable to the party injured for any damage done by her through the willful or negligent conduct of her officers or crew while acting for her as such.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_380"><akn:num>376.380</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of lien and liability against vessel.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The lien given in KRS 376.360, and the liability provided for in KRS 376.370, may be enforced by attachment from the court having jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_390"><akn:num>376.390</akn:num><akn:heading>Joinder of lienholders as plaintiffs — When lien may be enforced against purchaser without notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_390__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person having a lien under KRS 376.360 to 376.380 against a vessel may unite in an action to enforce the lien, and any person having a lien who is not so united may, by petition filed by leave of court, become a plaintiff in any action pending to enforce a lien without the issuing of additional process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_390__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien given by KRS 376.360 to 376.380 shall not be enforced against a purchaser without actual notice thereof unless action is instituted within one (1) year from the time the cause of action accrued, or unless notice thereof is endorsed on or attached to the enrollment of the vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_400"><akn:num>376.400</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien of keeper of livery stable or agister for care of livestock — Sale of livestock cared for — Conditions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_400__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any owner or keeper of a livery stable or other business providing for the care of animals, and a person feeding, grazing, or caring for any animal for compensation, shall, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, have a lien for one (1) year upon the animal placed in the stable, kennel, or similar facility, or put out to be fed or grazed by the owner, for his or her reasonable charges for keeping, caring for, feeding, and grazing the animal. The lien shall attach whether the animal is merely temporarily lodged, fed, grazed, and cared for, or is placed at the stable or other place or pasture for regular board. The lien shall take priority over a lien created pursuant to KRS 376.420(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_400__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who has agreed to provide feed or care for an animal for compensation may, in lieu of the lien provided for in subsection (1) of this section, cause the animal to be sold if:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The owner of the animal is at least forty-five (45) days in arrears on his or her payment for the care and feeding of the animal, and the animal is in the possession of the person or business providing for the care of the animal; (b)The proposed sale is published in one (1) or more newspapers and qualified pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, with a publication area in the locale where the person providing care for the animal is located and the locale where the owner of the animal was last known to reside; and (c)Written notice of the sale is sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, or registered mail, to the owner of the animal, addressed to such person at his or her last known address, and to all lien holders of record with the Kentucky Secretary of State and the local county clerk’s office, at least ten (10) days before the sale is conducted. The written notice shall include: 1.The amount due the person or business providing care for the animal; 2.The date, time, and location of the sale; and 3.A statement that the sale proceeds shall be disbursed as provided in subsection (3) of this section.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_400__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a sale is conducted as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the proceeds of the sale shall be disbursed in the following order:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Payment for costs associated with the sale; (b)Payment of amounts due to the person or business providing for the care and feeding of the animal; (c)Payment to lien holders and creditors pursuant to a court order; and (d)The remainder, if any, held for the owner for a period of twelve (12) months and, if not claimed at that time, then paid into the district school fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_410"><akn:num>376.410</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of lien for care of livestock.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person in whose favor a lien provided for in KRS 376.400 exists may, before the District Court of the county where the cattle were fed or grazed, by himself or agent, make affidavit of the amount due him and in arrears for keeping and caring for the cattle, and describing as nearly as possible the cattle so kept by him. The court shall then issue a warrant, directed to the sheriff or any constable or town marshal of the county, authorizing him to levy upon and seize the cattle for the amount due, with interest and costs. If the cattle are removed with the consent and from the custody of the livery stable keeper or the person feeding or grazing them, the lien shall not continue longer than one (1) year from and after the removal, nor shall the lien in case of such removal be valid against a bona fide purchaser without notice at any time after the removal. The warrant may be issued to a county other than that in which the cattle were fed or grazed, and the lien may also be enforced by action as in the case of other liens.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_420"><akn:num>376.420</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for service fee of stallion, jack, or bull — Enforcement of lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_420__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any licensed keeper of a stallion, jack, or bull shall have a lien for the payment of the service fee upon the get of the stallion, jack, or bull, for one (1) year after the birth of the progeny. However, a lien created pursuant to KRS 376.400 shall take priority over a lien created pursuant to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_420__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This lien may be enforced by action as in cases of other liens, or by warrant as permitted in the case of the enforcement of the lien of the keeper of a livery stable or an agister.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_430"><akn:num>376.430</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on radios, phonographs and other electrical or electronic devices, for repair.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_430__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>All persons, firms and corporations engaged in the business of repairing radios, phonographs, combinations thereof, automatic music instruments, refrigerators, televisions, electrical or electronic recording devices, and any and all portable electrical or electronic instruments or appliances shall have a lien upon such articles and appliances for the agreed or reasonable charge for parts, supplies, accessories and labor performed in their repair, said lien to attach upon completion of such repairs. The lien may be enforced by legal action or as hereafter provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_430__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>After completion of repairs, the owner shall be notified thereof by certified mail, return receipt requested or by registered mail, and if the repaired article be not removed and all charges paid within thirty (30) days after giving the notice, the person, firm or corporation making such repairs may hold such repaired articles and sell same at public or bona fide private sale to pay all agreed or reasonable charges, including charges for storage after notice of completion of repairs, and expenses incidental to advertisement and sale, accounting to the owner for any excess of charges and expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_430__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Before any sale of the repaired article, the person, firm or corporation making the repairs shall notify the owner of the article of the time and place of the sale. The notice may be served by certified mail, return receipt requested, or by registered mail directed to the owner’s last known address, or, if the owner or his address is unknown, notice of the sale shall be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_435"><akn:num>376.435</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on die, mold, form, or pattern — Respective rights of molder and customer.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_435__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)“Customer” means any person who causes a molder to fabricate, cast, or otherwise make a die, mold, form, or pattern, or who provides a molder with a die, mold, form, or pattern, to manufacture, assemble, cast, fabricate, or otherwise make a product for a customer; and (b)“Molder” means any person who fabricates, casts, or otherwise makes or uses a die, mold, form, or pattern for the purpose of manufacturing, assembling, casting, fabricating, or otherwise making a product for a customer. “Molder” includes, but is not limited to, a tool or die maker.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_435__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)In the absence of any agreement to the contrary, a customer shall have all rights and title to any die, mold, form, or pattern in the possession of a molder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)If a customer does not claim possession from a molder of a die, mold, form, or pattern, all rights and title to any die, mold, form, or pattern shall be transferred by operation of law to the molder for the purpose of destroying or otherwise disposing of the die, mold, form, or pattern, consistent with this subsection. (c)If a molder chooses to have all rights and title to any die, mold, form, or pattern transferred to the molder by operation of law, the molder shall send written notice by registered mail to the chief executive officer of the customer or, if the customer is not a business entity, to the customer, at the customer’s last known address. The written notice shall indicate that the molder intends to terminate the customer’s rights and title by having the rights and title transferred to the molder by operation of law under this section. The notice shall include a statement of the customer’s rights set forth in paragraph (d) of this subsection. (d) 1.If a customer does not respond in person or by mail to claim possession of a particular die, mold, form, or pattern within one hundred twenty (120) days following the date that the notice was mailed, or does not make contractual arrangements with the molder for storage of the die, mold, form, or pattern, all rights and title of the customer, except patents and copyrights, shall transfer by operation of law to the molder. Thereafter, the molder may destroy or otherwise dispose of the particular die, mold, form, or pattern as the molder’s own property without any risk of liability to the customer. 2.This section shall not be construed in any manner to affect any right of the customer under federal patent or copyright law or federal law pertaining to unfair competition.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_435__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)A molder shall have a lien, dependent on possession, on all dies, molds, forms, or patterns in his hands and that belong to a customer, for the balance due him from the customer for any manufacturing or fabrication work, and in the value of all material related to the work. The molder may retain possession of the die, mold, form, or pattern until the charges are paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)Before enforcing a lien, a molder shall give notice in writing to the customer, whether delivered personally or sent by registered mail to the last known address of the customer. The notice shall state that a lien is claimed for the damages set forth in or attached to the writing for manufacturing or fabrication work contracted or performed for the customer. The notice shall also include a demand for payment. (c)If the molder has not been paid the amount due within sixty (60) days after the notice has been received by the customer, as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, the molder may sell the die, mold, form, or pattern at a public auction.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_376_435__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)Before a molder may sell the die, mold, form, or pattern, the molder shall notify the customer by registered mail, return receipt requested. The notice shall include:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>1.The molder’s intention to sell the die, mold, form, or pattern thirty (30) days after the customer’s receipt of the notice; 2.A description of the die, mold, form, or pattern to be sold; 3.The time and place of the sale; and 4.An itemized statement for the amount due. (b)If there is not a return of the receipt of the mailing or if the postal service returns the notice as being nondeliverable, the molder shall publish the notice of the molder’s intention to sell the die, mold, form, or pattern in a newspaper of general circulation in the customer’s last known place of business. The notice shall include a description of the die, mold, form, or pattern. (c) 1.If the sale is for a sum greater than the amount of the lien, the excess shall be paid to any prior lienholder known to the molder at the time of the sale and any remainder shall be paid to the customer, if the customer’s address is known, or the Kentucky State Treasurer for deposit in the general fund if the customer’s address is unknown to the molder at the time of the sale. 2.A molder shall not conduct a sale if the sale violates any right of a customer under federal patent or copyright law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_440"><akn:num>376.440</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien on equipment, machinery and motors for work and supplies — Filing of lien statement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_440__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person engaged in the business of selling, repairing, or furnishing accessories, or supplies for any kind of equipment or machinery, including motors, shall have a lien on the equipment, machine, machinery, or motor, for the reasonable or agreed charges for repairs, work done, accessories, parts, and supplies furnished for the equipment, machine, machinery, or motor until the reasonable or agreed charge therefor has been paid. The lien shall not be lost by the removal of the equipment, machine, machinery or motor from the premises of the person performing labor, repairing, or furnishing accessories, parts or supplies therefor, if the lien shall be asserted within three (3) months by filing in the office of the county clerk a statement showing the amount and cost of materials furnished or labor performed on the equipment, machine, machinery, or motor. This statement shall be filed in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the owner of the equipment, machine, machinery, or motor resides, unless such owner be a nonresident, in which event the lien statement shall be filed in the office of the county clerk of the county in which such equipment, machine, machinery, or motor is at the time being kept or used.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_440__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The lien provided for in this section shall attach regardless of whether or not the equipment, machine, machinery, motor, or motors, are ever upon the premises of or in the possession of the person making the repairs, furnishing the parts, or the supplies for such repairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_445"><akn:num>376.445</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of lien statement — Indorsement and filing by county clerk — Fee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_445__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The lien statement referred to in KRS 376.440 shall be construed to mean a statement in writing in which is stated the amount due the claimant, with all just credits and setoffs known to him, together with a description of the property intended to be covered by the lien sufficiently accurate to identify it and the name of the owner. This statement shall be subscribed and sworn to by the person claiming the lien or by someone in his behalf.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_445__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The county clerk shall endorse upon each statement the date of its filing, and shall make an abstract of the statement in a book to be kept by him for that purpose, properly endorsed and indexed, containing the date of filing, the name of the person seeking to enforce the lien, the amount claimed, the name of the person against whose property the lien is filed, and a description of the property charged with the lien. The clerk shall receive a fee as provided for in KRS 64.012 from the person filing the statement as full compensation, which shall be taxed and collected as other costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_450"><akn:num>376.450</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien inferior to mortgage or sale unless statement filed.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The lien shall not take precedence over a mortgage or bona fide sale and delivery for value without notice, unless the person claiming the prior lien shall, before the recording of the mortgage, or before sale and delivery, file in the office of the county clerk a statement showing that he has furnished or expects to furnish labor, or materials, or parts, or supplies, and the amount in full thereof. The lien shall not, as against the holder of a mortgage, or a purchaser for value, exceed the amount of the lien claimed, as set forth in the statement. The statement shall in all other respects be in the form provided in KRS 376.445.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_455"><akn:num>376.455</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of equipment, machinery or motor to pay charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any equipment, machine, machinery, motor or motors remaining in the possession of a person who has made repairs, furnished parts, performed labor, or furnished accessories or supplies for the equipment, machine, machinery, motor, or motors, for more than thirty (30) days, may be sold to pay the charges. The proposed sale shall be advertised by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. The owner of the equipment, machine, machinery, motor or motors, shall be served with written notice of such proposed sale at least two (2) weeks before the date of such sale. The notice may be in writing addressed to the owner at his last known address and sent by registered United States mail, postage prepaid. Such written notice may be served upon the owner in any other mode generally recognized by the laws and practice before courts in this state.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_460"><akn:num>376.460</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney’s lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Each attorney shall have a lien upon all claims, except those of the state, put into his hands for suit or collection or upon which suit has been instituted, for the amount of any fee agreed upon by the parties or, in the absence of such agreement, for a reasonable fee. If the action is prosecuted to a recovery of money or property, the attorney shall have a lien upon the judgment recovered, legal costs excepted, for his fee. If the records show the name of the attorney, the defendant shall be deemed to have notice of the lien. If the parties in good faith and before judgment compromise or settle their controversy without the payment of money or other thing of value, the attorney for the plaintiff shall have no claim against the defendant for any part of his fee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_470"><akn:num>376.470</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterinarian’s lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_470__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any licensed veterinarian who performs professional services for an animal, by contract with, or by the written consent of, the owner or authorized agent shall have a lien on the animal to secure the cost of the service provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_470__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The priority among veterinarian’s liens filed under this section shall be according to the first lien filed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_475"><akn:num>376.475</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing requirement — Indexing — Dissolution for nonenforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_475__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien provided for in KRS 376.470 shall be dissolved unless the claimant, within six (6) months after he ceases to provide services for the animal, files in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the animal is located, a statement of the amount due him, together with a description of the animal intended to be covered by the lien sufficiently accurate to identify it, the name of the owner, and whether the services were furnished by contract or written consent of the owner or agent. This statement shall be subscribed and sworn to by the person claiming the lien or by someone in his behalf. The claimant shall send by regular mail a copy of the statement to the owner at his last known address within seven (7) days of filing the statement with the county clerk. Any lien provided for in KRS 376.470 shall be dissolved if a copy of the statement is not sent to the property owner as provided in this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_475__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The county clerk shall endorse upon each statement the date of its filing, and shall make an abstract of the statement in a book to be kept by him for that purpose, properly endorsed and indexed, containing the date of filing, the name of the person seeking to enforce the lien, the amount claimed, the name of the person against whose animal the lien is filed, and a description of the animal charged with the lien. The clerk shall receive a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012 from the person filing the statement as full compensation, which shall be taxed and collected as other costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_475__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any lien created under this section shall be dissolved unless an action is brought to enforce the lien within twelve (12) months from the day of filing the statement in the clerk’s office as required by subsection (1) of this section. If the lienholder complies with all filing requirements under this section, and does so within the time herein fixed, his lien shall be valid and effective against any creditor of, or bona fide or other purchaser from, the owner of the animal, except as provided in KRS 257.105(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_475__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The procedure to enforce a lien under KRS 376.470 shall be as provided in KRS 376.110, 376.120, and 376.130.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_480"><akn:num>376.480</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for rent due on space for parking abandoned house trailer or mobile home — Sale of abandoned property.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_480__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any owner of real property who rents space on which a house trailer or mobile home is parked shall have a lien for rent due on any house trailer or mobile home, its contents, and other personalty abandoned by the occupant on the landowner’s property for rent due, reasonable storage, cleanup costs, and utilities furnished to the unit and paid for by the landowner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_480__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If, after a period of sixty (60) days, the rent, reasonable storage, cleanup costs, and utilities have not been paid, the house trailer or mobile home, its contents, and other personalty abandoned by the occupant may be sold to pay the rent, reasonable storage, cleanup costs, and utilities after the unit owner has been notified of the time and place of the sale, at the unit owner’s last known address. Notice shall be made by registered mail at least ten (10) days prior to the time of the sale. If there is a valid recorded lien against the property to be sold, the landowner shall notify the lienholder of the time and place of sale by registered mail at least ten (10) days prior to the time of the sale. If the proceeds of the sale are insufficient to pay the debt and costs of sale, the sale and collection of proceeds shall not constitute a waiver or release of responsibility for payment of the debt owed by the unit owner. This lien shall be subject to prior recorded liens and property taxes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_480__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any money obtained in excess of the sale costs, taxes, and liens shall be paid by the seller to the unit owner; and if the unit owner cannot be located, the excess money shall escheat to the state pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 393.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_480__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Before the sale, the landowner shall advertise a description of the property to be sold and the time and place of sale for three (3) consecutive publishing periods in a local newspaper distributed in the county where the property is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_480__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The sale may be by written bids or by auction, or both, and the seller may bid on the property. The sale shall be to the highest bidder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_480__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The house trailer or mobile home shall be transferred to the purchaser in the county where the sale is conducted upon an affidavit being filed by the seller stating that the provisions of this section have been met, listing the sale price, and containing any other information that may be required by the state or county.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_376_990"><akn:num>376.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_376_990__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates the provisions of subsection (2) of KRS 376.050 shall be guilty of a Class D felony.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_376_990__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 376.060 or 376.070 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter><akn:chapter eId="chap_377"><akn:num>Chapter 377</akn:num><akn:heading>Bulk Sales [Superseded]</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_377_010"><akn:num>377.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction and application of chapter.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_020"><akn:num>377.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Bulk sales of merchandise or fixtures; statement of creditors of vendor required.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_030"><akn:num>377.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of proposed sale to be given creditors of vendor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_040"><akn:num>377.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of purchase money.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_050"><akn:num>377.050</akn:num><akn:heading>When sale is deemed fraudulent and void; effect of such sale; limitation of action to invalidate.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_060"><akn:num>377.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Vendor not to make an incomplete or false statement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_070"><akn:num>377.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Vendor may require security from purchaser.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_990"><akn:num>377.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_010"><akn:num>377.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction and application of chapter.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_020"><akn:num>377.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Bulk sales of merchandise or fixtures; statement of creditors of vendor required.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_030"><akn:num>377.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of proposed sale to be given creditors of vendor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_040"><akn:num>377.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of purchase money.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_050"><akn:num>377.050</akn:num><akn:heading>When sale is deemed fraudulent and void; effect of such sale; limitation of action to invalidate.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_060"><akn:num>377.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Vendor not to make an incomplete or false statement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_070"><akn:num>377.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Vendor may require security from purchaser.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_377_990"><akn:num>377.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter><akn:chapter eId="chap_378A"><akn:num>Chapter 378A</akn:num><akn:heading>Kentucky Uniform Voidable Transactions Act</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_378A_005"><akn:num>378A.005</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_010"><akn:num>378A.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for chapter.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_020"><akn:num>378A.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Insolvency.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_030"><akn:num>378A.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Value.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_040"><akn:num>378A.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer or obligation voidable as to present or future creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_050"><akn:num>378A.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer or obligation voidable as to present creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_060"><akn:num>378A.060</akn:num><akn:heading>When transfer is made or obligation is incurred.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_070"><akn:num>378A.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies of creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_080"><akn:num>378A.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Defenses, liability, and protection of transferee or obligee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_090"><akn:num>378A.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Extinguishment of claim for relief.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_100"><akn:num>378A.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Governing law.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_110"><akn:num>378A.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to series organization.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_120"><akn:num>378A.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplementary provisions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_130"><akn:num>378A.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniformity of application and construction.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_140"><akn:num>378A.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_005"><akn:num>378A.005</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>This chapter may be cited as the Kentucky Uniform Voidable Transactions Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_010"><akn:num>378A.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for chapter.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this chapter:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Affiliate” means:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)A person that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds with power to vote, twenty percent (20%) or more of the outstanding voting securities of the debtor, other than a person that holds the securities: 1.As a fiduciary or agent without sole discretionary power to vote the securities; or 2.Solely to secure a debt, if the person has not in fact exercised the power to vote; (b)A corporation twenty percent (20%) or more of whose outstanding voting securities are directly or indirectly owned, controlled, or held with power to vote, by the debtor or a person that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds, with power to vote, twenty percent (20%) or more of the outstanding voting securities of the debtor, other than a person that holds the securities: 1.As a fiduciary or agent without sole discretionary power to vote the securities; or 2.Solely to secure a debt, if the person has not in fact exercised the power to vote; (c)A person whose business is operated by the debtor under a lease or other agreement, or a person substantially all of whose assets are controlled by the debtor; or (d)A person that operates the debtor’s business under a lease or other agreement or controls substantially all of the debtor’s assets;</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Asset” means property of a debtor, but the term does not include:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Property to the extent it is encumbered by a valid lien; (b)Property to the extent it is generally exempt under nonbankruptcy law; or (c)An interest in property held in tenancy by the entireties to the extent it is not subject to process by a creditor holding a claim against only one (1) tenant.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Claim,” except as used in “claim for relief,” means a right to payment, whether or not the right is reduced to judgment, liquidated, unliquidated, fixed, contingent, matured, unmatured, undisputed, legal, equitable, secure, or unsecured;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Creditor” means a person that has a claim;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Debt” means liability on a claim;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Debtor” means a person that is liable on a claim;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Electronic” means relating to technology having electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Insider” includes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)If the debtor is an individual: 1.A relative of the debtor or of a general partner of the debtor; 2.A partnership in which the debtor is a general partner; 3.A general partner in a partnership described in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph; or 4.A corporation of which the debtor is a director, officer, or person in control; (b)If the debtor is a corporation: 1.A director of the debtor; 2.An officer of the debtor; 3.A person in control of the debtor; 4.A partnership in which the debtor is a general partner; 5.A general partner in a partnership described in subparagraph 4. of this paragraph; or 6.A relative of a general partner, director, officer, or person in control of the debtor; (c)If the debtor is a partnership: 1.A general partner in the debtor; 2.A relative of a general partner in, a general partner of, or a person in control of the debtor; 3.Another partnership in which the debtor is a general partner; 4.A general partner in a partnership described in subparagraph 3. of this paragraph; or 5.A person in control of the debtor; (d)An affiliate, or an insider of an affiliate as if the affiliate were the debtor; and (e)A managing agent of the debtor;</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Lien” means a charge against or an interest in property to secure payment of a debt or performance of an obligation, and includes a security interest created by agreement, a judicial lien obtained by legal or equitable process or proceedings, a common-law lien, or a statutory lien;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Organization” means a person other than an individual;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_11"><akn:num>(11)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, estate, business or nonprofit entity, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or other legal entity;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_12"><akn:num>(12)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Property” means anything that may be the subject of ownership;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_13"><akn:num>(13)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Record” means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_14"><akn:num>(14)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Relative” means an individual related by consanguinity within the third degree as determined by the common law, a spouse, or an individual related to a spouse within the third degree as so determined, and includes an individual in an adoptive relationship within the third degree;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_15"><akn:num>(15)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Sign” means, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)To execute or adopt a tangible symbol; or (b)To attach to or logically associate with the record an electronic symbol, sound, or process;</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_16"><akn:num>(16)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Transfer” means every mode, direct or indirect, absolute or conditional, voluntary or involuntary, of disposing of or parting with an asset or an interest in an asset, and includes payment of money, release, lease, license, and creation of a lien or other encumbrance; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_010__point_17"><akn:num>(17)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Valid lien” means a lien that is effective against the holder of a judicial lien subsequently obtained by legal or equitable process or proceedings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_020"><akn:num>378A.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Insolvency.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_378A_020__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A debtor is insolvent if, at a fair valuation, the sum of the debtor’s debts is greater than the sum of the debtor’s assets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_020__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A debtor that is generally not paying the debtor’s debts as they become due other than as a result of a bona fide dispute is presumed to be insolvent. The presumption imposes on the party against which the presumption is directed the burden of proving that the nonexistence of insolvency is more probable than its existence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_020__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Assets under this section do not include property that has been transferred, concealed, or removed with intent to hinder, delay, or defraud creditors or that has been transferred in a manner making the transfer voidable under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_020__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Debts under this section do not include an obligation to the extent it is secured by a valid lien on property of the debtor not included as an asset.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_030"><akn:num>378A.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Value.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_378A_030__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Value is given for a transfer or an obligation if, in exchange for the transfer or obligation, property is transferred or an antecedent debt is secured or satisfied, but value does not include an unperformed promise made otherwise than in the ordinary course of the promisor’s business to furnish support to the debtor or another person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_030__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of KRS 378A.040(1)(b) and 378A.050, a person gives a reasonably equivalent value if the person acquires an interest of the debtor in an asset pursuant to a regularly conducted, noncollusive foreclosure sale or execution of a power of sale for the acquisition or disposition of the interest of the debtor upon default under a mortgage, deed of trust, or security agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_030__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer is made for present value if the exchange between the debtor and the transferee is intended by them to be contemporaneous and is in fact substantially contemporaneous.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_040"><akn:num>378A.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer or obligation voidable as to present or future creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_378A_040__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer made or obligation incurred by a debtor is voidable as to a creditor, whether the creditor’s claim arose before or after the transfer was made or the obligation was incurred, if the debtor made the transfer or incurred the obligation:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)With actual intent to hinder, delay, or defraud any creditor of the debtor; or (b)Without receiving a reasonably equivalent value in exchange for the transfer or obligation, and the debtor: 1.Was engaged or was about to engage in a business or a transaction for which the remaining assets of the debtor were unreasonably small in relation to the business or transaction; or 2.Intended to incur, or believed or reasonably should have believed that the debtor would incur, debts beyond the debtor’s ability to pay as they became due.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_040__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In determining actual intent under subsection (1)(a) of this section, consideration may be given, among other factors, to whether:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The transfer or obligation was to an insider; (b)The debtor retained possession or control of the property transferred after the transfer; (c)The transfer or obligation was disclosed or concealed; (d)Before the transfer was made or obligation was incurred, the debtor had been sued or threatened with suit; (e)The transfer was of substantially all the debtor’s assets; (f)The debtor absconded; (g)The debtor removed or concealed assets; (h)The value of the consideration received by the debtor was reasonably equivalent to the value of the asset transferred or the amount of the obligation incurred; (i)The debtor was insolvent or became insolvent shortly after the transfer was made or the obligation was incurred; (j)The transfer occurred shortly before or shortly after a substantial debt was incurred; and (k)The debtor transferred the essential assets of the business to a lienor that transferred the assets to an insider of the debtor.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_040__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A creditor making a claim for relief under subsection (1) of this section has the burden of proving the elements of the claim for relief by a preponderance of the evidence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_050"><akn:num>378A.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer or obligation voidable as to present creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_378A_050__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer made or obligation incurred by a debtor is voidable as to a creditor whose claim arose before the transfer was made or the obligation was incurred if the debtor made the transfer or incurred the obligation without receiving a reasonably equivalent value in exchange for the transfer or obligation and the debtor was insolvent at the time or the debtor became insolvent as a result of the transfer or obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_050__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer made by a debtor is voidable as to a creditor whose claim arose before the transfer was made, if the transfer was made to an insider for an antecedent debt, the debtor was insolvent at that time, and the insider had reasonable cause to believe that the debtor was insolvent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_050__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Subject to KRS 378A.020(2), a creditor making a claim for relief under subsection (1) or (2) of this section has the burden of proving the elements of the claim for relief by a preponderance of the evidence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_060"><akn:num>378A.060</akn:num><akn:heading>When transfer is made or obligation is incurred.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this chapter:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_060__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer is made:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)With respect to an asset that is real property other than a fixture, but including the interest of a seller or purchaser under a contract for the sale of the asset, when the transfer is so far perfected that a good-faith purchaser of the asset from the debtor against which applicable laws permit the transfer to be perfected cannot acquire an interest in the asset that is superior to the interest of the transferee; and (b)With respect to an asset that is not real property or that is a fixture, when the transfer is so far perfected that a creditor on a simple contract cannot acquire a judicial lien otherwise than under this chapter that is superior to the interest of the transferee.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_060__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If applicable law permits the transfer to be perfected as provided in subsection (1) of this section, and the transfer is not so perfected before the commencement of an action for relief under this chapter, the transfer is deemed made immediately before the commencement of the action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_060__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If applicable law does not permit the transfer to be perfected as provided in subsection (1) of this section, the transfer is made when it becomes effective between the debtor and the transferee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_060__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer is not made until the debtor has acquired rights in the asset transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_060__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An obligation is incurred:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)If oral, when it becomes effective between the parties; or (b)If evidenced by a record, when the record, signed by the obligor, is delivered to or for the benefit of the obligee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_070"><akn:num>378A.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies of creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_378A_070__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In an action for relief against a transfer or obligation under this chapter, a creditor, subject to the limitations in KRS 378A.080, may obtain:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Avoidance of the transfer or obligation to the extent necessary to satisfy the creditor’s claim; (b)An attachment or other provisional remedy against the asset transferred or other property of the transferee if available under applicable law; and (c)Subject to applicable principles of equity and in accordance with applicable Rules of Civil Procedure: 1.An injunction against further disposition by the debtor or a transferee, or both, of the asset transferred or of other property; 2.Appointment of a receiver to take charge of the asset transferred or of the other property of the transferee; or 3.Any other relief the circumstances may require.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_070__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a creditor has obtained a judgment on a claim against the debtor, the creditor, if the court so orders, may levy execution on the asset transferred or its proceeds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_080"><akn:num>378A.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Defenses, liability, and protection of transferee or obligee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_378A_080__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer or obligation is not voidable under KRS 378A.040(1)(a) against a person that took in good faith and for a reasonably equivalent value given the debtor or against any subsequent transferee or obligee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_080__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>To the extent a transfer is avoidable in an action by a creditor under KRS 378A.070(1)(a), the following rules apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Except as otherwise provided in this section, the creditor may recover judgment for the value of the asset transferred, as adjusted under subsection (3) of this section, or the amount necessary to satisfy the creditor’s claim, whichever is less. The judgment may be entered against: 1.The first transferee of the asset or the person for whose benefit the transfer was made; or 2.An immediate or mediate transferee of the first transferee, other than: a.A good-faith transferee that took for value; or b.An immediate or mediate good-faith transferee of a person described in subdivision a. of this subparagraph; and (b)Recovery pursuant to KRS 378A.070(1)(a) or (b) of or from the asset transferred or its proceeds, by levy or otherwise, is available only against a person described in subsection (2)(a)1. or 2. of this section.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_080__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the judgment under subsection (2) of this section is based upon the value of the asset transferred, the judgment shall be for an amount equal to the value of the asset at the time of the transfer, subject to adjustment as the equities may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_080__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding voidability of a transfer or an obligation under this chapter, a good-faith transferee or obligee is entitled, to the extent of the value given the debtor for the transfer or obligation, to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)A lien on or a right to retain an interest in the asset transferred; (b)Enforcement of an obligation incurred; or (c)A reduction in the amount of the liability on the judgment.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_080__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer is not voidable under KRS 378A.040(1)(b) or 378A.050 if the transfer results from:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Termination of a lease upon default by the debtor when the termination is pursuant to the lease and applicable law; or (b)Enforcement of a security interest in compliance with Subtitle 9 of KRS Chapter 355, other than acceptance of collateral in full or partial satisfaction of the obligation it secures.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_080__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A transfer is not voidable under KRS 378A.050(2):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)To the extent the insider gave new value to or for the benefit of the debtor after the transfer was made, except to the extent the new value was secured by a valid lien; (b)If made in the ordinary course of business or financial affairs of the debtor and the insider; or (c)If made pursuant to a good-faith effort to rehabilitate the debtor and the transfer secured present value given for that purpose as well as an antecedent debt of the debtor.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_080__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The following rules determine the burden of proving matters referred to in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)A party that seeks to invoke subsection (1), (4), (5), or (6) of this section has the burden of proving the applicability of the subsection invoked; (b)Except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (c) and (d) of this subsection, the creditor has the burden of proving each applicable element of subsections (2) or (3) of this section; (c)The transferee has the burden of proving the applicability to the transferee of subsection (2)(a)2.a. or b. of this section; and (d)A party that seeks adjustment under subsection (3) of this section has the burden of proving the adjustment.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_080__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The standard of proof required to establish matters referred to in this section is preponderance of the evidence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_090"><akn:num>378A.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Extinguishment of claim for relief.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A claim for relief with respect to a transfer or obligation under this chapter is extinguished unless action is brought:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_090__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Under KRS 378A.040(1)(a), not later than four (4) years after the transfer was made or the obligation was incurred or, if later, not later than one (1) year after the transfer or obligation was or could reasonably have been discovered by the claimant;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_090__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Under KRS 378A.040(1)(b) or 378A.050(1), not later than four (4) years after the transfer was made or the obligation was incurred; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_378A_090__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Under KRS 378A.050(2), no later than one (1) year after the transfer was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_100"><akn:num>378A.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Governing law.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_378A_100__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In this section, the following rules determine a debtor’s location:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)A debtor who is an individual is located at the individual’s principal residence; (b)A debtor that is an organization and has only one (1) place of business is located at its place of business; and (c)A debtor that is an organization and has more than one (1) place of business is located at its chief executive office.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_100__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A claim for relief in the nature of a claim for relief under this chapter is governed by the local laws of the jurisdiction in which the debtor is located when the transfer is made or the obligation is incurred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_110"><akn:num>378A.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to series organization.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_378A_110__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)“Protected series” means an arrangement, however denominated, created by a series organization that, pursuant to the law under which the series organization is organized, has the characteristics set forth in paragraph (b) of this subsection; and (b)“Series organization” means an organization that, pursuant to the law under which it is organized, has the following characteristics: 1.The organic record of the organization provides for creation by the organization of one (1) or more protected series, however denominated, with respect to specified property of the organization, and for records to be maintained for each protected series that identify the property of, or associated with, the protected series; 2.Debt incurred or existing with respect to the activities of, or property of, or associated with, a particular protected series is enforceable against the property of, or associated with, the protected series only, and not against the property of, or associated with, the organization or other protected series of the organization; and 3.Debt incurred or existing with respect to the activities or property of the organization is enforceable against the property of the organization only, and not against the property of, or associated with, a protected series of the organization.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_378A_110__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A series organization and each protected series of the organization is a separate person for purposes of this chapter, even if for other purposes a protected series is not a person separate from the organization or other protected series of the organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_120"><akn:num>378A.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplementary provisions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Unless displaced by the provisions of this chapter, the principles of law and equity, including the law merchant and the law relating to principal and agent, estoppel, laches, fraud, misrepresentation, duress, coercion, mistake, insolvency, or other validating or invalidating cause, supplement its provisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_130"><akn:num>378A.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniformity of application and construction.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>This chapter shall be applied and construed to effectuate its general purpose to make uniform the law with respect to the subject of this chapter among states enacting it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_378A_140"><akn:num>378A.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>This chapter modifies, limits, or supersedes the Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act, 15 U.S.C. secs. 7001 et seq., but does not modify, limit, or supersede Section 101(c) of that Act, 15 U.S.C. sec. 7001(c), or authorize electronic delivery of any of the notices described in Section 103(B) of that Act, 15 U.S.C. sec. 7003(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter><akn:chapter eId="chap_379"><akn:num>Chapter 379</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary Assignments</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_379_010"><akn:num>379.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary assignments for benefit of creditors — Preferred claims.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_020"><akn:num>379.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Deed of assignment — Recordation — Effect of deed — Schedule of assignor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_030"><akn:num>379.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond of assignee — Appointment of another on failure to qualify — On failure to furnish additional security.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_040"><akn:num>379.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Resignation or removal of assignee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_050"><akn:num>379.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of assignee by District Court — Exception — Filing of inventory of assignee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_060"><akn:num>379.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings, orders and summons of the court — Attendance of assignor or his debtors.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_070"><akn:num>379.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferential or fraudulent transfer or purchase prior to deed of assignment — Effect — Action by assignee or creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_080"><akn:num>379.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions claimed by assignor — Proceedings.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_090"><akn:num>379.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of property by assignee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_100"><akn:num>379.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipt of claims by assignee — Notice of — Filing.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_110"><akn:num>379.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise or sale of debts due or claims against estate.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_120"><akn:num>379.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance or rejection of claims by assignee — Report to court — Exceptions — Court determination.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_130"><akn:num>379.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution — When to be made — Report on — Exceptions — Court determination.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_140"><akn:num>379.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge of assignee — Notice — Proceedings.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_150"><akn:num>379.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement or compromise by assignor with creditors to be filed in court — Assignee discharged.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_160"><akn:num>379.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals from judgments.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_170"><akn:num>379.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Circuit court has jurisdiction of action for settlement of estate.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_010"><akn:num>379.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary assignments for benefit of creditors — Preferred claims.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_010__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Every voluntary assignment made by a debtor to any person in trust for his creditors shall be for the benefit of all his creditors, except as provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section, in proportion to their respective claims after the payment of the expenses of the trust.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_010__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any property conveyed by the deed of assignment upon which there is a valid lien shall be first applied to the discharge of the lien debt, and if the property is not sufficient to satisfy the lien debt, the lien creditor may present the unsatisfied remainder as a claim against the estate and receive thereon his pro rata share of the assets in the same manner as general creditors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_010__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Debts due by the assignor as guardian, conservator, trustee of an express trust created by deed or will or as personal representative shall be paid in full before the general creditors receive anything.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_020"><akn:num>379.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Deed of assignment — Recordation — Effect of deed — Schedule of assignor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_020__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The deed of assignment shall be acknowledged by the assignor in the same manner as other deeds and shall be recorded in the county clerk’s office of the county where the assignor resides, where the business in respect to which the deed is made is carried on, and in each county where a tract of land or the greater part thereof conveyed by the deed is situated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_020__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The deed shall vest in the assignee title to all the property, real and personal, with all deeds, books and papers relating thereto belonging to the assignor at the time of making the assignment, except property exempt by law which shall not pass unless embraced in the deed. The intent of the assignor in making the assignment, whether appearing upon the face of the deed or otherwise, shall not invalidate the deed, unless he is solvent and it appears that the assignment was made to hinder or delay creditors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_020__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The assignor shall, within five (5) days from the day upon which the deed is lodged for record, file for record in the county where the assignee qualifies a schedule under oath, setting forth the general nature and full value of the property assigned, together with a list of his creditors, their post office address, the amount due each and whether secured by lien or not.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_030"><akn:num>379.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond of assignee — Appointment of another on failure to qualify — On failure to furnish additional security.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_030__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The assignee shall, when the deed of assignment is lodged for record or within seven (7) days thereafter, execute a bond with good security, approved by the District Court, conditioned upon the faithful discharge of his duties as assignee. The bond shall be recorded in the court clerk’s office. If the person named in the deed as assignee fails for any cause within the time named to qualify or to execute a sufficient bond, the District Court shall, by order entered of record, appoint an assignee who shall, within five (5) days, give bond with good surety, and who shall thereupon be vested with the same rights, powers and responsibilities with respect to the estate assigned as if named in the deed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_030__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The court may at any time, upon its own motion or upon motion of any party in interest and after ten (10) days’ notice to the assignee, require him to execute a new bond or give additional security if the original bond is not sufficient. If the assignee fails or refuses to execute a new bond or give additional security within the time allowed by the court, the court shall, by an order entered of record, remove the assignee and appoint another in his stead. The newly appointed assignee shall execute bond in the same manner as the original assignee and proceed to settle up the estate, and to this end he may institute any necessary proceedings against the former assignee and his sureties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_040"><akn:num>379.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Resignation or removal of assignee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_040__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An assignee may resign his trust upon settling his accounts, and the settlement shall be confirmed and the assignee discharged from liability sixty (60) days after the settlement has been filed, if no exceptions are filed thereto. If exceptions are filed, they shall be heard and determined by the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_040__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If an assignee moves his residence out of the state, or becomes insane or otherwise incapable of discharging the trust, the court may, upon ten (10) days’ notice to him, his attorney or committee, remove the assignee and appoint another in his stead. If creditors representing one-half (1/2) in number and two-thirds (2/3) of the amount of debts against the estate so request in writing, the court shall remove the assignee and appoint another in his stead.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_050"><akn:num>379.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of assignee by District Court — Exception — Filing of inventory of assignee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_050__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The assignee shall, except as provided in KRS 379.170, be subject to the orders and supervision of the District Court and may be required at any time upon reasonable notice to file any report ordered. He may, when the court so directs, be examined in open court touching the condition of the estate and its management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_050__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The assignee shall file in the clerk’s office of the District Court, as soon as possible, and within fifteen (15) days after his qualification unless the court allows a longer time, an inventory verified by him of all the property that came into his hands. If any property comes to the possession of the assignee after filing the inventory, he shall, in like manner, file an inventory thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_060"><akn:num>379.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings, orders and summons of the court — Attendance of assignor or his debtors.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_060__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>All orders and proceedings in the District Court, except as otherwise provided, shall be ex parte and upon motion, and in no case need a petition be filed. A notice or summons shall not be issued to any person unless ordered by the court or requested by a person in interest. If an exception is filed to a claim or report, the party affected thereby shall have ten (10) days’ notice of the time of hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_060__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The court may, upon the request of the assignee or any creditor, require the assignor or any person indebted to him to appear in court after reasonable notice and answer questions deemed proper concerning the estate or claims against it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_070"><akn:num>379.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferential or fraudulent transfer or purchase prior to deed of assignment — Effect — Action by assignee or creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the assignor has, before making the deed of assignment, made a preferential or fraudulent transfer, conveyance or gift of any of his property or a fraudulent purchase of any property in the name of another, the property fraudulently transferred, conveyed, given or purchased shall vest in the assignee. The assignee shall institute the proceedings necessary to recover the property so disposed of, using any remedy which a creditor might exercise. If the assignee upon demand refuses to institute such proceedings, any creditor may do so, and the property recovered shall become a part of the estate and be distributed as other assets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_080"><akn:num>379.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions claimed by assignor — Proceedings.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_080__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the assignor reserves any of his property as exempt, the court shall appoint three (3) competent and disinterested housekeepers, who, after being first duly sworn, shall set apart to the debtor the property exempt, and within ten (10) days thereafter the assignee shall file a report thereon. Exceptions may be filed to the report by any person in interest but not later than sixty (60) days after the report has been filed. The court shall hear and dispose of any exceptions and if none are filed it shall confirm the report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_080__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If land is exempt, an order shall be entered directing the assignee to employ, if necessary, a competent surveyor to lay off by metes and bounds the homestead exemption as set apart by the appraisers. The court may, with the consent of the assignor, and if it appears best for the interest of the creditors, or if the land is not divisible without impairing its value, order the property sold and the value of the homestead, not exceeding five thousand dollars ($5,000), paid to the assignor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_090"><akn:num>379.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of property by assignee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_090__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Personal property conveyed by the deed of assignment shall be sold by the assignee at private or public sale as the court may direct, and the assignee may pass title as fully as the assignor could have done at the date of the assignment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_090__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Real property, when sold at public sale, shall be sold in the same manner and upon the same terms as real property sold at decretal sale. However, the purchaser may pay and the assignee accept cash in payment of the purchase price, and the court may make any order it deems proper concerning the advertisement of the sale. The assignee may convey and pass all the right and title which the grantor in the deed of assignment had at its date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_090__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The report of sale shall be filed by the assignee within ten (10) days after the sale, and if no exceptions are filed thereto within sixty (60) days after it has been filed, the report shall be confirmed. If exceptions are filed, they shall be heard by the court and disposed of.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_100"><akn:num>379.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipt of claims by assignee — Notice of — Filing.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The assignee shall, within two (2) months after his appointment, give notice of the time and place where he will sit to receive claims against the estate. The notice shall be by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. Creditors not residing in the county where the assignee qualifies shall be notified by mailing notice to their last known address. Any creditor failing to present his claim at the time named or within three (3) months thereafter, verified in the same manner as a claim against the estate of a decedent except that it need not be verified by a person other than the claimant, shall waive his right to any part of the assigned estate. However, the court may direct the assignee to receive a claim at any time before the final distribution of the estate, and allow it and pay dividends thereon as on other claims, if there are sufficient unappropriated assets in his hands. Claims not due shall be presented in the same manner as claims due, but if claims not due are not bearing interest a just abatement shall be made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_110"><akn:num>379.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise or sale of debts due or claims against estate.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If it appears to be to the interest of the estate, the court may enter an order directing the assignee to sell, compound or compromise any debt due the estate, or to compromise any claim against the estate, but no such order shall be made within thirty (30) days after the application therefor has been made and filed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_120"><akn:num>379.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance or rejection of claims by assignee — Report to court — Exceptions — Court determination.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The assignee may administer oaths and examine witnesses concerning claims, and may allow or refuse to allow any claim or part thereof. He shall file in the District Court, within six (6) months after his appointment and every three (3) months thereafter until discharged, a list of all claims presented to him, together with his reasons for refusing any claim not allowed, and sixty (60) days thereafter the report shall be confirmed unless exceptions to it are filed. Any creditor may file exceptions to the report because of the failure to allow his claim, or because of the allowance of any claim, and the court shall hear and determine the exceptions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_130"><akn:num>379.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution — When to be made — Report on — Exceptions — Court determination.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As soon as practicable and within nine (9) months after his appointment, the assignee shall pay upon the claims allowed such an amount as the means on hand permit, after deducting expenses and his allowance, which shall be fixed by the court. He shall thereafter, when he has funds sufficient to pay five percent (5%) on the claims allowed, distribute that amount. Within fifteen (15) days after each distribution he shall file in court a report of the same, which shall lie over until the second regular term and if no exceptions are filed it shall then be confirmed. If exceptions are filed, they shall be heard and determined by the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_140"><akn:num>379.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge of assignee — Notice — Proceedings.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The assignee may, when he believes it is no longer to the interest of the estate to keep the assignment open, move the District Court to discharge him from the trust and release him from all liability. He shall have notice of his application to discharge published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. Sixty (60) days after the motion is entered, the court shall, upon proof that the required notice was given, enter an order discharging the assignee from his trust and releasing him from all liability, unless objection is made. If objection is made, the court shall hear the same and make such orders as are proper.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_150"><akn:num>379.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement or compromise by assignor with creditors to be filed in court — Assignee discharged.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the assignor settles or compromises with his creditors before the final discharge of the assignee or settlement of the estate, the writing showing the settlement or compromise shall be filed in the District Court and an order made discharging the assignee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_160"><akn:num>379.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals from judgments.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>An appeal may be taken from the judgment of the District Court overruling or sustaining an exception by the assignor, assignee or any party in interest, to the Circuit Court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_379_170"><akn:num>379.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Circuit court has jurisdiction of action for settlement of estate.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_379_170__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of KRS 379.010 to 379.160 shall not prevent an action to settle an estate by the assignee, or by any creditor or creditors representing one-fourth (1/4) of the liabilities, from being brought in the Circuit Court. When an action involving a settlement of the estate is brought in the Circuit Court of the county in which the assignment was made, the jurisdiction of the District Court shall cease, and all papers relating to the estate filed in the District Court shall be transferred by the clerk of the Circuit Court to the files of the Circuit Court. The Circuit Court may exercise any power conferred on the District Court by KRS 379.010 to 379.160 in administering and settling the assigned estate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_379_170__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The assignee may sell the personal and real property belonging to the assigned estate, at public or private sale, and convey and pass all the right and title to the same which the grantor had in the deed of assignment at its date. The assignee shall, within ten (10) days after the sale, report the sale to the Circuit Court in which the suit for settlement of the estate is pending. The report shall thereupon be laid over ten (10) days for exceptions, and if no exceptions are filed within that time the report shall thereupon be confirmed. If exceptions are filed, they shall be heard and determined by the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter><akn:chapter eId="chap_380"><akn:num>Chapter 380</akn:num><akn:heading>Debt Adjusting</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_380_010"><akn:num>380.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for chapter.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_020"><akn:num>380.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunction against debt adjuster — Appointment of receiver.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_030"><akn:num>380.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons exempt from classification as debt adjuster.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_040"><akn:num>380.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons engaged in debt adjusting — Powers and prohibitions — Requirements for registration, audits, insurance, and bond or letter of credit — Increase in amount of bond or insurance when debt is primarily for personal use.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_050"><akn:num>380.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative regulations governing debt adjusting.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_060"><akn:num>380.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Person engaged in debt adjusting to contract with debtor — Disclosure and notice to debtor — Debtor’s right to cancel.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_070"><akn:num>380.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Debt adjuster to take reasonable measures to protect debtor’s personal information.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_080"><akn:num>380.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Debt adjuster prohibited from sale of debtor’s personal information without written authorization — Confidentiality agreement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_090"><akn:num>380.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual disclosure of debt adjuster’s policies and practices to be provided to debtor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_100"><akn:num>380.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement for debt adjusting — Contents — Right to confer power of attorney upon debt adjuster — Prohibited provisions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_110"><akn:num>380.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Cause of action for loss resulting from violation of KRS Chapter 380 — Time limitation on prosecution of action.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_120"><akn:num>380.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of debtor’s rights void and unenforceable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_130"><akn:num>380.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of limitation on right of financial institution to collect valid debts.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_990"><akn:num>380.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_010"><akn:num>380.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for chapter.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this chapter, the following terms mean:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_010__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Person” includes, but is not limited to, individuals, partnerships, associations, corporations, limited liability companies, trusts, and other legal entities;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_010__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Debt adjuster” means a person engaged in the business of debt adjusting;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_010__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Debt adjusting” means doing business in this state in debt adjusting, budget counseling, debt management, debt modification or settlement, foreclosure assistance, or debt pooling service, or holding oneself out as acting or offering or attempting to act as an intermediary between a debtor and his or her creditors for a fee, contribution, or other consideration, or by words of similar import, as providing services to debtors in the management, settlement, modification, or adjustment of their debts, to do any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Effect the adjustment, compromise, settlement, modification, or discharge of any account, note or other indebtedness of the debtor; (b)Receive from the debtor and disburse to the debtor’s creditors any money or other thing of value; or (c)Solicit business and advertise as a debt adjuster;</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_010__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Reside” means to live in a particular place on a temporary or permanent basis;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_010__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Debtor” means an individual who resides in Kentucky and is indebted to a creditor or creditors, including two (2) or more individuals who are jointly and severally, or jointly or severally, indebted to a creditor or creditors;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_010__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)“Personal information” means any information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>1.That a debtor provides to a debt adjuster to obtain a debt-adjusting product or service from the debt adjuster; 2.About a debtor resulting from any transaction involving debt adjusting between a debtor and the debt adjuster; or 3.That a debt adjuster otherwise obtains about a debtor in connection with providing a debt-adjusting product or service to that debtor. (b)“Personal information” does not include information that a debt adjuster has a reasonable basis to believe is lawfully made available to the general public from: 1.Federal, state, or local government records; 2.Widely distributed media; or 3.Disclosures to the general public that are required to be made by federal, state, or local law. For purposes of this paragraph, “reasonable basis” to believe that information is lawfully made available to the general public means the debt adjuster has taken steps to determine that the information is the type that is available to the general public and whether an individual may direct that the information not be made available to the general public and, if so, that the debt adjuster’s consumer has not done so; and</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_010__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Additional interested party” means a party, including but not limited to the Attorney General, to whom written notice shall be sent at the same time that a notice is required to be sent to an insured regarding any cancellation, nonrenewal, modification, or change in the insurance coverage required by KRS 380.040(7).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_020"><akn:num>380.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunction against debt adjuster — Appointment of receiver.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_030"><akn:num>380.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons exempt from classification as debt adjuster.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The following persons shall not be considered debt adjusters for the purposes of this chapter:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_030__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any attorney-at-law admitted to the practice of law in this state by the Supreme Court of this Commonwealth, who is not principally engaged in the business of debt adjusting, when the person renders services in the course of his or her practice as an attorney-at-law;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_030__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who is a regular, full-time employee of a debtor, and who acts as an adjuster of his employer’s debts;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_030__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person acting pursuant to any order or judgment of court, or pursuant to authority conferred by any law of this state or of the United States;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_030__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who is a creditor of the debtor, or an agent of one (1) or more creditors of the debtor, and whose services in adjusting the debtor’s debts are rendered without cost to the debtor;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_030__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who arranges for or makes a loan to the debtor, and who, at the authorization of the debtor, acts as an adjuster of the debtor’s debts in the disbursement of the proceeds of the loan, without compensation from the debtor for the services rendered in adjusting the debts;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_030__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any charitable, religious or educational organization, determined to be exempt from taxation under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code that is not in the business of debt adjusting, as defined in KRS 380.010; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_030__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who is a creditor of the debtor, when adjusting a debt or debts owed by the debtor to the person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_040"><akn:num>380.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons engaged in debt adjusting — Powers and prohibitions — Requirements for registration, audits, insurance, and bond or letter of credit — Increase in amount of bond or insurance when debt is primarily for personal use.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Subject to subsection (3) of this section, a person, whether or not located in this state, who is engaged in debt adjusting and actually or constructively receives any money or other thing of value, other than the fees permitted by this chapter, for the purpose of disbursing the money or thing of value to the debtor’s creditors, shall do both of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Unless specifically instructed otherwise by a debtor, disburse to the appropriate creditors all funds received from the debtor, less any contributions or fees not prohibited by subsection (2) of this section, within thirty (30) days of receipt of the funds from the debtor; and (b)Maintain a separate trust account for the receipt of any funds from debtors and the disbursement of the funds to creditors on behalf of the debtors.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a fee, contribution, or other consideration for engaging in debt adjusting is accepted, directly or indirectly, a person engaged in debt adjusting shall not do any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Accept a fee, contribution, or other consideration exceeding seventy-five dollars ($75) from a debtor residing in this state for an initial set up; (b)Accept a fee, contribution, or other consideration exceeding fifty dollars ($50) per calendar year from a debtor residing in this state for consultation; (c)If money or anything else of value is received and held by the person engaged in debt adjusting for the purpose of disbursing the money or thing of value to the debtor’s unsecured creditors, accept a periodic fee, contribution, or other consideration from a debtor who resides in this state that exceeds the greater of eight and one-half percent (8.5%) of the amount paid by the debtor each month for distribution to the debtor’s creditors or thirty dollars ($30); or (d)Accept any other fee, contribution, or other consideration in advance of the complete performance of all promised services in relation to secured debt. Acceptance of a fee, contribution, or other consideration in advance of the complete performance of all promised services in relation to secured debt, including the placement of the fee, contribution, or other consideration into an escrow account to be paid upon completion of the services, is specifically prohibited. For purposes of this paragraph, “secured debt” means any debt primarily for personal, family, or household use that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, other equivalent consensual security interest on residential real property, or collateral that has a mortgage lien interest in residential real property.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall not prohibit a person engaged in debt adjusting for a debtor who resides in this state from charging the debtor a bad check charge of twenty dollars ($20) or the amount passed on from the debt adjuster’s bank, whichever is greater, in addition to fees, contributions, or other consideration not prohibited by subsection (2) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Fees, contributions, or other consideration permitted in subsections (1), (2), and (3) of this section may be adjusted on an annual basis by the amount equivalent to any increase in the consumer price index, published by the United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person that engages in debt adjusting shall file an initial registration form, accompanied by an initial registration fee of two hundred fifty dollars ($250), and the registration shall be renewed each year thereafter for a fee of two hundred fifty dollars ($250) to cover the actual cost of filing the registration, in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person that engages in debt adjusting shall arrange for and undergo an annual audit of the person’s business, including any trust funds deposited and distributed to creditors on behalf of debtors, which shall be conducted by an independent, third-party certified public accountant. Both of the following shall apply to an audit performed under this subsection:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The person shall file the results of the audit and the auditor’s opinion with the Consumer Protection Division of the Office of the Attorney General within thirty (30) days of the anniversary date of filing the initial registration; and (b)The Attorney General shall make available a summary of the results of the audit and the auditor’s opinion upon written request of any person and payment of a fee not to exceed the cost of copying the summary and opinion.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)A person engaged in debt adjusting shall obtain and at all times maintain insurance coverage for errors and omissions, employee dishonesty, depositor’s forgery, computer fraud, and violations of this chapter in the amount of ten percent (10%) of the monthly average for the immediately preceding six (6) months of the aggregate amount of all deposits made with the person by all debtors. The insurance coverage shall comply with all of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>1.The minimum limit of the insurance coverage shall not be less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), and the maximum limit of the insurance coverage shall not be more than two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000); 2.The insurance coverage shall not include a deductible in excess of ten percent (10%) of the face amount of the policy coverage; 3.The insurance coverage shall be issued by an insurer and rated at least A-, or its equivalent, by a nationally recognized rating organization; and 4.The insurance coverage shall provide that the Consumer Protection Division of the Office of the Attorney General shall be named as an additional interested party. (b)If the debt adjuster engages in debt adjusting in relation to any debt that is primarily for personal, family, or household use that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, other equivalent consensual security interest on residential real property, or collateral that has a mortgage lien interest in residential real property, the amount of insurance coverage required in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be increased by two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000).</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)A debt adjuster shall maintain a bond issued by a surety company admitted to do business in this Commonwealth. The bond shall be in the amount of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) in favor of the Attorney General for the benefit of the Commonwealth for any violation of this chapter or any person suffering injury or loss by reason of any violation of this chapter. A copy of the bond shall be filed with the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)The bond required by paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be in effect during the period of the debt adjuster’s registration as well as for two (2) years after the debt adjuster ceases to provide debt-adjusting services to debtors. (c)A change in ownership of a debt adjuster shall not release, cancel, or terminate liability under any bond previously filed unless the Attorney General agrees in writing to the release, cancellation, or termination because the debt adjuster has filed a new bond meeting the requirements of paragraph (a) of this subsection. (d)The proceeds of the bond required by paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be paid to any person suffering injury or loss by reason of any violation of this chapter or to the Attorney General for any violation of this chapter or shall be paid pursuant to the terms of any order of a court of competent jurisdiction. Any person who is damaged by any violation of this chapter may bring an action against the bond to recover damages pursuant to this paragraph, provided the aggregate liability of the surety shall not exceed the amount of the bond. (e)In lieu of the bond required by paragraph (a) of this subsection, a debt adjuster may, with the written approval of the Attorney General, deliver to the Attorney General an irrevocable letter of credit issued or confirmed by a financial institution authorized by law to transact business in the Commonwealth. The irrevocable letter of credit shall be in the amount of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) in favor of the Attorney General for the benefit of the Commonwealth or any person suffering injury or loss by reason of any violation of this chapter. (f)If the debt adjuster engages in debt adjusting in relation to any debt that is primarily for personal, family, or household use that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, other equivalent consensual security interest on residential real property, or collateral that has a mortgage lien interest in residential real property, the amount of the bond required in paragraph (a) of this subsection or the irrevocable letter of credit approved pursuant to paragraph (e) of this subsection shall be increased by fifty thousand dollars ($50,000).</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A debt adjuster may not, directly or indirectly:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Misappropriate or misapply money held in trust; (b)Settle a debtor’s debt if the amount the debtor will owe after settlement is equal to or more than fifty percent (50%) of the amount of the debt prior to settlement unless, after the creditor has assented, the debtor assents to a settlement for which the amount the debtor will owe after settlement is equal to or more than fifty percent (50%) of the amount of the debt prior to settlement; (c)Take a power of attorney that authorizes the debt adjuster to settle a debt, unless the power of attorney is expressly limited to the debtor’s debts and grants authority to settle debts only if the amount the debtor will owe after settlement is less than fifty percent (50%) of the amount of the debt prior to settlement. However, in no event shall an agreement confer on a debt adjuster a power of attorney to negotiate or settle any of the debtor’s debt that is primarily for personal, family, or household use that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, other equivalent consensual security interest on residential real property, or collateral that has a mortgage lien interest in residential real property; (d)Exercise or attempt to exercise a power of attorney after a debtor has terminated an agreement; (e)Initiate a transfer from a debtor’s account at a bank or with another person unless the transfer is: 1.A return of money to the debtor; or 2.Before termination of an agreement, properly authorized by the agreement and this chapter, and for payment to one (1) or more creditors pursuant to a plan or payment of a fee; (f)Structure a plan in a manner that would result in a negative amortization of any of a debtor’s debts, unless a creditor that is owed a negatively amortizing debt agrees to refund or waive the finance charge upon payment of the principal amount of the debt; (g)Settle a debt or lead a debtor to believe that a payment to a creditor is in settlement of a debt to the creditor unless, at the time of settlement, the debtor receives a certification by the creditor that the payment is in full settlement of the debt or is part of a payment plan, the terms of which are included in the certification, that upon completion will lead to full settlement of the debt; (h)Make a representation that: 1.The debt adjuster will furnish money to pay bills or prevent attachments; 2.Payment of a certain amount will permit satisfaction of a certain amount or range of indebtedness; 3.Participation in a plan will or may prevent litigation, garnishment, attachment, repossession, foreclosure, eviction, or loss of employment, and will or may stop efforts to collect a debt from the debtor; 4.Failure to make required minimum payments to creditors will not or may not break the terms of agreements with creditors, will not or may not lead creditors to increase finance charges and pursue litigation, will not or may not be reported to consumer reporting agencies, or will not or may not have an adverse effect on the debtor’s credit report and credit score; or 5.Fees paid to a debt adjuster will be used to pay creditors; (i)Misrepresent that it is authorized or competent to furnish legal advice or perform legal services; (j)Take a confession of judgment or power of attorney to confess judgment against a debtor; (k)Purchase a debt or obligation of the debtor; (l)Receive from or on behalf of the debtor: 1.A promissory note or other negotiable instrument other than a check or a demand draft; or 2.A postdated check or demand draft; (m)Lend money or provide credit to the debtor, except as a deferral of a settlement fee at no additional expense to the debtor; (n)Obtain a mortgage or other security interest from any person in connection with the services provided to the debtor; (o)Provide the debtor less than the full benefit of a compromise of a debt arranged by the debt adjuster; or (p)Charge the debtor for or provide credit or other insurance, coupons for goods or services, membership in a club, access to computers or the Internet, or any other matter not directly related to debt adjusting services or educational services concerning personal finance.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_040__point_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive act or practice in the conduct of debt adjusting is prohibited. For purposes of this subsection, “unfair” shall be construed to mean unconscionable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_050"><akn:num>380.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative regulations governing debt adjusting.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The Attorney General shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to ensure the proper administration and enforcement of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_060"><akn:num>380.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Person engaged in debt adjusting to contract with debtor — Disclosure and notice to debtor — Debtor’s right to cancel.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_380_060__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A person engaged in debt adjusting shall contract in writing with the debtor and obtain the debtor’s signature on the contract which shall designate the date on which the debtor actually signs the contract as the date of the transaction and fully disclose the exact nature of the debt-adjusting services and the total amount and terms of compensation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_060__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any debtor entering into a contract to provide debt-adjusting services shall have a right to cancel the contract until midnight of the fourteenth day after the day on which the debtor signs a contract offer to enter into a contract for debt-adjusting services, except as provided in subsection (7) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_060__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The following notice, printed in at least twelve (12) point boldface type and completed with the name and address of the debt adjuster, shall appear on the contract under the conspicuous caption “DEBTOR’S RIGHT TO CANCEL” and shall read as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>NOTICE OF CANCELLATION . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . (enter date of transaction) You may cancel this contract or offer without penalty or monetary obligation, within fourteen (14) days from the above date. To cancel this transaction, you may use any of the following methods: mail or otherwise deliver a signed and dated copy of this cancellation notice, or any other written notice of cancellation which you sign and date to (enter physical address of debt adjuster) or e-mail a notice of cancellation to (enter name of debt adjuster) at (enter e-mail address of debt adjuster) not later than midnight of (enter date fourteen (14) days after transaction date). I hereby cancel this transaction. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . (Date) . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . (Debtor’s Signature)</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_060__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Cancellation occurs when the debtor gives written notice of cancellation to the debt adjuster at the physical or e-mail address stated in the contract or offer to perform services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_060__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notice of cancellation, if given by mail, is given when it is deposited in a mailbox properly addressed and postage prepaid and, if given by e-mail, when the debtor sends the e-mail.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_060__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notice of cancellation given by the debtor is sufficient if it indicates in writing the intention of the debtor not to be bound by the contract or offer of services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_060__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Until the debt adjuster has complied with the disclosure notice required by subsection (3) of this section, the debtor may cancel the contract or offer of services by notifying the debt adjuster of his or her intention to cancel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_070"><akn:num>380.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Debt adjuster to take reasonable measures to protect debtor’s personal information.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_380_070__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A debt adjuster shall take reasonable measures to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Ensure the security and confidentiality of a debtor’s personal information; (b)Protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to the security or integrity of a debtor’s personal information; and (c)Protect against unauthorized access to or use of a debtor’s personal information.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_070__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The reasonable measures required by this section shall include, at a minimum:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Design and implementation of a comprehensive information security program that: 1.Is written in one (1) or more readily accessible parts; 2.Contains administrative, technical, and physical safeguards that are appropriate to the size and complexity of the debt adjuster, the nature and scope of the debt adjuster’s activities, and the sensitivity of any personal information at issue; 3.Designates one (1) or more employees to coordinate compliance with the information security program; and 4.Identifies reasonably foreseeable internal and external risks to the security, confidentiality, and integrity of the personal information of a debtor that could result in the unauthorized access to or use of the information, and assesses the sufficiency of any safeguards in place to control these risks. At a minimum, the risk assessment required by this subparagraph shall include consideration of risks in each relevant area of the debt adjuster’s operation, including employee training and management, information systems, information processing, information storage, information transmission, information disposal, and detecting, preventing, and responding to failures to comply with the information security program. (b)Design and implementation of information safeguards to control the risks identified by the risk assessment required by this subsection, as well as regular testing or other monitoring of the effectiveness of the safeguards of key controls, systems, and procedures; (c)Requirements for regular training of employees who will or may have access to records containing personal information of debtors regarding compliance with the information security program required by this subsection; (d)Oversight of service providers to whom personal information of a debtor will be disclosed, by taking reasonable steps to select and retain service providers that are capable of maintaining appropriate safeguards for the personal information at issue, as well as requiring service providers, by contract, to implement and maintain those safeguards; (e)Evaluation and adjustment of the information security program in light of the results of testing and monitoring, any material changes to the operation or business arrangements of the debt adjuster, or any other circumstances that the debt adjuster knows or has reason to know may have a material impact on compliance with the information security program; and (f)A requirement that when records containing personal information of a debtor are disposed of the records shall be shredded, erased, or otherwise modified so the personal information is made unreadable or indecipherable through any means.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_080"><akn:num>380.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Debt adjuster prohibited from sale of debtor’s personal information without written authorization — Confidentiality agreement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_380_080__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a debt adjuster shall not sell or transfer a debtor’s personal information unless the debtor provides a valid authorization that includes a specification that the debtor’s personal information may be sold or transferred by the debt adjuster who received the debtor’s personal information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_080__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An authorization shall:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Be in writing; and (b)Provide that prior to any sale or transfer of the debtor’s personal information, the debt adjuster shall obtain a written confidentiality agreement from the person to whom the personal information is sold or transferred stating that the person will not sell or transfer the debtor’s personal information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_090"><akn:num>380.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual disclosure of debt adjuster’s policies and practices to be provided to debtor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_380_090__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Prior to obtaining a debtor’s personal information, a debt adjuster shall provide a clear and conspicuous disclosure to the debtor of the debt adjuster’s policies and practices with respect to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Disclosing the debtor’s personal information to others, including the categories of personal information that may be disclosed; (b)Disclosing the personal information of persons for whom the debt adjuster is no longer providing a debt-adjusting service or product; and (c)Protecting the debtor’s personal information.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_090__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The disclosure required by this section shall also be provided to the debtor at least annually while the debt adjuster is providing debt-adjusting services or products to the debtor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_100"><akn:num>380.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement for debt adjusting — Contents — Right to confer power of attorney upon debt adjuster — Prohibited provisions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_380_100__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An agreement for debt adjusting shall:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Be in writing; (b)Be dated and signed by the debt adjuster and the debtor; (c)Include the name of the debtor and the address where the debtor resides; (d)Include the name, business address, and telephone number of the debt adjuster; (e)Be delivered to the debtor immediately upon formation of the agreement. Delivery of an electronic record occurs when the agreement is made available in a format in which the debtor may retrieve, save, and print the agreement and the debtor is notified that the electronic record is available; (f)Disclose: 1.The services to be provided; 2.The amount, or method of determining the amount, of all fees, individually itemized, to be paid by the debtor; 3.The schedule of payments to be made by or on behalf of the debtor, including the amount of each payment, the date on which each payment is due, and an estimate of the date of the final payment; 4.Whether a plan provides for regular periodic payments to creditors and, if a plan provides for regular periodic payments to creditors: a.Each creditor of the debtor to which payment will be made, the amount owed to each creditor, and any concessions the debt adjuster reasonably believes each creditor will offer; and b.The schedule of expected payments to each creditor, including the amount of each payment and the date on which it will be made; 5.Each creditor that the debt adjuster believes will not participate in the plan and to which the debt adjuster will not direct payment; 6.That the debt adjuster may terminate the agreement for good cause, upon return of unexpended money of the debtor; 7.That the debtor may cancel the agreement as provided in KRS 380.060; 8.That the debtor may contact the Attorney General with any questions or complaints regarding the debt adjuster; 9.The address, telephone number, and Internet address or Web site of the Attorney General; 10.That participation in a plan may not prevent litigation, garnishment, attachment, repossession, foreclosure, eviction, or loss of employment, and may not stop efforts to collect a debt from the debtor; 11.That failure to make required minimum payments to creditors may be breaking the terms of agreements with creditors, may lead creditors to increase finance charges and pursue litigation, may be reported to consumer reporting agencies, and may have an adverse effect on the debtor’s credit report and credit score; 12.The earliest date by which the debt adjuster will contact each creditor to attempt to adjust the debtor’s debts or, for settlement of unsecured debts, the estimated amount of money that shall be accumulated in savings before negotiations may begin; and 13.That fees paid to a debt adjuster will not be used to pay creditors; (g)Provide that the debtor has a right to terminate the agreement at any time, without penalty or obligation, by giving the debt adjuster written or electronic notice, in which event: 1.The debt adjuster will refund all unexpended money that the debt adjuster or its agent has received from or on behalf of the debtor for the reduction or satisfaction of the individual’s debt; and 2.All powers of attorney granted by the debtor to the debt adjuster are revoked and ineffective; (h)Provide that the debtor authorizes any financial institution in which the debt adjuster or its agent has established a trust account to disclose to the Attorney General any financial records relating to the trust account; and (i)Provide that the debt adjuster will notify the debtor within five (5) days after learning of a creditor’s decision to reject or withdraw from a plan. This notice shall include: 1.The identity of the creditor; and 2.The right of the debtor to modify or terminate the agreement.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_100__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An agreement may confer on a debt adjuster a power of attorney to negotiate with creditors of the debtor on behalf of the debtor and to settle the debtor’s debt if the amount the debtor will owe after settlement is less than fifty percent (50%) of the amount of the debt prior to settlement. An agreement shall not confer a power of attorney to settle the debtor’s debt if the amount the debtor will owe after settlement is equal to or more than fifty percent (50%) of the amount of the debt prior to settlement. An agreement shall provide that the debt adjuster shall obtain the assent of the debtor prior to settling a debt if the creditor has assented to a settlement for which the amount the debtor will owe after settlement is equal to or more than fifty percent (50%) of the amount of the debt prior to settlement. However, in no event shall an agreement confer on a debt adjuster a power of attorney to negotiate or settle any of the debtor’s debt that is primarily for personal, family, or household use that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, other equivalent consensual security interest on residential real property, or collateral that has a mortgage lien interest in residential real property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_100__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An agreement shall not:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Provide for application of the law of any jurisdiction other than the United States and this state; (b)Contain a provision that restricts the debtor’s remedies under this chapter or under any other law; or (c)Contain a provision that: 1.Limits or releases the liability of any person for not performing the agreement or for violating this chapter; or 2.Indemnifies any person for liability arising under the agreement or this chapter.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_380_100__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>All rights and obligations specified in paragraphs (g), (h), and (i) of subsection (1) of this section, subsection (2) of this section, subsection (3) of this section, and KRS 380.060, exist even if not provided in the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_100__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A provision in an agreement which violates paragraphs (g), (h), and (i) of subsection (1) of this section, subsection (2) of this section, or subsection (3) of this section is void.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_110"><akn:num>380.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Cause of action for loss resulting from violation of KRS Chapter 380 — Time limitation on prosecution of action.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_380_110__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who enters into a debt-adjusting transaction and thereby suffers any ascertainable loss of money or property, real or personal, as a result of a violation of this chapter, may bring an action under the Rules of Civil Procedure in the Circuit Court in which the person resides or where the transaction in question occurred, to recover actual damages. The court may, in its discretion, award actual damages and may provide such equitable relief as it deems necessary or proper. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit a person’s right to seek punitive damages where appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_110__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon commencement of any action brought under subsection (1) of this section, the clerk of the court shall mail a copy of the complaint or other initial pleading to the Attorney General and, upon entry of any judgment or decree in the action, shall mail a copy of such judgment to the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_110__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any action brought by a person under this section, the court may award to the prevailing party, in addition to the relief provided in this section, reasonable attorney’s fees and costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_110__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person bringing an action under this section shall bring such action within one (1) year after any action of the Attorney General has been terminated or within two (2) years after the violation of this chapter, whichever is later.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_120"><akn:num>380.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of debtor’s rights void and unenforceable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any waiver by the debtor of rights or protections provided in this chapter is contrary to public policy, is void and unenforceable, and will not relieve the debt adjuster of any obligation placed upon the debt adjuster by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_130"><akn:num>380.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of limitation on right of financial institution to collect valid debts.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit the ability of a financial institution licensed by KRS Chapter 286 from collecting on debts it is owed by a debtor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_380_990"><akn:num>380.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_380_990__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any action brought alleging a violation of this chapter, if the court finds that a person is willfully using or has willfully used a method, act, or practice declared unlawful by this chapter, the Attorney General, upon petition to the court, may recover, on behalf of the Commonwealth, a civil penalty of not more than five thousand dollars ($5,000) per violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_990__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 380.040 in the state is guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction, shall be punished by a fine of five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisonment not to exceed sixty (60) days, or both such fine and imprisonment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_990__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A violation of this chapter shall be deemed an unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive practice in the conduct of trade or commerce in violation of KRS 367.170. All of the remedies, powers, and duties provided by KRS 367.190 to 367.300 and the penalties pertaining to acts and practices declared unlawful under KRS 367.170 shall apply with equal force and effect to acts and practices in violation of this chapter, except as provided in subsection (1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_380_990__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In addition to subsection (1) of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)A court may make such additional orders or judgments as may be necessary to restore to any person in interest any moneys or property, real or personal, which may have been paid out as a result of any practice in violation of this chapter; (b)A court shall have jurisdiction in an action brought in the name of the Commonwealth by the Attorney General or the county attorney, to enjoin, as an unfair or deceptive trade practice pursuant to KRS 367.170, the continuation of any debt-adjusting business or the offering of any debt-adjusting services as defined in KRS 380.010; (c)A court may appoint a receiver who shall have all the powers and authority pursuant to KRS 367.210 for the property and money employed in the transaction of business by a debt adjuster to ensure the return to debtors of their money and property received by the debt adjuster which has not been paid to the creditors of the debtors; and (d)In any action brought by the Attorney General or a Commonwealth or county attorney under this chapter, in which the Commonwealth has substantially prevailed, the court shall award, in addition to the relief provide elsewhere in this chapter, reasonable attorney’s fees, investigative costs, and litigation costs including expert witness fees and expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter></akn:title></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>