<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act name="KentuckyRevisedStatutes"><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title30" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title30" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2023-01" name="publication" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#kyGeneralAssembly" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us-ky" /><akn:FRBRname value="Kentucky Revised Statutes" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title30/eng@2023-01" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title30/eng@2023-01" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2023-01" name="publication" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title30/eng@2023-01.akn" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title30/eng@2023-01.akn" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification><akn:references><akn:TLCOrganization eId="kyGeneralAssembly" href="https://legislature.ky.gov" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly" /><akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" /></akn:references></akn:meta><akn:preface><akn:docTitle>Kentucky Revised Statutes - Title 30: Contracts</akn:docTitle></akn:preface><akn:body><akn:title eId="title_30"><akn:num>Title 30</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts</akn:heading><akn:chapter eId="chap_371"><akn:num>Chapter 371</akn:num><akn:heading>Formality and Assignability of Contracts — Installment Sales Contracts</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_371_010"><akn:num>371.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of frauds — Contracts to be written.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_020"><akn:num>371.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Seal not necessary on any writing — Exceptions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_030"><akn:num>371.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of writing may be impeached.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_040"><akn:num>371.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonds, bills and notes assignable — Effect of assignment.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_050"><akn:num>371.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignee to aver consideration — Amount recoverable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_060"><akn:num>371.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Written obligation, when enforceable by representative or survivor of deceased.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_065"><akn:num>371.065</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for valid, enforceable guaranty.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_070"><akn:num>371.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of promissory note made payable to obligor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_080"><akn:num>371.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Person signing back of note considered assignor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_090"><akn:num>371.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Agent’s authority to bind another as surety to be in writing.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_100"><akn:num>371.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract for sale of standing timber to be written.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_110"><akn:num>371.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Pledge or transfer of future wages — What instrument shall state.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_120"><akn:num>371.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Assent of employer required for pledge or transfer of wages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_130"><akn:num>371.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Copy to be delivered to wage earner — Endorsement of payments made — Effect of violation or fraud.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_140"><akn:num>371.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Instrument to be definite and to bear execution date.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_150"><akn:num>371.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_160"><akn:num>371.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit in escrow of amount held back by owner in contract involving improvement of real estate.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_170"><akn:num>371.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for the payment of manufacturers’ excise taxes.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_180"><akn:num>371.180</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction services contracts.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_190"><akn:num>371.190</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation of debtor not extinguished or affected by internal actions of creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_010"><akn:num>371.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of frauds — Contracts to be written.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No action shall be brought to charge any person:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>For any representation or assurance concerning the character, conduct, credit, ability, trade, or dealings of another, made with intent that such other may obtain thereby credit, money, or goods;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon any promise to pay a debt contracted during infancy, or any ratification of a contract or promise made during infancy;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon any promise of a personal representative as such to answer any liability of his decedent out of his own estate;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon any promise to answer for the debt, default, or misdoing of another;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon any agreement made in consideration of marriage, except mutual promises to marry;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon any contract for the sale of real estate, or any lease thereof for longer than one year;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon any agreement that is not to be performed within one year from the making thereof;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon any promise, agreement, or contract for any commission or compensation for the sale or lease of any real estate or for assisting another in the sale or lease of any real estate; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_010__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon any promise, contract, agreement, undertaking, or commitment to loan money, to grant, extend, or renew credit, or make any financial accommodation to establish or assist a business enterprise or an existing business enterprise including, but not limited to the purchase of realty or real property, but this subsection shall not apply to agreements pursuant to which credit is extended by means of a credit card or similar device, or to consumer credit transactions;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>unless the promise, contract, agreement, representation, assurance, or ratification, or some memorandum or note thereof, be in writing and signed by the party to be charged therewith, or by his authorized agent. It shall not be necessary to express the consideration in the writing, but it may be proved when necessary or disproved by parol or other evidence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_020"><akn:num>371.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Seal not necessary on any writing — Exceptions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A seal or scroll is not necessary in order to give effect to any writing. All unsealed writings shall stand upon the same footing with sealed writings, shall have the same effect, and the same actions may be brought thereon. This section does not apply to any law requiring the state or county seal or the seal of a court, corporation or notary to any writing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_030"><akn:num>371.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of writing may be impeached.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The consideration of any writing, with or without seal, may be impeached or denied by pleading.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_040"><akn:num>371.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonds, bills and notes assignable — Effect of assignment.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>All bonds, bills or notes for money or property are assignable so as to vest the right of action in the assignee; but, except in the case of negotiable instruments, the assignment shall not impair the right to any defense, discount or set-off that the defendant has and might have used against the original obligee, or any intermediate assignor, before the defendant received notice of the assignment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_050"><akn:num>371.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignee to aver consideration — Amount recoverable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In an action on any assignment of a writing, the consideration for the assignment shall be averred. The plaintiff shall recover no more than the consideration actually paid by him for the note or assignment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_060"><akn:num>371.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Written obligation, when enforceable by representative or survivor of deceased.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A written nonnegotiable obligation to a person or persons who, or some of whom, are dead at the time of its execution, may be proceeded on by the representative of that person or by the survivor, as if it had been executed in the lifetime of the deceased person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_065"><akn:num>371.065</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for valid, enforceable guaranty.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_065__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No guaranty of an indebtedness which either is not written on, or does not expressly refer to, the instrument or instruments being guaranteed shall be valid or enforceable unless it is in writing signed by the guarantor and contains provisions specifying the amount of the maximum aggregate liability of the guarantor thereunder, and the date on which the guaranty terminates. Termination of the guaranty on that date shall not affect the liability of the guarantor with respect to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Obligations created or incurred prior to the date; or (b)Extensions or renewals of, interest accruing on, or fees, costs or expenses incurred with respect to, the obligations on or after the date.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_065__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a guaranty may, in addition to the maximum aggregate liability of the guarantor specified therein, guarantee payment of interest accruing on the guaranteed indebtedness, and fees, charges and costs of collecting the guaranteed indebtedness, including reasonable attorneys’ fees, without specifying the amount of the interest, fees, charges and costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_070"><akn:num>371.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of promissory note made payable to obligor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If a nonnegotiable promissory note is made by the obligor payable to himself or to his order, and is signed on the back by the obligor, and then delivered, the signature and delivery shall constitute a promise to pay the face of the note at maturity to the party to whom the note is delivered, and that party may fill up the blank with words of promise, and recover on it as if he had been named as payee in the note. Such notes shall be assignable as are other promissory notes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_080"><akn:num>371.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Person signing back of note considered assignor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who signs his name upon the back of a nonnegotiable promissory note shall be considered an assignor as to the party holding it, unless a different purpose is expressed in writing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_090"><akn:num>371.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Agent’s authority to bind another as surety to be in writing.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No person shall be bound as the surety of another by the act of an agent unless the authority of the agent is in writing, signed by the principal, or, if the principal does not write his name, then by his sign or mark, made in the presence of at least one creditable attesting witness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_100"><akn:num>371.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract for sale of standing timber to be written.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No contract for the sale of standing trees or standing timber shall be enforceable by action unless the contract or some memorandum thereof is in writing, signed by the person to be charged or by his duly authorized agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_110"><akn:num>371.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Pledge or transfer of future wages — What instrument shall state.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No assignment, sale, pledge, mortgage or other transfer of wages to be earned or paid in the future, where the whole or a part of the consideration for the assignment, sale, pledge, mortgage or other transfer is a sum of money of less than two hundred dollars ($200) shall be valid unless the instrument evidencing it:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_110__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Is in writing subscribed by the assignor, and bears the true date of its signature by the assignor and the true date of delivery of the money;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_110__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Contains a true statement of the consideration, the amount of money advanced or paid, the interest and all other fees and charges paid or agreed to be paid by the assignor, the time when the debt, if any, matures and, if the debt is to be paid in installments, the date of payment of each installment; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_110__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Gives the full name and address of each assignee, vendee, pledgee or mortgagee. If the assignee, vendee, pledgee or mortgagee is a partnership, the instrument shall give the name of each member of the partnership, and if it is a corporation or a nonresident partnership or individual, the instrument shall give the name and address of some person in the state upon whom process may be served in any litigation involving the instrument.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_120"><akn:num>371.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Assent of employer required for pledge or transfer of wages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No such instrument shall be valid against the employer who is to pay the wages until the employer signifies in writing upon the instrument his assent to the assignment, sale, pledge, mortgage or transfer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_130"><akn:num>371.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Copy to be delivered to wage earner — Endorsement of payments made — Effect of violation or fraud.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_130__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No such instrument shall be valid against the wage earner unless a true and complete copy is delivered to him at or before the time of the payment of the consideration to him.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_130__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No such instrument shall be valid against any such wage earner in any case where the copy was, with or without the consent of the wage earner, taken from his possession, altered or destroyed by the assignee, vendee, pledgee or mortgagee, or his agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_130__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The assignee, vendee, pledgee or mortgagee shall, upon demand and the payment of ten cents ($0.10), furnish the wage earner an exact copy of the instrument. Any false statement made in the copy shall make the original instrument invalid against the wage earner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_130__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The time and amount of all payments made by the wage earner under the terms of the instrument shall be endorsed on the copy and on the original, and shall be a part thereof. A failure to endorse any such payment shall make the instrument invalid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_140"><akn:num>371.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Instrument to be definite and to bear execution date.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No such instrument shall be valid or enforceable unless it is for a fixed and definite part of the wages earned or to be earned during a period not exceeding ninety (90) days immediately following the date of the instrument. Any such instrument bearing any other date than that of its execution shall be void.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_150"><akn:num>371.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 371.110 to 371.150 do not apply to any national or state bank, or to any credit union or trust company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_160"><akn:num>371.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit in escrow of amount held back by owner in contract involving improvement of real estate.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_160__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If, in any contract in the amount of five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) or more involving the improvement of real estate, a certain amount or percentage of the contract is held back by the owner, that retained amount shall be deposited in a separate escrow account with a bank or trust company authorized to do business in the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_160__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As of the time of the deposit of the retained funds, they shall become the sole and separate property of the contractor to whom they are owed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_160__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The escrow agent shall promptly invest all escrowed principal in obligations selected by the escrow agent in its discretion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_160__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Upon satisfactory completion of the contract, to be evidenced by a written release by the owner, all funds accumulated in the escrow account, together with any interest thereon, shall be paid immediately to the contractor to whom it is owed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_160__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The escrow agent shall be compensated for its services in an amount agreed to by the owner, contractor, and escrow agent. The compensation shall be a commercially reasonable fee commensurate with fees being charged for handling of escrow accounts of similar size and duration. The compensation shall be paid from the escrow account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_160__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In the event the owner fails or refuses to execute the release provided for in subsection (4) of this section, then the contractor shall have a cause of action against the owner in a court of proper jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_160__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to contracts with the Commonwealth, any county, charter county, urban-county government, or municipality, or any other political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality of the Commonwealth, or school boards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_170"><akn:num>371.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for the payment of manufacturers’ excise taxes.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_170__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a contract requires one (1) party to reimburse another party for taxes levied under Part III of Subchapter A of Chapter 32 of the Internal Revenue Code, the party making the reimbursement, at its option, shall not be required to reimburse the other party more than one (1) business day before the other party is required to remit the taxes to the Internal Revenue Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_170__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a party chooses to exercise its option under subsection (1) of this section, and provision is not already provided in the contract, the party shall notify the other party in writing of its intention. The option may not be exercised until at least thirty (30) days after the written notification or the beginning of the next federal tax quarter, whichever is later.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_170__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The party to be reimbursed under subsection (1) of this section may require security from the reimbursing party for the payment of the taxes in proportion to the amount the taxes represent compared to the security required on the contract as a whole. The party to be reimbursed shall not change other payment terms of the contract due to the timing of the tax reimbursement, but may require the taxes to be reimbursed by electronic transfer of funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_180"><akn:num>371.180</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction services contracts.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_180__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)“Construction services contract” means: 1.A contract or agreement relating to the construction, alteration, repair, addition to, subtraction from, improvement to, or maintenance of any building, highway, road, railroad, excavation, or other structure, project, development, or improvement attached to real estate, including moving and demolition connected therewith; or 2.A contract or agreement relating to the planning, design, administration, study, evaluation, consulting, or other professional and technical support services provided in connection with any of the work or activities described in subparagraph 1. of this paragraph. (b)“Contractor” means the person offering a contract for services provided. (c)“Contractee” means the person providing services under a contract.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_180__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any provision contained in any construction services contract purporting to indemnify or hold harmless a contractor from that contractor’s own negligence or from the negligence of his or her agents, or employees is void and wholly unenforceable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_180__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section does not apply to construction bonds or affect the validity of insurance contracts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_180__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section does not affect contracts or agreements entered into before June 20, 2005.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_190"><akn:num>371.190</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation of debtor not extinguished or affected by internal actions of creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_190__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The obligation of a debtor or obligor to pay or satisfy a debt, liability, or other obligation, including an obligation to pay interest, is not extinguished or otherwise adversely affected, in whole or in part, by any internal action or reporting of internal actions taken by the creditor or other obligee for purposes of the creditor or obligee’s own financial, tax, or accounting records or affairs, including but not limited to treating the debt, liability, or other obligation as not collectible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_190__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall preclude the debtor or obligor, in any event, from proving that it has fully or partially paid or otherwise satisfied the debt, liability, or other obligation in accordance with the terms of the debt, liability, or other obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>Installment Sales Contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_210"><akn:num>371.210</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 371.210 to 371.330.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_220"><akn:num>371.220</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisites of retail installment contract.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_230"><akn:num>371.230</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts composed of more than one document.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_240"><akn:num>371.240</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts made by mail.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_250"><akn:num>371.250</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract not to be signed in blank — Acknowledgment of delivery of copy.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_260"><akn:num>371.260</akn:num><akn:heading>Time price differential — Prepayment.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_270"><akn:num>371.270</akn:num><akn:heading>Charge for installment defaults — Refinancing options.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_280"><akn:num>371.280</akn:num><akn:heading>Written statement of payments and amount unpaid.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_290"><akn:num>371.290</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation of subsequent purchases with existing contract — Memorandum — Allocation of payments.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_300"><akn:num>371.300</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisites of retail charge agreement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_310"><akn:num>371.310</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of contracts and agreements.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_320"><akn:num>371.320</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior acts and agreements of retail buyer do not waive requirements of KRS 371.210 to 371.330.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_325"><akn:num>371.325</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of waiver of defense clause as to defense acquired in third party materialmen’s lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_330"><akn:num>371.330</akn:num><akn:heading>KRS 371.210 to 371.330 do not affect validity of pre-1963 contracts.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_210"><akn:num>371.210</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 371.210 to 371.330.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 371.210 to 371.330, unless the context otherwise requires:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Goods” means all tangible chattels personal when purchased primarily for personal, family or household use and not for commercial, industrial or agricultural use, but not including motor vehicles as herein defined, money, things in action or intangible personal property other than merchandise certificates or coupons as herein described. The term includes such chattels which are furnished or used, at the sale of or subsequently, in the modernization, rehabilitation, repair, alteration, improvement or construction of real property as to become a part thereof whether or not severable therefrom. The term also includes merchandise certificates or coupons, issued by a retail seller, not redeemable in cash and to be used in their face amount in lieu of cash.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Services” means work, labor or services of any kind when purchased primarily for personal, family or household use and not for commercial or business use, but not including services for which the prices charged are required by law to be determined or approved by or to be filed, subject to approval or disapproval, with the United States or any state, or any department, division, agency, officer or official of either as in the case of transportation services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Motor vehicle” means any automobile, mobile home, recreational vehicle, motorcycle, truck trailer, semitrailer, truck tractor and bus designed and used primarily to transport persons or property on a public highway, or any vehicle designed to run only on rails or tracks or in the air, excepting however, any boat trailer and any vehicle propelled or drawn exclusively by muscular power.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Retail buyer” or “buyer” means a person who buys or agrees to buy goods or obtain services or agrees to have services rendered or furnished, from a retail seller.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Retail seller” or “seller” means a person regularly and principally engaged in the business of selling goods to retail buyers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Retail installment transaction” means any transaction in which a retail buyer purchases goods or services from a retail seller pursuant to a retail installment contract or a retail charge agreement, as defined in this section, which provides for a time price differential, as defined in this section, and under which the buyer agrees to pay the unpaid balance in one (1) or more installments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Retail installment contract” means an instrument, other than a retail charge agreement or an instrument reflecting a sale made pursuant thereto, entered into in this state evidencing a retail installment transaction. The term “retail installment contract” may include a chattel mortgage, a security agreement, a conditional sale contract and a contract in the form of a bailment or a lease if the bailee or lessee contracts to pay as compensation for their use a sum substantially equivalent to or in excess of the value of the goods sold and if it is agreed that the bailee or lessee is bound to become, or for no other or a merely nominal consideration, has the option of becoming the owner of the goods upon full compliance with the provisions of the bailment or lease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Retail charge agreement” means an instrument prescribing the terms of retail installment transactions which may be made thereunder from time to time and under the terms of which a time price differential, as defined in this section, is to be computed in relation to the buyer’s unpaid balance from time to time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Time price differential” however denominated or expressed, means the amount which is paid or payable for the privilege of purchasing goods or services to be paid for by the buyer in installments over a period of time. It does not include the amount, if any, charged for insurance premiums, delinquency charges, attorneys fees, court costs, or official fees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Cash sale price” means the price stated in a retail installment contract or in a sales slip or other memorandum furnished by a retail seller to a retail buyer under or in connection with a retail charge agreement, for which the seller would have sold or furnished to the buyer and the buyer would have bought or obtained from the seller the goods or services which are the subject matter of a retail installment transaction, if the sale had been a sale for cash. The cash sale price may include any taxes and charges for delivery, installation, servicing, repairs, alterations or improvements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_11"><akn:num>(11)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Official fees” means the amount of the fees prescribed by law for filing, recording or otherwise perfecting, and releasing or satisfying, a retained title, lien or other security interest created by a retail installment transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_12"><akn:num>(12)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Time sale price” means the total of the cash sale price of the goods or services and the amount, if any, included for insurance, if a separate identified charge is made therefor, and the official fees and the time price differential.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_13"><akn:num>(13)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Principal balance” means the cash sale price of the goods or services which are the subject matter of a retail installment contract plus the amounts, if any, included therein, if a separate identified charge is made therefor and stated in the contract, for insurance and official fees, less the amount of the buyer’s down payment in money or goods or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_14"><akn:num>(14)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Holder” means the retail seller of the goods or services under the retail installment contract or retail charge agreement or the assignee if the retail installment contract or the retail charge agreement or any indebtedness under either has been sold or otherwise transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_15"><akn:num>(15)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, partnership, joint venture, corporation, association or any other group, however organized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_210__point_16"><akn:num>(16)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Words of the masculine gender include the feminine and the neuter and, when the sense so indicates, words of the neuter gender may refer to any gender.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_220"><akn:num>371.220</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisites of retail installment contract.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_220__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Each retail installment contract shall be in writing, dated, signed by the retail buyer, and completed as to all essential provisions, except as otherwise provided in KRS 371.250.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_220__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The printed or typed portion of the contract, other than instructions for completion, shall be in a size equal to at least eight (8) point type. The contract shall be designated “Retail Installment Contract” and shall contain substantially the following notice printed or typed in a size equal to at least ten (10) point bold type: “NOTICE TO THE BUYER. DO NOT SIGN THIS CONTRACT BEFORE YOU READ IT OR IF IT CONTAINS BLANK SPACES. YOU ARE ENTITLED TO A COPY OF THE CONTRACT YOU SIGN.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_220__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The retail seller shall deliver to the retail buyer, or mail to him at his address shown on the retail installment contract, a copy of the contract as accepted by the seller. Until the seller does so, a buyer, who has not received delivery of the goods or been furnished or rendered the services, shall have the right to rescind his contract and to receive a refund of all payments made and return of all goods traded in to the seller on account of or in contemplation of the contract, or if such goods cannot be returned, the value thereof. Any acknowledgment by the buyer of delivery of a copy of the contract shall be in a size equal to at least ten (10) point bold type and, if contained in the contract, shall appear directly above the buyer’s signature.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_220__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The retail installment contract shall contain the names of the seller and the buyer, the place of business of the seller, the residence or other address of the buyer as specified by the buyer and a description or identification of the goods sold or to be sold, or services furnished or rendered or to be furnished or rendered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_220__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The retail installment contract shall contain the following items:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The cash sale price of the goods or services; (b)The amount of the buyer’s down payment, identifying the amounts paid in money and allowed for goods traded in; (c)The difference between items (a) and (b); (d)The aggregate amount, if any, included for insurance, if a separate identified charge is made therefor, specifying the type or types of insurance and the term or terms of coverage; (e)The aggregate amount of official fees; (f)The principal balance, which is the sum of items (c), (d) and (e); (g)The amount of the time price differential; and (h)The amount of the time balance owed by the buyer to the seller, which is the sum of items (f) and (g) and, except as otherwise provided in the next two (2) sentences, the maximum number of installment payments required and the amount of each installment and the due date of each payment necessary to pay such balance. If installment payments other than the final payment are stated as a series of equal scheduled amounts and if the amount of the final installment payment does not substantially exceed the scheduled amount of each preceding installment payment, the maximum number of payments and the amount and due date of each payment need not be separately stated and the amount of the scheduled final installment payment may be stated as the remaining unpaid balance. The due date of the first installment payment may be fixed by a day or date or may be fixed by reference to the date of the contract or to the time of delivery or installation. The above items need not be stated in the sequence or order set forth; additional items may be included to explain the computations made in determining the amount to be paid by the buyer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_230"><akn:num>371.230</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts composed of more than one document.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A retail installment contract need not be contained in a single document. If the contract is contained in more than one (1) document, one (1) such document shall be an original document signed by the retail buyer, stated to be applicable to purchases of goods or services to be made by the retail buyer from time to time. In such case such document, together with the sales slip, account book or other written statement relating to each purchase, shall set forth all of the information required by KRS 371.220 to 371.290 and shall constitute the retail installment contract for each purchase. On each succeeding purchase pursuant to such original document, the sales slip, account book or other written statement may at the option of the seller constitute the memorandum required by KRS 371.290.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_240"><akn:num>371.240</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts made by mail.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_240__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Retail installment contracts negotiated and entered into by mail without personal solicitation by salesmen or other representatives of the seller and based upon a catalog of the seller, or other printed solicitation of business, if such catalog or other printed solicitation clearly sets forth the cash sale prices and other terms of sales to be made through such medium, may be made as provided in this section. The provisions of KRS 371.210 to 371.330 with respect to retail installment contracts shall be applicable to such sales, except that:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The designation and notice provisions of subsection (2) of KRS 371.220 shall not be applicable to such contract; and (b)The retail installment contract, when completed by the buyer, need not contain the items required by subsection (5) of KRS 371.220.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_240__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>When the contract is received from the retail buyer, the seller shall prepare a written memorandum containing all of the information required by subsection (5) of KRS 371.220 to be included in a retail installment contract. In lieu of delivering a copy of the contract to the retail buyer as provided in subsection (3) of KRS 371.220, the seller shall deliver to the buyer a copy of such memorandum prior to the due date of the first installment payable under the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_250"><akn:num>371.250</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract not to be signed in blank — Acknowledgment of delivery of copy.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A retail installment contract shall not be signed by any party thereto when it contains blank spaces of items which are essential provisions of the transaction; provided, however, if delivery of the goods is not made at the time of the execution of the contract, the identifying numbers or marks of the goods or similar information and the due date of the first installment may be inserted by the seller in the seller’s counterpart of the contract after it has been signed by the buyer. The buyer’s acknowledgment, conforming to the requirements of KRS 371.220 to 371.290, of delivery of a copy of the contract shall be presumptive proof or, in the case of a holder of the contract without knowledge to the contrary when he purchases it, conclusive proof of such delivery and of compliance with this section in any action or proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_260"><akn:num>371.260</akn:num><akn:heading>Time price differential — Prepayment.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_260__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, a retail installment contract payable in substantially equal successive monthly installments beginning one (1) month from the date of the contract may provide for, and the seller or holder may then charge, collect, and receive a time price differential.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_260__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any retail installment contract to the contrary, any buyer may prepay in full the unpaid time balance thereof at any time before its final due date and, if he does so, shall receive a refund credit thereon for such prepayment. The amount of such refund credit shall represent at least as great a proportion of the original time price differential, after deducting therefrom a maximum of twenty dollars ($20), as (a) the sum of the monthly unpaid balances under the schedule of payments in the contract beginning as of the date after such prepayment which is the next succeeding monthly anniversary date of the due date of the first installment under the contract, or, if the prepayment is prior to the due date of the first installment under the contract, then as of the date after such prepayment which is the next succeeding monthly anniversary date of the date of the contract, bears to (b) the sum of all the monthly unpaid balances under the schedule of installment payments in the contract. Where the amount of refund credit is less than one dollar ($1), no refund credit need be made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_270"><akn:num>371.270</akn:num><akn:heading>Charge for installment defaults — Refinancing options.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_270__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The holder of any retail installment contract, if it so provides, may collect a delinquency and collection charge on each installment in default for a period of more than ten (10) days in the amount not to exceed five (5%) percent of each installment or ten dollars ($10), whichever is greater, provided that a minimum charge of one dollar ($1) may be made, or, in lieu thereof, interest after maturity on each such installment not to exceed the highest lawful contract rate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(2) The holder of a retail installment contract upon request by the buyer, may agree to an amendment thereto to extend or defer the scheduled due date of all or any part of any installment or installments or to renew, restate or reschedule the unpaid balance of the contract, and may collect for same a refinance charge not to exceed an amount ascertained as provided under either of the following optional methods of computation: Option I. The refinance charge may be computed on the amount of the scheduled installment or installments extended or deferred for the period of extension or deferment at the rate of one and one-half percent (1.5%) per month; provided that a minimum deferment charge of one dollar ($1) shall be permitted. Such amendment may also include payment by the buyer of the additional cost to the holder of premiums for continuing in force any insurance coverages provided for in the contract until the end of such deferral period, and of any additional necessary official fees. Option II. The refinance charge may be computed as follows: The sum of the unpaid balance as of the refinancing date and the cost for any insurance and other benefits incidental to the refinancing, and for any additional necessary official fees and any accrued delinquency and collection charges, after deducting a refund credit as for prepayment pursuant to subsection (2) of , shall constitute a principal balance for such refinancing on which the refinance charge may be computed for the term of the refinanced contract at the applicable rate for finance charges. Acquisition costs under the refund schedule in subsection (2) of shall not apply in calculating refinance charges. KRS 371.260 KRS 371.260 Click to view</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_270__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The amendment to the contract must be confirmed in a writing signed by the holder. The writing shall set forth the terms of the amendment and the new due dates and amounts of the installments, and shall either be delivered to the buyer or mailed to him at his address as shown on the contract. Said writing together with the original contract and any previous amendments thereto shall constitute the retail installment contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_280"><akn:num>371.280</akn:num><akn:heading>Written statement of payments and amount unpaid.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Upon written request of the buyer, the holder of a retail installment contract shall give or forward to the buyer a written statement of the dates and amounts of payments and the total amount unpaid under the contract. A buyer shall be given a written receipt for any payment when made in cash. Such a statement or receipt shall be given the buyer once without charge; if any additional statement is requested by the buyer, it shall be supplied by the holder at a charge not in excess of one dollar ($1) for each additional statement or receipt so supplied.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_290"><akn:num>371.290</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation of subsequent purchases with existing contract — Memorandum — Allocation of payments.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_290__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If, in a retail installment transaction, a retail buyer makes any subsequent purchases of goods or services from a retail seller from whom he has previously purchased goods or services under one or more retail installment contracts, and the amounts under such previous contract or contracts have not been fully paid, the subsequent purchases may, at the seller’s option, be included in and consolidated with one or more of the previous contract or contracts. Each subsequent purchase shall be a separate retail installment contract under KRS 371.210 to 371.330, notwithstanding that the same may be included in and consolidated with one or more of such previous contract or contracts. All the provisions of KRS 371.210 to 371.330 with respect to retail installment contracts shall be applicable to such subsequent purchases except as stated in subsections (2) to (7) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_290__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In the event of such consolidation, in lieu of the buyer’s executing a retail installment contract respecting each subsequent purchase, as provided in KRS 371.220 to 371.290, it shall be sufficient if the seller shall prepare a written memorandum of each subsequent purchase, in which case the provisions of subsections (1), (2), (3), and (4) of KRS 371.220 shall not be applicable. Unless previously furnished in writing to the buyer by the seller, by sales slip, memoranda, or otherwise, such memorandum shall set forth with respect to each subsequent purchase the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The cash sale price of the goods or services; (b)The amount of the buyer’s down payment, identifying the amounts paid in money and allowed for goods traded in; (c)The difference between items (a) and (b); (d)The aggregate amount, if any, included for insurance, if a separate identified charge is made therefor, specifying the type or types of insurance and the term or terms of coverage; (e)The aggregate amount of official fees; (f)The principal balance, which is the sum of items (c), (d), and (e); (g)The amount or rate of the time price differential; (h)The amount of the time balance owed by the buyer to the seller, which is the sum of items (f) and (g); (i)The outstanding balance of the previous contract or contracts; (j)The consolidated time balance, which is the sum of items (h) and (i); (k)The revised installments applicable to the consolidated time balance, if any. The seller shall deliver to the buyer a copy of such memorandum prior to the due date of the first installment of such consolidated contract.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_290__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>When such subsequent purchases are made, if the seller has retained title or taken a lien or other security interest in any of the goods purchased under any one of the contracts included in the consolidation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_290__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The entire amount of all payments made prior to such subsequent purchases shall be deemed to have been applied on the previous purchases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_290__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Each payment after such subsequent purchases made on this consolidated contract shall be deemed to have been allocated to all of the various purchases in the same ratio as the original cash sale prices of the various purchases bear to the total of all.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_290__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Where the amount of each installment payment is increased in connection with such subsequent purchases, at the seller’s option, the subsequent payments may be deemed to be allocated as follows: an amount equal to the original periodic payment to the previous purchase, the balance to the subsequent purchase. However, the amount of any down payment on the subsequent purchase shall be allocated in its entirety to such subsequent purchase.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_290__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of subsections (3), (4), (5), and (6) of this section shall not apply to cases where such previous and subsequent purchases involve equipment, parts, or other goods attached or affixed to goods previously purchased and not fully paid, or to services in connection therewith rendered by the seller at the buyer’s request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_300"><akn:num>371.300</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisites of retail charge agreement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_300__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Each retail charge agreement shall be in writing and signed or accepted by the buyer. A retail charge agreement shall be deemed to be signed or accepted by the buyer if, after a request for a retail charge account, the agreement or application for a retail charge account is in fact signed by the buyer, or if the retail charge account is used by the buyer, or if the retail charge account is used by another person authorized by the buyer to use it. The agreement shall not become effective until the buyer has received the disclosures required pursuant to the Federal Truth-in-Lending Act, 15 U.S.C. secs. 1601 et seq., and the buyer or person authorized by the buyer uses the retail charge account. A copy of any such agreement executed or accepted by the buyer on or after January 1, 1963, shall be delivered or mailed to the buyer by the seller prior to the date on which the first payment is due thereunder. Any acknowledgment by the buyer of delivery of a copy of the agreement contained in the body thereof shall be in a size equal to at least ten (10) point bold type and shall appear directly above the buyer’s signature. No agreement executed on or after January 1, 1963, shall be signed or accepted by the buyer when it contains blank spaces to be filled in after it has been signed. The buyer’s acknowledgment, conforming to the requirements of this subsection, of delivery of a copy of an agreement, shall be presumptive proof, in any action or proceeding, of such delivery and that the agreement, when signed or accepted, did not contain any blank spaces as provided in KRS 371.210 to 371.330. All retail charge agreements executed on or after January 1, 1963, shall state the maximum amount or rate of the time price differential to be charged and paid pursuant thereto. Any such agreement shall contain substantially the following notice printed or typed in a size equal to at least ten (10) point bold type: “NOTICE TO THE BUYER — DO NOT SIGN THIS AGREEMENT BEFORE YOU READ IT OR IF IT CONTAINS BLANK SPACES. YOU ARE ENTITLED TO A COPY OF THE AGREEMENT YOU SIGN.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_300__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The seller shall promptly supply the buyer under the retail charge agreement with a statement as of the end of each monthly period, which need not be a calendar month, or other regular period agreed upon in writing by the seller and the buyer, in which there is any unpaid balance thereunder, which statement shall recite the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The unpaid balance under the retail charge agreement at the beginning and at the end of the period; (b)Unless otherwise furnished by the seller to the buyer by sales slip, memorandum, or otherwise, a description or identification of the goods or services purchased during the period, the cash sale price and the date of each purchase; (c)The payments made by the buyer to the seller and any other credits to the buyer during the period; (d)The amount, if any, of any time price differential for such period; and (e)A legend to the effect that the buyer may at any time pay his total unpaid balance or any part thereof.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_300__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A retail charge agreement may provide for, and the seller or holder may then, notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, charge, collect and receive, in addition to the cash price, a time price differential for the privilege of paying in installments thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_300__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The holder of a retail charge agreement, if it so provides, may collect a delinquency and collection charge on each minimum payment in default for a period of more than ten (10) days in an amount not to exceed five percent (5%) of each minimum payment, or ten dollars ($10), whichever is greater.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_310"><akn:num>371.310</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of contracts and agreements.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_310__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An assignee may purchase or acquire or agree to purchase or acquire any retail installment contract or retail charge agreement or any indebtedness under either from a seller on such terms and conditions and for such price as may be mutually agreed upon;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_310__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Filing of the assignment, notice to the buyer of the assignment and any requirement that the seller be deprived of dominion over payments upon a retail installment contract or retail charge agreement, or over the goods if returned to or repossessed by the seller, shall not be necessary to the validity of a written assignment of the retail installment contract or retail charge agreement or any indebtedness under either as against creditors, subsequent purchasers, pledgees, mortgagees and lien claimants of the seller; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_310__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Unless the buyer has notice of the assignment of his retail installment contract, retail charge agreement or any indebtedness under either, payment therefor made by the buyer to the holder last known to him shall be binding upon all subsequent holders.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_320"><akn:num>371.320</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior acts and agreements of retail buyer do not waive requirements of KRS 371.210 to 371.330.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No act or agreement of the retail buyer before or at the time of the making of a retail installment contract, retail charge agreement or purchases thereunder shall constitute a valid waiver of any of the provisions of KRS 371.210 to 371.330 or of any remedies granted to the buyer by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_325"><akn:num>371.325</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of waiver of defense clause as to defense acquired in third party materialmen’s lien.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No waiver of defense clause in any retail installment contract shall operate to cut off any defense that an owner-occupant of a single or double family dwelling or the appurtenances or additions thereto may have acquired by virtue of a third party materialmen’s lien under KRS 376.010(4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_330"><akn:num>371.330</akn:num><akn:heading>KRS 371.210 to 371.330 do not affect validity of pre-1963 contracts.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of KRS 371.210 to 371.330 shall not invalidate or make unlawful retail installment contracts or retail charge agreements executed prior to January 1, 1963. Sales Representatives’ Contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_370"><akn:num>371.370</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 371.375 to 371.385.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_375"><akn:num>371.375</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of contract — Civil action — Liability of principal or sales representative.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_380"><akn:num>371.380</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal jurisdiction over nonresident principal.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_385"><akn:num>371.385</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver provisions to be void.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_370"><akn:num>371.370</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 371.375 to 371.385.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 371.375 to 371.385, unless the context otherwise requires:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_370__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Commissions” means compensation accruing to a sales representative for payment by a principal, the rate of which is expressed as a percentage of the amount of orders or sales or as a specified amount per order or per sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_370__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, partnership, association, estate, or trust.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_370__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Principal” means a person who does not have a permanent or fixed place of business in this state and who:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Manufactures, produces, imports, or distributes a tangible product for wholesale; (b)Contracts with a sales representative to solicit orders for the product; and (c)Compensates the sales representative, in whole or in part, by commission.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_370__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Sales representative” means a person who:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Contracts with a principal to solicit wholesale orders; (b)Is compensated, in whole or in part, by commission; (c)Does not place orders or purchase for his own account or for resale; and (d)Does not sell or take orders for the sale of products to the ultimate consumer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_375"><akn:num>371.375</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of contract — Civil action — Liability of principal or sales representative.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_375__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>When a contract between a sales representative and a principal is terminated for any reason, the principal shall pay the sales representative all commissions accrued under the contract to the sales representative within thirty (30) days after the effective date of such termination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_375__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A principal who fails to comply with the provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall be liable to the sales representative in a civil action for:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)All amounts due the sales representative, plus exemplary damages in an amount not to exceed two (2) times the amount of commissions due the sales representative; and (b)Attorney’s fees actually and reasonably incurred by the sales representative in the action and court costs.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_375__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Where the court determines that an action brought by a sales representative against a principal under KRS 371.370 to 371.385 is frivolous, the sales representative shall be liable to the principal for attorney’s fees actually and reasonably incurred by the principal in defending the action and court costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_375__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in KRS 371.370 to 371.385 shall invalidate or restrict any additional right or remedy available to a sales representative or preclude a sales representative from seeking to recover in an action on any other claim against a principal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_380"><akn:num>371.380</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal jurisdiction over nonresident principal.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A principal who is not a resident of this state that contracts with a sales representative to solicit orders in this state is declared to be doing business in this state for purposes of the exercise of personal jurisdiction over nonresidents under KRS Chapter 454.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_385"><akn:num>371.385</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver provisions to be void.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A provision in any contract between a sales representative and a principal purporting to waive any provision of KRS 371.370 to 371.385, whether by expressed waiver or by a contract subject to the laws of another state, shall be void.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_400"><akn:num>371.400</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 371.400 to 371.425.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_405"><akn:num>371.405</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions governing enforceability of construction contracts — Payment of amounts due.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_410"><akn:num>371.410</akn:num><akn:heading>Retainage that may be withheld — Release of retainage — Substantial completion.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_415"><akn:num>371.415</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of costs and attorney’s fees in action to enforce KRS 371.400 to 371.425.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_420"><akn:num>371.420</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title for KRS 371.400 to 371.425 — Filing of mechanic’s lien by contractor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_425"><akn:num>371.425</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of KRS 371.400 to 371.425.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_400"><akn:num>371.400</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 371.400 to 371.425.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 371.400 to 371.425:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Construction” means the process of building, altering, repairing, improving, or demolishing any structures or buildings, or other improvements of any kind to any real property, but does not include processing equipment used for the process of manufacturing or the routine maintenance of existing structures, buildings, or real property;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Contract” means a contract or agreement concerning construction made and entered into by and between a contracting entity and a contractor, a contractor and a subcontractor, or a subcontractor and another subcontractor;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Contracting entity” means an owner of real property; a trustee or agent of an owner of real property; or a public official, public authority, or other public entity authorized to contract under the Kentucky Revised Statutes;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Contractor” means a person performing construction and having a contract with a contracting entity;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Disputed amount” means to question in good faith the validity, either in whole or part, of a request for payment asserted by any party;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Owner” means a person who holds an ownership interest in real property;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, or any other legal entity;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Processing equipment” means equipment which uses physical or chemical methods to increase the value of a raw material or product and is installed by the person contractually responsible to the contracting entity for the design, purchase, installation, and performance of that equipment;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Retainage” means money earned by a contractor or subcontractor but withheld to ensure proper performance by the contractor or subcontractor and that shall be paid upon completion of contractual obligations;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Subcontractor” means any person performing construction covered by a contract between a contracting entity and a contractor who does not have a contract with the contracting entity; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_400__point_11"><akn:num>(11)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Undisputed amount” means a good faith, valid, accurate, timely request for payment which has been submitted to any entity owing money, that the recipient of the request for payment has reviewed and agrees that the money is due and owing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_405"><akn:num>371.405</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions governing enforceability of construction contracts — Payment of amounts due.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>All payments on construction contracts entered into after June 26, 2007, shall be made pursuant to the terms of the contract and as required in this section and KRS 371.410.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The following provisions in a contract for construction shall be against the public policy of this Commonwealth and shall be void and unenforceable:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)A provision that purports to waive, release, or extinguish the right to resolve disputes through litigation in court or substantive or procedural rights in connection with such litigation, except that a contract may require binding arbitration as a substitute for litigation or require nonbinding alternative dispute resolution as a prerequisite to litigation; (b)A provision that purports to waive, release, or extinguish rights provided by KRS Chapter 376, with the exception of partial waivers of lien rights provided by the contractor or subcontractor for progress payments; or (c)A provision that purports to waive, release, or extinguish the right of a contractor or subcontractor to recover costs, additional time, or damages, or obtain an equitable adjustment of the contract, for delays in performing the contract that are, in whole or part, within the control of the contracting entity. Unusually bad weather that cannot be reasonably anticipated, fire, or other act of God shall not automatically entitle the contractor to additional compensation under this paragraph.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (2)(c) of this section shall not render null, void, and unenforceable a contract provision that:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Permits a contractor or subcontractor to recover that portion of delay costs caused by acts or omissions of the contracting entity; (b)Requires notice of any delay by the party affected by the delay; (c)Provides for reasonable liquidated damages; (d)Provides for arbitration or any other procedure designed to resolve contract disputes; or (e)Specifies which costs are recoverable by a contractor or subcontractor for delay.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a provision of a construction contract is found to be null and unenforceable, that provision shall not affect other provisions of the contract that are in compliance with this section and, to this end, the provisions of the contract are severable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (7) of this section, all contracts for construction shall provide that payment of amounts due a contractor from a contracting entity, except retainage, shall be made within thirty (30) business days after the contracting entity receives a timely, properly completed, undisputed request for payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsection (7) of this section, if the contracting entity fails to pay a contractor within thirty (30) business days following receipt of a timely, properly completed, undisputed request for payment, the contracting entity shall pay interest to the contractor beginning on the thirty-first business day after receipt of the request for payment, computed at the rate of twelve percent (12%) per annum on the unpaid amount. Twenty-five (25) business days following the submission of a timely, properly completed, undisputed request for payment, the contractor shall notify the contracting entity by certified mail if payment has not been received. The notice shall also include the date on which interest shall begin to accrue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of subsections (5) and (6) of this section, a postsecondary institution and a board of education shall have forty-five (45) business days to make the payment required by those subsections. For purposes of payments by a board of education, the Department of Education shall have ten (10) business days, including the day the undisputed request for payment is received, to complete the final approval and application for payment and return it to the board of education. The ten (10) business days shall be included in the forty-five (45) business days. If the contracting entity fails to pay a contractor within forty-five (45) business days after receipt of the timely, properly completed, undisputed request for payment, the contracting entity shall, beginning on the forty-sixth day after receipt of the request, pay interest to the contractor computed at the rate of twelve percent (12%) per annum on the unpaid amount.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A contractor shall pay its subcontractors any undisputed amounts due within fifteen (15) business days of receipt of payment from the contracting entity, including payment of retainage if retainage is released by the contracting entity, if the subcontractor has provided a timely, properly completed, and undisputed request for payment to the contractor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a contractor fails to pay a subcontractor any undisputed amounts due within fifteen (15) business days of receipt of payment from the contracting entity, the contractor shall pay interest to the subcontractor beginning on the sixteenth business day after receipt of payment by the contractor, computed at the rate of twelve percent (12%) per annum on the unpaid amount.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_405__point_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Subsections (8) and (9) of this section shall apply to all payments from subcontractors to their subcontractors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_410"><akn:num>371.410</akn:num><akn:heading>Retainage that may be withheld — Release of retainage — Substantial completion.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_410__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes to the contrary, until fifty percent (50%) of the construction project has been completed in accordance with the contract, a contracting entity, contractor, or subcontractor may withhold no more than ten percent (10%) retainage from the amount of any undisputed payment due, and retainage held after fifty-one percent (51%) of the construction project has been completed shall not be more than five percent (5%) of the total contract amount.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_410__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Within thirty (30) days after substantial completion of a construction project, the contracting entity or contractor shall release the retainage less an amount equal to two hundred percent (200%) of the contracting entity’s reasonably estimated cost of the balance of any contractor’s or subcontractor’s contractually obligated, yet uncompleted, work remaining. The contracting entity’s agent shall determine the reasonably estimated cost due under this subsection. The contracting entity, contractor, and any subcontractor with work yet to be completed shall mutually agree with the schedule for completion of the work necessary for release of final payment. Within fifteen (15) business days after the retainage has been released by the contracting entity to the contractor, the contractor shall release to the subcontractors their proportional shares of the retainage. For purposes of this subsection, “substantial completion” is the point at which, as certified in writing by the contracting entity, a project is at the level of completion, in strict compliance with the contract, where:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Necessary approval by public regulatory authorities has been given; (b)The owner has received all required warranties and documentation; and (c)The owner may enjoy beneficial use or occupancy and may use, operate, and maintain the project in all respects, for its intended purpose. Partial use or occupancy shall not necessarily result in the project being deemed substantially complete and shall not be evidence of substantial completion.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_371_410__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a contracting entity, contractor, or subcontractor fails to pay retainage, if any, pursuant to the terms of a contract or as required in this section, the contracting entity, contractor, or subcontractor shall pay interest to the contractor or subcontractor to whom payment was due, beginning on the first business day after the payment was due, at the rate of twelve percent (12%) per annum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_415"><akn:num>371.415</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of costs and attorney’s fees in action to enforce KRS 371.400 to 371.425.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In any action to enforce KRS 371.400 to 371.425, including arbitration, the court or arbitrator shall award costs and reasonable attorney’s fees to the prevailing party if the losing party is deemed to have acted in bad faith. For public construction contracts, recovery of attorney’s fees under this section shall be limited to the public contract rate for attorney’s fees. Venue of such an action shall be within the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_420"><akn:num>371.420</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title for KRS 371.400 to 371.425 — Filing of mechanic’s lien by contractor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_420__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 371.400 to 371.425 shall be known and may be cited as the Kentucky Fairness in Construction Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_420__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes to the contrary, after a judgment for the contractor against a contracting entity is entered by a court of competent jurisdiction, a contractor has sixty (60) days to file a mechanic’s lien as provided in KRS Chapter 376. The filing of this lien shall not preclude the contractor from seeking additional relief. This subsection shall not apply to public construction contracts with lien rights governed under KRS 376.250.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_425"><akn:num>371.425</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of KRS 371.400 to 371.425.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_425__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in subsections (3) and (4) of this section, KRS 371.400 to 371.425 shall apply to public construction and public works projects, and to private construction, excluding residential construction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_425__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 371.400 to 371.425 shall apply to construction contracts entered into after June 26, 2007.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_425__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 371.400 to 371.425 shall not apply to contracts entered into by a borrower of funds that are provided, insured, or guaranteed by the United States Department of Agriculture’s Rural Utilities Service, or financed under a lien accommodation by the Rural Utilities Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_425__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 371.400 to 371.425 shall not apply to any contract for construction of or relating to any facility as defined in KRS Chapter 278.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>Penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_990"><akn:num>371.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_371_990"><akn:num>371.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_371_990__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 371.130, or assents to any such violation shall be fined not less than fifty (50) nor more than two hundred dollars ($200) for each offense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_990__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who shall willfully and intentionally violate any provision of KRS 371.210 to 371.330 shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be punished by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500) or by imprisonment for not more than six (6) months, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_990__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates any provision of KRS 371.210 to 371.330 except as a result of an accidental or bona fide error shall be barred from the recovery of any time price differential, or any delinquency or collection charge under or in connection with the related installment contract or retail charge agreement; but the holder may nevertheless recover from the buyer an amount equal to the cash price of the goods or services and the cost to the seller or holder of any insurance included in the transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_371_990__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (2), (3) and (4) of this section, any failure, other than a willful and intentional failure, to comply with any provision of KRS 371.210 to 371.330 may be corrected within ten (10) days after the holder is notified thereof in writing by the buyer and, if so corrected, neither the seller nor the holder is subject to any penalty under subsections (2), (3) and (4) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter><akn:chapter eId="chap_372"><akn:num>Chapter 372</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts Against Public Policy</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_372_005"><akn:num>372.005</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of chapter to legal gambling transactions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_010"><akn:num>372.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Gambling transactions void.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_020"><akn:num>372.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of gambling losses from winner or his transferee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_030"><akn:num>372.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable relief against winner — No penalty or forfeiture.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_040"><akn:num>372.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Suit by third person where loser or creditor does not sue.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_050"><akn:num>372.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of money or property held by stakeholder.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_060"><akn:num>372.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Champertous contracts and conveyances void.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_070"><akn:num>372.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of land adversely held — Subjection to claims of judgment creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_080"><akn:num>372.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract to recover land in adverse possession is void — Right of action to vest in state.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_090"><akn:num>372.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Champertous contract a defense in favor of adverse holder.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_100"><akn:num>372.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Parties to champertous contract may be required to testify — Immunity from prosecution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_110"><akn:num>372.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Person in possession may purchase adverse claim.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_120"><akn:num>372.120</akn:num><akn:heading>No right of action on champertous contract.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_130"><akn:num>372.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeitures not to apply to certain cases.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_140"><akn:num>372.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Power of attorney to confess judgment — Release of errors.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_160"><akn:num>372.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Mailing that contains item that appears to be check — Disclosure of consequences of signing — Offer for contract formation not valid without disclosure — Notice relating to time limit — Delivery of goods or services does not form contract — Remedies — Jurisdiction.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_990"><akn:num>372.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_005"><akn:num>372.005</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of chapter to legal gambling transactions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The terms and provisions of this chapter do not apply to betting, gaming, or wagering that has been authorized, permitted, or legalized, including, but not limited to, all activities and transactions permitted under KRS Chapters 154A, 230, and 238.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_010"><akn:num>372.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Gambling transactions void.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Every contract, conveyance, transfer or assurance for the consideration, in whole or in part, of money, property or other thing won, lost or bet in any game, sport, pastime or wager, or for the consideration of money, property or other thing lent or advanced for the purpose of gaming, or lent or advanced at the time of any betting, gaming, or wagering to a person then actually engaged in betting, gaming, or wagering, is void.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_020"><akn:num>372.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of gambling losses from winner or his transferee.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If any person loses to another at one (1) time, or within twenty-four (24) hours, five dollars ($5) or more, or anything of that value, and pays, transfers or delivers it, the loser or any of his creditors may recover it, or its value, from the winner, or any transferee of the winner, having notice of the consideration, by action brought within five (5) years after the payment, transfer or delivery. Recovery may be had against the winner, although the payment, transfer or delivery was made to the endorsee, assignee, or transferee of the winner. If the conveyance or transfer was of real estate, or the right thereto, in violation of KRS 372.010, the heirs of the loser may recover it back by action brought within two (2) years after his death, unless it has passed to a purchaser in good faith for valuable consideration without notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_030"><akn:num>372.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable relief against winner — No penalty or forfeiture.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person entitled to recovery under KRS 372.020 may have discovery and relief in equity; but when such relief is obtained, the winner shall be discharged from all penalty and forfeiture for having won the money or other thing which, or the value of which, is so recovered back.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_040"><akn:num>372.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Suit by third person where loser or creditor does not sue.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the loser or his creditor does not, within six (6) months after its payment or delivery to the winner, sue for the money or thing lost, and prosecute the suit to recovery with due diligence, any other person may sue the winner, and recover treble the value of the money or thing lost, if suit is brought within five (5) years from the delivery or payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_050"><akn:num>372.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of money or property held by stakeholder.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The stakeholder of any money or other thing staked on any bet or wager shall, when notified to do so, return the stake to the person who deposited it. If he fails to do so, the person aggrieved may recover from him the amount or value of the stake.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_060"><akn:num>372.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Champertous contracts and conveyances void.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any contract, agreement or conveyance made in consideration of services to be rendered in the prosecution or defense, or aiding in the prosecution or defense, in or out of court, of any suit, by any person not a party on record in the suit, whereby the thing sued for or in controversy or any part thereof, is to be taken, paid or received for such services or assistance, is void.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_070"><akn:num>372.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of land adversely held — Subjection to claims of judgment creditor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_372_070__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any sale or conveyance, including those made under execution, of any land, or the pretended right or title thereto, of which any other person has adverse possession at the time of the sale or conveyance, is void; but this section does not render void any devise of land in adverse possession.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_070__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A judgment creditor, after a return on the execution of no property found, may file a petition in equity to subject any real estate to which the defendant has legal or equitable title even if the property is in the adverse possession of another. The person in possession shall be made a defendant in any such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_080"><akn:num>372.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract to recover land in adverse possession is void — Right of action to vest in state.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any contract to prosecute an action for the recovery of any land in the adverse possession of another, for the whole or part of the land thus possessed, or for the whole or any part of the profits thereof, is void. The parties to the contract shall forfeit all right in and claim to the land, and all such rights and claims, and the right to maintain an action at law or in equity thereon, shall vest in the state, and inure to the benefit of the person in possession.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_090"><akn:num>372.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Champertous contract a defense in favor of adverse holder.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The person in the adverse possession, his personal representatives, heirs or assigns, or the person under whom the person in adverse possession claims or holds, or his personal representatives, heirs or assigns, may give in evidence under a general denial, or may plead, the sale or purchase of any pretended right or title in violation of KRS 372.070, or any contract or agreement made in violation of KRS 372.080, in bar of any action against him to recover the possession or title to the land so held.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_100"><akn:num>372.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Parties to champertous contract may be required to testify — Immunity from prosecution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Persons in possession, or the person under whom the occupant holds the land, may compel the parties to any such champertous contract to testify on the trial, or to make discovery by answer to petition in equity. The person so compelled to give evidence or to make discovery shall not be subjected thereby to any penal or criminal prosecution for champerty and maintenance, and the evidence or discovery shall not be used in any such prosecution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_110"><akn:num>372.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Person in possession may purchase adverse claim.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Persons in possession may purchase the adverse outstanding title or claim. The purchase shall be good and shall inure to the benefit of the person making it, or to the person under whom he claims and holds the land so possessed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_120"><akn:num>372.120</akn:num><akn:heading>No right of action on champertous contract.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Neither party to any contract made in violation of any of the provisions of KRS 372.060 to 372.120 shall have any right of action thereon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_130"><akn:num>372.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeitures not to apply to certain cases.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>None of the forfeitures declared by KRS 372.060 to 372.120 apply to cases of controversy between lessor and lessee, mortgagor and mortgagee, vendor and vendee or trustee and beneficiary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_140"><akn:num>372.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Power of attorney to confess judgment — Release of errors.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_372_140__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in KRS 457.150, any power of attorney to confess judgment or to suffer judgment to pass by default or otherwise, and any release of errors, given before an action is instituted, is void.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_140__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No person shall appear for a defendant under any such power in any court in this state.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_160"><akn:num>372.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Mailing that contains item that appears to be check — Disclosure of consequences of signing — Offer for contract formation not valid without disclosure — Notice relating to time limit — Delivery of goods or services does not form contract — Remedies — Jurisdiction.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any term which is defined in the Uniform Commercial Code, KRS Chapter 355, shall have that same meaning in this section, unless the context otherwise requires.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person soliciting business in this Commonwealth who intends to make an offer for contract formation by sending through the mail, as part of the solicitation, what appears to be a check or other item payable to the recipient where the indorsement and subsequent negotiation of the item by the recipient is intended by any party to the item, or agent or assignee thereof, to form an acceptance of the contract shall make the following disclosure in upper case twelve (12) point bold face type immediately adjacent to the designated place of indorsement: “BY SIGNING AND DELIVERING THIS DOCUMENT YOU AGREE TO PAY FOR FUTURE SERVICES ARISING OUT OF THIS CONTRACT.”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A purported offer described in subsection (2) of this section that does not contain the required disclosure, to the extent a subsequent indorsement and negotiation of the item would otherwise constitute an acceptance, shall not be a valid offer for contract formation in this Commonwealth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a purported offer which meets the requirements in subsection (2) of this section relates to a free membership period, trial period, or some other similar acceptance incentive that is prescribed by a time limit and which purports to form a contract without a cancellation, rescission, revocation, or other form of termination by the recipient prior to the end of such a period, then the offeror shall send notice to the recipient at least two (2) weeks prior to the end of that time period of the recipient’s purported obligation to cancel, rescind, revoke, or otherwise terminate the recipient’s purported acceptance before a purported contract is formed. The notice shall be readily apparent on any communication from the offeror and it shall be in upper case twelve (12) point bold face type and in the following form: “YOU MUST ACT NOW TO AVOID FUTURE CHARGES.” Any time period described under this subsection that is part of a purported offer described in subsection (2) of this section and that is less than two (2) weeks shall not be a valid offer for contract formation in this Commonwealth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a purported offer described in subsection (2) of this section does not contain the required disclosure, or is not followed by the required notice, then any goods or services delivered to the recipient pursuant to the purported offer shall not operate to form a contract by or between the offeror and the recipient. Any such offer or purported contract as a result thereof is void as against the public policy of the Commonwealth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An attempt by an offeror, or an agent or assignee thereof, to enforce a purported contract or to bind a recipient to a purported acceptance arising out of a purported offer that does not comply with this section shall be a violation of the Consumer Protection Act, KRS 367.170 to 367.300. Remedies available for a violation of KRS 367.170 to 367.300 shall be in addition to any remedies available at common law or under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The Attorney General, Commonwealth’s attorneys, and county attorneys shall have concurrent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this section in a court of the county where the purported offer was received.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any waiver by the recipient of jurisdiction for actions arising out of a purported offer under this section shall be void. Any depository bank or holder in due course of an item which does not meet the requirements of subsection (2) of this section or, as the case may be subsection (4) of this section, shall be held harmless by the offeror of the item, or an agent or assignee thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_372_160__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing contained in this section shall apply to licensed lenders that are regulated by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, or to a bank regulated by the federal government or any agency thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_372_990"><akn:num>372.990</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (2) of KRS 372.140 shall forfeit one thousand dollars ($1,000) to the defendant, and shall be liable to damages at the suit of the party aggrieved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter></akn:title></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>