<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act name="KentuckyRevisedStatutes"><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title36" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title36" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2023-01" name="publication" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#kyGeneralAssembly" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us-ky" /><akn:FRBRname value="Kentucky Revised Statutes" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title36/eng@2023-01" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title36/eng@2023-01" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2023-01" name="publication" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title36/eng@2023-01.akn" /><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-ky/act/krs/title36/eng@2023-01.akn" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification><akn:references><akn:TLCOrganization eId="kyGeneralAssembly" href="https://legislature.ky.gov" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly" /><akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" /></akn:references></akn:meta><akn:preface><akn:docTitle>Kentucky Revised Statutes - Title 36: Statutory Actions and Limitations</akn:docTitle></akn:preface><akn:body><akn:title eId="title_36"><akn:num>Title 36</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory Actions and Limitations</akn:heading><akn:chapter eId="chap_411"><akn:num>Chapter 411</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of Action and Survival of Actions</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_411_010"><akn:num>411.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for assault — Battery — Provocation as a defense or in mitigation of punitive damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_020"><akn:num>411.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Battery with certain weapons — Punitive damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_025"><akn:num>411.025</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against terrorist for injury to person or property — Damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_030"><akn:num>411.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for seduction — Proof.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_040"><akn:num>411.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Accusation of incest, fornication or adultery — Proof of damage.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_045"><akn:num>411.045</akn:num><akn:heading>Defenses allowed in action for libel or slander.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_050"><akn:num>411.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for libel; retraction of statement; effect.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_051"><akn:num>411.051</akn:num><akn:heading>Libel actions against newspaper, magazine, or periodical — Demand for and publication of correction — Effect.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_060"><akn:num>411.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for libel — Privileged communications.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_061"><akn:num>411.061</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions against a radio or television broadcasting station for damages for publication of a defamatory statement — Definitions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_062"><akn:num>411.062</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense to actions for damages for publication of a defamatory statement against a radio or television broadcasting station.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_065"><akn:num>411.065</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for disseminating personally identifying information — Exemption of service providers.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_070"><akn:num>411.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for falsely stating financial condition.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_080"><akn:num>411.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Wrongful distress or attachment — Reparation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_090"><akn:num>411.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of person gaming on premises without permission of owner.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_095"><akn:num>411.095</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for stealing or damaging goods of retailer or wholesaler.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_100"><akn:num>411.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of city for property damaged by mob.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_110"><akn:num>411.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against city for injury from defect in thoroughfare — Service of notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_115"><akn:num>411.115</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of action against governmental unit for damages from use of airport required — Contents.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_120"><akn:num>411.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to quiet title; court order if title proved.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_130"><akn:num>411.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for wrongful death — Personal representative to prosecute — Distribution of amount recovered.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_133"><akn:num>411.133</akn:num><akn:heading>Joinder of wrongful death and personal injury actions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_135"><akn:num>411.135</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages in action for wrongful death of minor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_137"><akn:num>411.137</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on right to recover for wrongful death of child if parent has abandoned care and maintenance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_140"><akn:num>411.140</akn:num><akn:heading>What action shall survive.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_145"><akn:num>411.145</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages for loss of consortium.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_148"><akn:num>411.148</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonliability of licensees and certified technicians for emergency care.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_150"><akn:num>411.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by surviving spouse or child of person killed with deadly weapon.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_155"><akn:num>411.155</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for damages resulting from criminal use of a firearm by another person.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_160"><akn:num>411.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolutions authorizing suit against Commonwealth not to be mentioned in trial of suit.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_165"><akn:num>411.165</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of attorney for professional negligence.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_167"><akn:num>411.167</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate of merit for medical malpractice actions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_170"><akn:num>411.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Action on lost, destroyed, mutilated or defaced writing.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_180"><akn:num>411.180</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions against joint obligors — Death of joint obligors — Effect of judgment against some.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_182"><akn:num>411.182</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of fault in tort actions — Award of damages — Effect of release.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_184"><akn:num>411.184</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions — Punitive damages — Proof of punitive damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_186"><akn:num>411.186</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of punitive damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_187"><akn:num>411.187</akn:num><akn:heading>Supersedeas bond to stay execution of judgment granting any relief during appeal — Limit — Rescission of limit if assets diverted or dissipated.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_188"><akn:num>411.188</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of parties holding subrogation rights — Collateral source payments and subrogation rights admissible.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_190"><akn:num>411.190</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations of owner to persons using land for recreation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_195"><akn:num>411.195</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforceability of written agreement to pay attorney fees in event of default.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_200"><akn:num>411.200</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from civil liability of officer, director or trustee of nonprofit organization.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_210"><akn:num>411.210</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for theft of identity or trafficking in stolen identities — Statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_212"><akn:num>411.212</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages caused by falsely reporting an incident — Liability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_215"><akn:num>411.215</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for failure to remove sexually explicit image from Web site, online service or application, or mobile application upon request — Damages — Statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_220"><akn:num>411.220</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by crime stalking victim against stalker — Damages — Statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_225"><akn:num>411.225</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer immunity from civil liability for disclosure of employee information — Exceptions — Effect of provision.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_230"><akn:num>411.230</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages caused by tampering with operations of key infrastructure asset.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Donations of Apparently Wholesome Food or Apparently Fit Grocery Product Look Before You Lock Act Construction Professionals’ Opportunity to Repair Home Inspectors’ Opportunity to Cure Product Liability Act Civil Liability for Theft of Motor Fuel Hazardous Materials Oil Spills Nuisances Commonsense Consumption Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_010"><akn:num>411.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for assault — Battery — Provocation as a defense or in mitigation of punitive damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In any civil action for damages inflicted by an assault or by an assault and battery, the defendant may plead as a defense to the claim for punitive damages, and introduce in evidence in mitigation of punitive damages, any matter of provocation that preceded the assault or battery, if the provocation prompted the assault or battery and was of a nature to cause a person of ordinary prudence and judgment to take the action taken by the defendant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_020"><akn:num>411.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Battery with certain weapons — Punitive damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person struck by another with any of the weapons popularly known as colts, brass knuckles, slung shots or sandbags, or any imitation or substitute therefor, may recover for the injury done. The jury may also award punitive damages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_025"><akn:num>411.025</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against terrorist for injury to person or property — Damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_025__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)“Act of terror” means an activity that: 1.Involves violent acts or acts dangerous to human life that violate federal or state law; 2.Appears to be intended to: a.Intimidate or coerce a civilian population; b.Influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion; or c.Affect the conduct of a government by mass destruction, assassination, or kidnapping; and 3.Occurs primarily within the Commonwealth; and (b)“Terrorist” means a person who commits an act of terror, including a person who acts as an accessory before or after the fact, aids or abets, solicits, or conspires to commit an act of terror or who lends material support to an act of terror.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_025__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person whose property or person is injured by a terrorist may file a claim for and recover damages from the terrorist.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_025__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who files an action under this section is entitled to recover three (3) times the actual damages sustained or fifty thousand dollars ($50,000), whichever is greater, as well as court costs and attorney’s fees in the trial and appellate courts if the person prevails in the claim.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_025__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A civil action brought under this section is remedial and does not limit any other civil or criminal action provided by law. Civil remedies provided under this section are supplemental and not exclusive.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_030"><akn:num>411.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for seduction — Proof.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>An action for seduction may be maintained without any allegation or proof of the loss of service of the victim by reason of the wrongful act of the defendant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_040"><akn:num>411.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Accusation of incest, fornication or adultery — Proof of damage.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>An accusation of incest, fornication or adultery against any person shall be actionable. In such a case the plaintiff shall not be required to allege or prove special damage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_045"><akn:num>411.045</akn:num><akn:heading>Defenses allowed in action for libel or slander.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In the actions for libel or slander, the defendant may state the truth of the alleged libel or slander, and any mitigating circumstances; and, whether he prove the justification or not, he may prove the mitigating circumstances to reduce the amount of damages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_050"><akn:num>411.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for libel; retraction of statement; effect.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_051"><akn:num>411.051</akn:num><akn:heading>Libel actions against newspaper, magazine, or periodical — Demand for and publication of correction — Effect.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_051__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any action for damages for the publication of a defamatory statement in a newspaper, magazine, or periodical, the defendant shall be liable for actual damages sustained by plaintiff. The defendant may plead the publication of a correction in mitigation of damages. Punitive damages may be recovered only if the plaintiff shall allege and prove publication with legal malice and that the newspaper, magazine, or periodical failed to make conspicuous and timely publication of a correction after receiving a sufficient demand for correction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_051__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A “sufficient demand for correction” is a demand for correction which is in writing; which is signed by the plaintiff or his duly-authorized attorney or agent; which specifies the statement or statements claimed to be false and defamatory, states wherein they are false, and sets forth the facts; and which is delivered to the defendant prior to the commencement of the action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_051__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A “correction” is either:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The publication of an acknowledgment that the statement or statements specified as false and defamatory in the plaintiff’s demand for correction are erroneous; or (b)The publication, in a fair and impartial manner as a matter of law, of the plaintiff’s statement of the facts (as set forth in his demand for correction) or a fair summary thereof, exclusive of any portions thereof which are defamatory of another, obscene, or otherwise improper for publication. If the demand for correction has specified two (2) or more statements as false and defamatory, the correction may deal with some of such statements pursuant to (a) above and with other of such statements pursuant to (b) above.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_051__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A “conspicuous publication” in a newspaper is a publication which is printed in substantially as conspicuous a manner as the statement or statements specified as false and defamatory in the demand for correction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_051__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A “timely publication” in a daily newspaper is a publication within ten (10) business days after the day on which a sufficient demand for correction is received by the defendant. A “timely publication” in a newspaper, magazine, or periodical other than a daily newspaper is a publication in or prior to the next regular issue which is published not less than ten (10) business days after the day on which a sufficient demand for correction is received by the defendant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_060"><akn:num>411.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for libel — Privileged communications.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The publication of a fair and impartial report of any proceeding before any state or city legislative or executive body, board or officer, or the whole or a fair synopsis of any bill, report, resolution, bulletin, notice, petition, or other document presented, filed, or used in any proceeding before any state or city legislative or executive body, board or officer, shall be privileged, unless it is proved that the publication was maliciously made. The publication of a fair and impartial report or the whole or a synopsis of any indictment, warrant, affidavit, pleading or other document in any criminal or civil action in any court of competent jurisdiction shall be privileged, unless it is proved that it was published maliciously, or that the defendant after request by the plaintiff has failed to publish a reasonable explanation or contradiction thereof, giving the explanation or contradiction the same prominence and space as the original publication, or that the publisher has refused after request by the plaintiff to publish the subsequent determination of the proceeding. This section shall not authorize the publication of any indecent matter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_061"><akn:num>411.061</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions against a radio or television broadcasting station for damages for publication of a defamatory statement — Definitions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_061__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any action against a radio or television broadcasting station for damages for the publication of a defamatory statement by a visual or sound radio broadcast, the plaintiff shall recover no more than special damages unless he shall allege and prove that he made a sufficient demand for correction and that the radio or television broadcasting station failed to make conspicuous and timely publication of said correction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_061__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A “sufficient demand for correction” is a demand for correction which is in writing; which is signed by the plaintiff or his duly authorized attorney or agent; which specifies the statement or statements claimed to be false and defamatory, states wherein they are false, and sets forth the true facts; and which is delivered to the defendant prior to the commencement of the action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_061__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A “correction” is either (a) the publication of an acknowledgment that the statement or statements specified as false and defamatory in the plaintiff’s demand for correction are erroneous, or (b) the publication of the plaintiff’s statement of the true facts (as set forth in his demand for correction) or a fair summary thereof, exclusive of any portions thereof which are defamatory of another, obscene, or otherwise improper for publication. If the demand for correction has specified two (2) or more statements as false and defamatory, the correction may deal with some of such statements pursuant to (a) above and with other of such statements pursuant to (b) above.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_061__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A “conspicuous publication” in a visual or sound radio broadcast is a publication which is broadcast at substantially the same time of day, and with the same sending power, as the statement or statements specified as false and defamatory in the demand for correction. A publication in a particular manner which is agreeable to the plaintiff shall in any event be deemed “conspicuous.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_061__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A “timely publication” in a visual or sound radio broadcast is a publication within one (1) business day after the day on which a sufficient demand for correction is received by the defendant. A “business day” is any day other than a Sunday or legal holiday. A publication on a particular day which is agreeable to the plaintiff shall in any event be deemed “timely.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_061__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Special damages” are pecuniary damages which the plaintiff alleges and proves that he has suffered in respect to his property, business, trade, profession, or occupation (including such amounts of money as the plaintiff alleges and proves he has expended as a proximate result of the alleged defamation), and no other.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_062"><akn:num>411.062</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense to actions for damages for publication of a defamatory statement against a radio or television broadcasting station.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If in any action for damages for the publication of a defamatory statement on a visual or sound radio broadcast, the defendant proves that said defamatory statement has been uttered by one other than the owner, licensee, or operator of the broadcasting station or one acting as the agent or employee of said owner, licensee or operator, the action shall be dismissed unless the plaintiff shall allege and prove that such owner, licensee, operator, agency or employee has failed to exercise due care to prevent the publication of said statement in said broadcast; provided, however, that bona fide compliance with any federal law or the regulation of any federal regulatory agency shall be construed as the exercise of due care; and provided, further, that in no event shall the owner, operator or licensee of a radio or television broadcasting station, or one acting as the agent or employee of such owner, operator or licensee, be held liable for the utterance of a defamatory statement in a visual or sound radio broadcast over the facilities of such station by any person speaking as a legally qualified candidate for public office, or on behalf of any such candidate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_065"><akn:num>411.065</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for disseminating personally identifying information — Exemption of service providers.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_065__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates KRS 525.085 shall be personally liable for actual and punitive damages, court costs, and reasonable attorney’s fees in a civil cause of action brought against an alleged perpetrator:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)By a victim; (b)By a victim’s parent or legal guardian on behalf of a victim who is a minor; and (c)By a victim’s immediate family member or household member, if he or she is harmed as a result of the same violation against the victim.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_065__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The action may be filed in the Circuit Court for the county where the alleged violation occurred or the county where the victim resides.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_065__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An individual found liable under this section shall be jointly and severally liable with each other person found liable under this section for the damages arising from the same violation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_065__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall be construed to impose liability on a broadband Internet access service provider, a telecommunications service provider, an interconnected VoIP provider, or a mobile service provider as defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 153, a commercial mobile service provider as defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 332(d), or a cable operator as defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 522, when acting in its capacity as a provider of those services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_070"><akn:num>411.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for falsely stating financial condition.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who violates KRS 517.090 shall be personally liable to any person damaged by the violation for the amount of the damage. This section shall not release the principal for whom the person may have acted from any liability, but the person liable and the principal for whom he acted in violating this section shall be jointly and severally liable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_080"><akn:num>411.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Wrongful distress or attachment — Reparation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If property is distrained or attached without good cause the owner may, in an action against the party suing out the distress or attachment, recover damages for the wrongful seizure. If the property is sold he may also recover damages for the sale, and the defendant’s costs in the distress or attachment, including reasonable attorney’s fees. The plaintiff shall not be required to allege or prove malice on the part of the defendant under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_090"><akn:num>411.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of person gaming on premises without permission of owner.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If any person shall, in any house, boat, float or premises, without the permission of the owner, controller or occupier, engage in any hazard or game in which money or property is bet, won or lost, he shall be liable to the owner, controller or occupier for all damages and costs, legal and extraordinary, sustained in consequence thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_095"><akn:num>411.095</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for stealing or damaging goods of retailer or wholesaler.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An adult or emancipated minor who damages, destroys, or takes possession of any goods, wares, or merchandise, stored, displayed, or offered for sale by any wholesale or retail store or other mercantile establishment, or who alters the price indicia of the merchandise, in violation of the provisions of KRS Chapters 512 and 514, without having paid the purchase price thereof, shall be civilly liable to the owner for actual damages, if any, and for a penalty to the owner in the amount of the retail value of the merchandise not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500), plus an additional penalty to the owner of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than two hundred fifty dollars ($250).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The custodial parents or legal guardian having custody of an unemancipated minor who damages, destroys, or takes possession of any goods, wares, or merchandise, stored, displayed, or offered for sale by any wholesale or retail store or other mercantile establishment, or who alters the price indicia of the merchandise, which would be a public offense, without having paid the purchase price thereof, shall be civilly liable to the owner for actual damages, if any, and for a penalty to the owner in the amount of the retail value of the merchandise not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500), plus an additional penalty to the owner of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than two hundred fifty dollars ($250). For purposes of this subsection, liability shall not be imposed upon any governmental entity, private agency, or foster parents assigned responsibility for the minor child pursuant to a court order or action of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or any agency thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, “owner” shall include any agent or employee of the owner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A conviction of an offense under KRS Chapters 512 or 514 is not a condition precedent to the maintenance of a civil action under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Civil liability under this section shall not be limited by any other law that limits liability of parents of minor children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action for recovery of damages, or penalty, or both, and costs under this section may be brought in any court of competent jurisdiction, including the small claims division of District Court, if the total amount sought does not exceed the jurisdictional limit of the respective court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The fact that an owner has a right to bring an action against any individual as provided in this section shall not limit the right of the owner to demand, in writing, that a person who is liable under this section remit the amount of the claim prior to the commencement of any legal action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Judgments, but not claims, arising under this section may be assigned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any civil damages or penalties, or both, which may be recovered under this section, a judgment for recovery shall also include court costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_095__point_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Civil claims under this section shall apply to those claims which arise after July 13, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_100"><akn:num>411.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of city for property damaged by mob.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If, within any city, any church, convent, chapel, dwelling house, house used or designed for the transaction of lawful business, vessel or shipyard, railroad or property of any kind belonging to any street or other railroad company, or any article of personal property is damaged, or if any property is taken away or damaged by any riotous or tumultuous assemblage of people, the full amount of the damage done may be recovered by the person injured by action against the city, if the city authorities themselves, or with the aid of their own citizens, could have prevented the damage. However, no such liability shall be incurred by the city unless the city authorities had notice or good reason to believe that a riot or tumultuous assemblage was about to take place in time to prevent the destruction, either by their own force or by the aid of the citizens of the city. No person may maintain an action under this section if he has unlawfully contributed by word or deed toward exciting or inflaming the tumult or riot, or if he failed to do what he reasonably could toward preventing, allaying or suppressing it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_110"><akn:num>411.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against city for injury from defect in thoroughfare — Service of notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No action shall be maintained against any city in this state because of any injury growing out of any defect in the condition of any bridge, street, sidewalk, alley or other public thoroughfare, unless notice has been given to the mayor, city clerk or clerk of the board of aldermen in the manner provided for the service of notice in actions in the Rules of Civil Procedure. This notice shall be filed within ninety (90) days of the occurrence for which damage is claimed, stating the time of and place where the injury was received and the character and circumstances of the injury, and that the person injured will claim damages therefor from the city.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_115"><akn:num>411.115</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of action against governmental unit for damages from use of airport required — Contents.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No action shall be brought against any governmental unit for damages, noise abatement or otherwise, arising from the operation of aircraft into or out of an airport unless written notice is given to such governmental unit within seven (7) days of the time within which each such operation occurred. Such notice shall state: (1) The location of the property affected; (2) The approximate time such operation occurred; and (3) If known, the type of aircraft and general direction of its flight.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_120"><akn:num>411.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to quiet title; court order if title proved.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person having both the legal title and possession of land may prosecute suit, by petition in equity, in the circuit court of the county where the land or some part of it lies, against any other person setting up a claim to it. If the plaintiff establishes his title to the land the court shall order the defendant to release his claim to it and to pay the plaintiff his costs, unless the defendant by his answer disclaims all title to the land and offers to give such release to the plaintiff, in which case the plaintiff shall pay the defendant’s costs, unless for special reasons the court decrees otherwise respecting the costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_130"><akn:num>411.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for wrongful death — Personal representative to prosecute — Distribution of amount recovered.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_130__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Whenever the death of a person results from an injury inflicted by the negligence or wrongful act of another, damages may be recovered for the death from the person who caused it, or whose agent or servant caused it. If the act was willful or the negligence gross, punitive damages may be recovered. The action shall be prosecuted by the personal representative of the deceased.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_130__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The amount recovered, less funeral expenses and the cost of administration and costs of recovery including attorney fees, not included in the recovery from the defendant, shall be for the benefit of and go to the kindred of the deceased in the following order:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)If the deceased leaves a widow or husband, and no children or their descendants, then the whole to the widow or husband. (b)If the deceased leaves a widow and children or a husband and children, then one-half (1/2) to the widow or husband and the other one-half (1/2) to the children of the deceased. (c)If the deceased leaves a child or children, but no widow or husband, then the whole to the child or children. (d)If the deceased leaves no widow, husband or child, then the recovery shall pass to the mother and father of the deceased, one (1) moiety each, if both are living; if the mother is dead and the father is living, the whole thereof shall pass to the father; and if the father is dead and the mother living, the whole thereof shall go to the mother. In the event the deceased was an adopted person, “mother” and “father” shall mean the adoptive parents of the deceased. (e)If the deceased leaves no widow, husband or child, and if both father and mother are dead, then the whole of the recovery shall become a part of the personal estate of the deceased, and after the payment of his debts the remainder, if any, shall pass to his kindred more remote than those above named, according to the law of descent and distribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_133"><akn:num>411.133</akn:num><akn:heading>Joinder of wrongful death and personal injury actions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>It shall be lawful for the personal representative of a decedent who was injured by reason of the tortious acts of another, and later dies from such injuries, to recover in the same action for both the wrongful death of the decedent and for the personal injuries from which the decedent suffered prior to death, including a recovery for all elements of damages in both a wrongful death action and a personal injury action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_135"><akn:num>411.135</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages in action for wrongful death of minor.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In a wrongful death action in which the decedent was a minor child, the surviving parent, or parents, may recover for loss of affection and companionship that would have been derived from such child during its minority, in addition to all other elements of the damage usually recoverable in a wrongful death action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_137"><akn:num>411.137</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on right to recover for wrongful death of child if parent has abandoned care and maintenance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_137__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A parent who has willfully abandoned the care and maintenance of his or her child shall not have a right to maintain a wrongful death action for that child and shall not have a right otherwise to recover for the wrongful death of that child, unless:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The abandoning parent had resumed the care and maintenance at least one (1) year prior to the death of the child and had continued the care and maintenance until the child’s death; or (b)The parent had been deprived of the custody of his or her child under an order of a court of competent jurisdiction and the parent had substantially complied with all orders of the court requiring contribution to the support of the child.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_137__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section may be cited as Mandy Jo’s Law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_140"><akn:num>411.140</akn:num><akn:heading>What action shall survive.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No right of action for personal injury or for injury to real or personal property shall cease or die with the person injuring or injured, except actions for slander, libel, criminal conversation, and so much of the action for malicious prosecution as is intended to recover for the personal injury. For any other injury an action may be brought or revived by the personal representative, or against the personal representative, heir or devisee, in the same manner as causes of action founded on contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_145"><akn:num>411.145</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages for loss of consortium.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_145__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section “consortium” means the right to the services, assistance, aid, society, companionship and conjugal relationship between husband and wife, or wife and husband.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_145__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Either a wife or husband may recover damages against a third person for loss of consortium, resulting from a negligent or wrongful act of such third person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_148"><akn:num>411.148</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonliability of licensees and certified technicians for emergency care.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_148__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No physician licensed under KRS Chapter 311, registered or practical nurse licensed under KRS Chapter 314, person certified as an emergency medical technician by the Kentucky Cabinet for Health and Family Services, person certified by the American Heart Association or the American Red Cross to perform cardiopulmonary resuscitation, or employee of any board of education established pursuant to the provision of KRS 160.160, who has completed a course in first aid and who maintains current certification therein in accordance with the standards set forth by the American Red Cross shall be liable in civil damages for administering emergency care or treatment at the scene of an emergency outside of a hospital, doctor’s office, or other place having proper medical equipment excluding house calls, for acts performed at the scene of such emergency, unless such acts constitute willful or wanton misconduct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_148__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section applies to the administering of such care or treatment where the same is rendered for remuneration or with the expectation of remuneration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_148__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The administering of emergency care or treatment at the scene of an emergency by employees of a board of education shall not be considered to be rendered for remuneration or with the expectation of remuneration because such personnel perform such care as part of their regular professional or work responsibilities for which they receive their regular salaries from the school board which is their employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_150"><akn:num>411.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by surviving spouse or child of person killed with deadly weapon.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The surviving spouse and child, under the age of eighteen (18) or either of them, of a person killed by the careless, wanton or malicious use of a deadly weapon, not in self-defense, may have an action against the person who committed the killing and all others aiding or promoting, or any one (1) or more of them. In such actions the jury may give vindictive damages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_155"><akn:num>411.155</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for damages resulting from criminal use of a firearm by another person.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_155__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A person or entity shall not be held liable for damages of any kind resulting from injuries to another person sustained as a result of the criminal use of any firearm by a third person, unless the person or entity conspired with the third person to commit, or willfully aided, abetted, or caused the commission of, the criminal act in which the firearm was used.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_155__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not be construed to negate, limit, or modify the doctrine of negligence or strict liability relating to abnormally dangerous products or activities and defective products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_160"><akn:num>411.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolutions authorizing suit against Commonwealth not to be mentioned in trial of suit.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_165"><akn:num>411.165</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of attorney for professional negligence.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_165__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If any attorney employed to attend to professional business neglects to attend to the business, after being paid anything for his services, or attends to the business negligently, he shall be liable to the client for all damages and costs sustained by reason thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_165__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If any attorney employed to attend to any professional business receives his fee and does not attend to the business, he may be sued and made to refund the fee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_167"><akn:num>411.167</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate of merit for medical malpractice actions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_167__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A claimant commencing any action identified in KRS 413.140(1)(e), or against a long-term-care facility as defined in KRS 216.510 alleging that the long-term-care facility failed to provide proper care to one (1) or more residents of the facility, shall file a certificate of merit with the complaint in the court in which the action is commenced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_167__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Certificate of merit” means an affidavit or declaration that:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The claimant has reviewed the facts of the case and has consulted with at least one (1) expert qualified pursuant to the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure and the Kentucky Rules of Evidence who is qualified to give expert testimony as to the standard of care or negligence and who the claimant or his or her counsel reasonably believes is knowledgeable in the relevant issues involved in the particular action, and has concluded on the basis of review and consultation that there is reasonable basis to commence the action; (b)The claimant was unable to obtain the consultation required by paragraph (a) of this subsection because a limitation of time established by KRS Chapter 413 would bar the action and that the consultation could not reasonably be obtained before that time expired. An affidavit or declaration executed pursuant to this paragraph shall be supplemented by an affidavit or declaration pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection or paragraph (c) of this subsection within sixty (60) days after service of the complaint or the suit shall be dismissed unless the court grants an extension for good cause; or (c)The claimant was unable to obtain the consultation required by paragraph (a) of this subsection because the claimant or his or her counsel had made at least three (3) separate good-faith attempts with three (3) different experts to obtain a consultation and that none of those contacted would agree to a consultation; so long as none of those contacted gave an opinion that there was no reasonable basis to commence the action.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_167__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A single certificate of merit is required for an action even if more than one (1) defendant has been named in the complaint or is subsequently named.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_167__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A certificate of merit is not required where the claimant intends to rely solely on one (1) or more causes of action for which expert testimony is not required, including claims of res ipsa loquitur and lack of informed consent, in which case the complaint shall be accompanied by an affidavit or declaration that no cause of action is asserted for which expert testimony is required.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_167__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a request by the claimant for the records of the claimant’s medical treatment by the defendants has been made and the records have not been produced, the claimant shall not be required to file a certificate of merit under this section until ninety (90) days after the records have been produced. For purposes of this section, “records” includes but is not limited to paper or electronic copies of dictations, video recordings, fetal heart monitor strips, and imaging studies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_167__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The identity and statements of an expert relied upon in subsection (2) of this section above are not discoverable, except:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)When a claim is made under subsection (2)(c) of this section that the claimant was unable to obtain the required consultation with an expert, the court, upon the request of a defendant made prior to compliance by the claimant with this section, may require the claimant to divulge to the court, in camera and without disclosure by the court to any other party, the names of the physicians refusing to consult; or (b)If any party to an action hereto prevails on the basis of the failure of an opposing party to offer any competent expert testimony, the court may, upon motion, for good cause shown compel the opposing party or party’s counsel to provide to the court the name of any expert consulted and any written materials relied upon in executing the certificate.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_167__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The claimant, in lieu of serving a certificate of merit, may provide the defendant or defendants with expert information in the form required by the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure. Nothing in this section requires the disclosure of any “consulting” or nontrial expert, except as expressly stated in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_170"><akn:num>411.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Action on lost, destroyed, mutilated or defaced writing.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>An ordinary or equitable action may be brought upon a bill of exchange, or a note or other obligation, or upon an indorsement or assignment thereof, which, or upon a judgment the record of which, is lost, destroyed, mutilated, or defaced, without fraud on the part of the plaintiff, or of those under whom he claims. But no action shall be brought upon an instrument transferable by delivery, merely, which is alleged to be lost, destroyed, mutilated, or defaced, without a previous tender by the plaintiff to the defendant, if his name and place of residence be known to the plaintiff, of an indemnifying bond, with good surety, nor shall judgment be given against the defendant, in such action, until such bond is given, with good surety approved by the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_180"><akn:num>411.180</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions against joint obligors — Death of joint obligors — Effect of judgment against some.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If two (2) or more persons be jointly bound by contract, the action thereon may be brought against all or any of them, at the plaintiff’s option. If any of the persons so bound be dead, the action may be brought against any or all of the survivors with the representatives of all or any of the decedents, or against the latter or any of them. If all the persons so bound be dead, the action may be brought against the representatives of all or any of them. An action or judgment against any one (1) or more of several persons jointly bound shall not be a bar to proceedings against the others.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_182"><akn:num>411.182</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of fault in tort actions — Award of damages — Effect of release.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_182__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In all tort actions, including products liability actions, involving fault of more than one (1) party to the action, including third-party defendants and persons who have been released under subsection (4) of this section, the court, unless otherwise agreed by all parties, shall instruct the jury to answer interrogatories or, if there is no jury, shall make findings indicating:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The amount of damages each claimant would be entitled to recover if contributory fault is disregarded; and (b)The percentage of the total fault of all the parties to each claim that is allocated to each claimant, defendant, third-party defendant, and person who has been released from liability under subsection (4) of this section.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_182__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In determining the percentages of fault, the trier of fact shall consider both the nature of the conduct of each party at fault and the extent of the causal relation between the conduct and the damages claimed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_182__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The court shall determine the award of damages to each claimant in accordance with the findings, subject to any reduction under subsection (4) of this section, and shall determine and state in the judgment each party’s equitable share of the obligation to each claimant in accordance with the respective percentages of fault.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_182__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A release, covenant not to sue, or similar agreement entered into by a claimant and a person liable, shall discharge that person from all liability for contribution, but it shall not be considered to discharge any other persons liable upon the same claim unless it so provides. However, the claim of the releasing person against other persons shall be reduced by the amount of the released persons’ equitable share of the obligation, determined in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_184"><akn:num>411.184</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions — Punitive damages — Proof of punitive damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_184__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section and KRS 411.186, unless the context requires otherwise:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)“Oppression” means conduct which is specifically intended by the defendant to subject the plaintiff to cruel and unjust hardship. (b)“Fraud” means an intentional misrepresentation, deceit, or concealment of material fact known to the defendant and made with the intention of causing injury to the plaintiff. (c)“Malice” means either conduct which is specifically intended by the defendant to cause tangible or intangible injury to the plaintiff or conduct that is carried out by the defendant both with a flagrant indifference to the rights of the plaintiff and with a subjective awareness that such conduct will result in human death or bodily harm. (d)“Plaintiff” means any party claiming punitive damages. (e)“Defendant” means any party against whom punitive damages are sought. (f)“Punitive damages” includes exemplary damages and means damages, other than compensatory and nominal damages, awarded against a person to punish and to discourage him and others from similar conduct in the future.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_184__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A plaintiff shall recover punitive damages only upon proving, by clear and convincing evidence, that the defendant from whom such damages are sought acted toward the plaintiff with oppression, fraud or malice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_184__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In no case shall punitive damages be assessed against a principal or employer for the act of an agent or employee unless such principal or employer authorized or ratified or should have anticipated the conduct in question.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_184__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In no case shall punitive damages be awarded for breach of contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_184__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This statute is applicable to all cases in which punitive damages are sought and supersedes any and all existing statutory or judicial law insofar as such law is inconsistent with the provisions of this statute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_186"><akn:num>411.186</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of punitive damages.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_186__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any civil action where claims for punitive damages are included, the jury or judge if jury trial has been waived, shall determine concurrently with all other issues presented, whether punitive damages may be assessed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_186__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the trier of fact determines that punitive damages should be awarded, the trier of fact shall then assess the sum of punitive damages. In determining the amount of punitive damages to be assessed, the trier of fact should consider the following factors:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The likelihood at the relevant time that serious harm would arise from the defendant’s misconduct; (b)The degree of the defendant’s awareness of that likelihood; (c)The profitability of the misconduct to the defendant; (d)The duration of the misconduct and any concealment of it by the defendant; and (e)Any actions by the defendant to remedy the misconduct once it became known to the defendant.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_186__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.184 and this section are applicable to all cases in which punitive damages are sought.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_187"><akn:num>411.187</akn:num><akn:heading>Supersedeas bond to stay execution of judgment granting any relief during appeal — Limit — Rescission of limit if assets diverted or dissipated.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_187__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any civil action brought under any legal theory, the amount of a supersedeas bond necessary to stay execution of a judgment granting legal, equitable, or any other relief during the entire course of all appeals or discretionary reviews of the judgment by all appellate courts shall be set in accordance with applicable law, except that the total amount of the supersedeas bonds that are required collectively of all appellants during the appeal of a civil action may not exceed one hundred million dollars ($100,000,000) in the aggregate, regardless of the amount of the judgment that is appealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_187__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the appellee proves by a preponderance of the evidence that a party bringing an appeal, for whom the supersedeas bond requirement has been limited, is purposefully dissipating or diverting assets outside of the ordinary course of its business for the purpose of avoiding ultimate payment of the judgment, the limitation granted under subsection (1) of this section shall be rescinded and a court may require the appellant to post a bond in an amount up to the full amount of the judgment pursuant to the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_188"><akn:num>411.188</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of parties holding subrogation rights — Collateral source payments and subrogation rights admissible.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_188__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section shall apply to all actions for damages, whether in contract or tort, commenced after July 15, 1988.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_188__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>At the commencement of an action seeking to recover damages, it shall be the duty of the plaintiff or his attorney to notify, by certified mail, those parties believed by him to hold subrogation rights to any award received by the plaintiff as a result of the action. The notification shall state that a failure to assert subrogation rights by intervention, pursuant to Kentucky Civil Rule 24, will result in a loss of those rights with respect to any final award received by the plaintiff as a result of the action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_188__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Collateral source payments, except life insurance, the value of any premiums paid by or on behalf of the plaintiff for same, and known subrogation rights shall be an admissible fact in any civil trial.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_188__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A certified list of the parties notified pursuant to subsection (2) of this section shall also be filed with the clerk of the court at the commencement of the action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_190"><akn:num>411.190</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations of owner to persons using land for recreation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_190__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)“Land” means land, roads, water, watercourses, private ways and buildings, structures, and machinery or equipment when attached to the realty; (b)“Owner” means the possessor of a fee, reversionary, or easement interest, a tenant, lessee, occupant, or person in control of the premises; (c)“Recreational purpose” includes, but is not limited to, any of the following, or any combination thereof: hunting, fishing, swimming, boating, camping, picnicking, hiking, bicycling, horseback riding, pleasure driving, nature study, water-skiing, winter sports, and viewing or enjoying historical, archaeological, scenic, or scientific sites; and (d)“Charge” means the admission price or fee asked in return for invitation or permission to enter or go upon the land but does not include fees for general use permits issued by a government agency for access to public lands if the permits are valid for a period of not less than thirty (30) days.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_190__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The purpose of this section is to encourage owners of land to make land and water areas available to the public for recreational purposes by limiting their liability toward persons entering thereon for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_190__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Except as specifically recognized by or provided in subsection (6) of this section, an owner of land owes no duty of care to keep the premises safe for entry or use by others for recreational purposes, or to give any warning of a dangerous condition, use, structure, or activity on the premises to persons entering for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_190__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Except as specifically recognized by or provided in subsection (6) of this section, an owner of land who either directly or indirectly invites or permits without charge any person to use the property for recreation purposes does not thereby:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Extend any assurance that the premises are safe for any purpose; (b)Confer upon the person the legal status of an invitee or licensee to whom a duty of care is owed; or (c)Assume responsibility for or incur liability for any injury to person or property caused by an act or omission of those persons.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_190__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Unless otherwise agreed in writing, the provisions of subsections (3) and (4) of this section shall be deemed applicable to the duties and liability of an owner of land leased to the state or any subdivision thereof for recreational purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_190__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section limits in any way any liability which otherwise exists:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)For willful or malicious failure to guard or warn against a dangerous condition, use, structure, or activity; or (b)For injury suffered in any case where the owner of land charges the person or persons who enter or go on the land for the recreational use thereof, except that in the case of land leased to the state or a subdivision thereof, any consideration received by the owner for the lease shall not be deemed a charge within the meaning of this section.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_190__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall be construed to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Create a duty of care or ground of liability for injury to persons or property; (b)Relieve any person using the land of another for recreational purposes from any obligation which he may have in the absence of this section to exercise care in his use of the land and in his activities thereon, or from the legal consequences of failure to employ such care; or (c)Ripen into a claim for adverse possession, absent a claim of title or legal right.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_190__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No action for the recovery of real property, including establishment of prescriptive easement, right-of-way, or adverse possession, may be brought by any person whose claim is based on use solely for recreational purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_195"><akn:num>411.195</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforceability of written agreement to pay attorney fees in event of default.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any provisions in a writing which create a debt, or create a lien on real property, requiring the debtor, obligor, lienor or mortgagor to pay reasonable attorney fees incurred by the creditor, obligee or lienholder in the event of default, shall be enforceable, provided, however, such fees shall only be allowed to the extent actually paid or agreed to be paid, and shall not be allowed to a salaried employee of such creditor, obligor or lienholder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_200"><akn:num>411.200</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from civil liability of officer, director or trustee of nonprofit organization.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Any person who serves as a director, officer, volunteer or trustee of a nonprofit organization qualified as a tax-exempt organization under Section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as from time to time amended, and who is not compensated for such services on a salary or prorated equivalent basis, shall be immune from civil liability for any act or omission resulting in damage or injury occurring on or after July 15, 1988, if such person was acting in good faith and within the scope of his official functions and duties, unless such damage or injury was caused by the willful or wanton misconduct of such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_210"><akn:num>411.210</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for theft of identity or trafficking in stolen identities — Statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_210__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In addition to pursuing any other remedy, anyone who is a victim under KRS 434.872, 434.874, 514.160, or 514.170, shall have a cause of action, either where the victim resides or the defendant resides, for compensatory and punitive damages against anyone who violates KRS 434.872, 434.874, 514.160, or 514.170 and, if successful, shall be awarded reasonable costs and attorneys’ fees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_210__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The statute of limitations for cases under the provisions of this section shall be five (5) years from the date of the discovery of the violation of KRS 434.872, 434.874, 514.160, or 514.170.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_212"><akn:num>411.212</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages caused by falsely reporting an incident — Liability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_212__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In addition to any restitution ordered by the court under KRS 519.040(4), any person who suffers harm as a result of a violation of KRS 519.040(1)(a) or (e) may recover damages in a civil cause of action against the alleged perpetrator, including but not limited to damages for infliction of emotional distress, compensatory and punitive damages, court costs, and reasonable attorney’s fees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_212__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The action may be filed in a court of competent jurisdiction for the county in which the alleged violation occurred or the plaintiff resides.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_212__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An individual found liable under this section shall be jointly and severally liable with each other person, if any, found liable under this section for the damages arising from the same violation of KRS 519.040.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_215"><akn:num>411.215</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for failure to remove sexually explicit image from Web site, online service or application, or mobile application upon request — Damages — Statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_215__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A civil action may be maintained under this section against any person who, in violation of KRS 531.120(3), does not remove a sexually explicit image upon the request of the person depicted in the image.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_215__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A civil action may be maintained under this section whether or not the individual who is alleged to have violated KRS 531.120(3) has been charged or convicted under KRS 531.120. Liability under this section shall include damages of one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each sexually explicit image for each day the image remains on the Web site after receipt of the request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_215__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action under this section shall be brought within two (2) years of the last act of conduct in violation of KRS 531.120(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_220"><akn:num>411.220</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by crime stalking victim against stalker — Damages — Statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A civil action may be maintained under this section against any person who commits the conduct prohibited under KRS 508.140 or 508.150. A civil action may be maintained under this section whether or not the individual who is alleged to have violated KRS 508.140 or 508.150 has been charged or convicted of the alleged crime. Liability under this section shall include the actual damages caused by the violation and may include punitive damages, court costs, and reasonable attorney’s fees. An action under this section shall be brought within two (2) years of the last act of conduct in violation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_225"><akn:num>411.225</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer immunity from civil liability for disclosure of employee information — Exceptions — Effect of provision.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_225__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An employer who provides information about the job performance, professional conduct, or evaluation of a former or current employee to a prospective employer of that employee, at the request of that employee or prospective employer, shall be immune from civil liability arising out of the disclosure unless the plaintiff in the civil action proves:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)That the employer disclosed the information knowing that it was false, with reckless disregard of whether it was true or false, or with intent to mislead the prospective employer; or (b)That the disclosure of the information by the employer constitutes an unlawful discriminatory practice under KRS Chapter 344.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_225__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section does not create a new cause of action or substantive legal right against an employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_225__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section does not limit an employer’s immunity from civil liability or defenses established in another section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes or available at common law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_230"><akn:num>411.230</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages caused by tampering with operations of key infrastructure asset.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A civil action may be maintained under this section against any person that knowingly directs or causes a person to violate KRS 512.020(1)(b). Liability shall include actual damages to personal or real property caused by the offense and may include punitive damages and court costs. Donations of Apparently Wholesome Food or Apparently Fit Grocery Product</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_240"><akn:num>411.240</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions of KRS 411.240 to 411.243.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_241"><akn:num>411.241</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability for person, gleaner, or representative of nonprofit organization for donation of apparently wholesome food or apparently fit grocery product made in good faith to a nonprofit organization — Exception.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_242"><akn:num>411.242</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability for person or gleaner donating food or grocery products not meeting governmental consumer safety standards — Conditions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_243"><akn:num>411.243</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of KRS 411.240 to 411.243.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_240"><akn:num>411.240</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions of KRS 411.240 to 411.243.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in Sections KRS 411.240 to 411.243:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Apparently fit grocery product” means a grocery product that meets all consumer safety standards imposed by federal, state, and local laws and regulations even though the product may not be readily marketable because of appearance, age, date labeling, freshness, grade, size, surplus, or other conditions;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Apparently wholesome food” means food that meets all consumer safety standards imposed by federal, state, and local laws and regulations even though the food may not be readily marketable because of appearance, age, date labeling, freshness, grade, size, surplus, or other conditions;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Donate” means to give without requiring anything of monetary value from the recipient. The term donate includes giving by a nonprofit organization to another nonprofit organization, even if the donor organization has charged a fee to the donee organization, if the ultimate recipient or user is not required to give anything of monetary value;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Food” means any raw, cooked, processed, or prepared edible substance, ice, beverage, or ingredient used or intended for use in whole or in part for human consumption;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Gleaner” means a person who harvests an agriculture crop that has been donated by the owner for:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Free distribution to people; or (b)Donation to a nonprofit organization for ultimate distribution to people;</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Grocery product” means a nonfood grocery product, including but not limited to a disposable paper or plastic product, household cleaning product, laundry detergent cleaning product, or miscellaneous household item;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Intentional misconduct” means conduct by a person with actual knowledge at the time of the conduct that the conduct is harmful to the health and well-being of another person;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Nonprofit organization” means an incorporated or unincorporated entity that:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Is operating for religious, charitable, or educational purposes; and (b)Does not provide net earnings to, or operate in any manner that inures to the benefit of, any officer, employee, or shareholder of the entity; and</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_240__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means an individual, corporation, partnership, organization, association, or governmental entity, including a retail grocer, wholesaler, hotel, motel, restaurant, caterer, farmer, nonprofit food distributor, or hospital. In the case of a corporation, partnership, organization, association, or governmental entity, the term includes an officer, director, partner, deacon, trustee, council member, or other elected or appointed individual responsible for the governance of the entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_241"><akn:num>411.241</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability for person, gleaner, or representative of nonprofit organization for donation of apparently wholesome food or apparently fit grocery product made in good faith to a nonprofit organization — Exception.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_241__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)A person, gleaner, or paid or unpaid representative of a nonprofit organization shall not be subject to any civil or criminal liability arising from the nature, age, packaging, or condition of apparently wholesome food or an apparently fit grocery product that the person or gleaner donates in good faith to a nonprofit organization for ultimate distribution to people, unless the acts constitute intentional misconduct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)The protection from liability created by this subsection extends to an apparently wholesome food or apparently fit grocery product bearing a past-date expiration date, sell-by date, use-by date, or other date.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_241__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)A nonprofit organization or paid or unpaid representative of a nonprofit organization shall not be subject to any civil or criminal liability arising from the nature, age, packaging, or condition of apparently wholesome food or an apparently fit grocery product that the nonprofit organization received as a donation in good faith from a person or gleaner for ultimate distribution to people, unless the acts constitute intentional misconduct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)The protection from liability created by this subsection extends to an apparently wholesome food or apparently fit grocery product bearing a past- due expiration date, sell-by date, use-by date, or other date.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_241__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A person who allows the collection or gleaning of donations on property owned or occupied by the person, by gleaners or by paid or unpaid representatives of a nonprofit organization for ultimate distribution to people, shall not be subject to civil or criminal liability that arises due to the injury or death of the gleaner or representative unless the acts constitute intentional misconduct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_242"><akn:num>411.242</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability for person or gleaner donating food or grocery products not meeting governmental consumer safety standards — Conditions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If some or all of any food or grocery products donated by a person or gleaner to a nonprofit organization do not meet consumer safety standards imposed by federal, state, and local laws and regulations, the person or the gleaner who donates the food or grocery products shall not be subject to civil or criminal liability in accordance with this section, if the nonprofit organization that receives the donated food or grocery products:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_242__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Is informed by the donor of the distressed or defective condition of the donated food or grocery product;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_242__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Agrees to recondition the donated food or grocery product to comply with consumer safety standards prior to distribution; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_242__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Is knowledgeable about the standards to properly recondition the donated food or grocery product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_243"><akn:num>411.243</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of KRS 411.240 to 411.243.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.240 to 411.243 shall not be construed to create any liability for any person or entity. Nothing in KRS 411.240 to 411.243 shall be construed to supersede any federal or state regulations. Look Before You Lock Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_245"><akn:num>411.245</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability for damaging a vehicle to remove a minor — Conditions — Limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_245"><akn:num>411.245</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability for damaging a vehicle to remove a minor — Conditions — Limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_245__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A person who enters a vehicle, as defined in KRS 503.010, for the purpose of removing a minor shall be immune from civil liability for any resulting damage to the vehicle if the person:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Has a reasonable, good faith belief, based upon the circumstances known to the person at the time, that entry into the vehicle is necessary because the minor is in imminent danger of physical injury if not immediately removed from the vehicle; (b)Has contacted local law enforcement, the local fire department, or a 911 emergency telephone service prior to entering the vehicle; (c)Uses no more force to enter the vehicle and remove the minor than is reasonably necessary under the circumstances; and (d) 1.Remains with the minor in a safe location, out of the elements but reasonably close to the vehicle, until law enforcement, firefighters, or other emergency responders arrive; or 2.Reasonably determines that emergency conditions require leaving the scene with the minor, and places written notice on the vehicle containing: a.The person’s contact information; b.The reason entry into the vehicle was made; c.The minor’s location; and d.Notice that authorities have been contacted.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_245__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section does not limit a person’s immunity from civil liability or defenses established in another section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes or available at common law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_250"><akn:num>411.250</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislative intent.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_252"><akn:num>411.252</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.250 to 411.266.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_254"><akn:num>411.254</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of KRS 411.250 to 411.266.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_256"><akn:num>411.256</akn:num><akn:heading>Circumstances under which construction professional is liable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_258"><akn:num>411.258</akn:num><akn:heading>Written notice of claim to be served on construction professional in construction defect action — Offer to remedy or settle — Acceptance or rejection of offer — Commencement of action — Notice of claim tolls statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_260"><akn:num>411.260</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of construction professional’s right to offer to cure defects before commencement of litigation — Action not barred if homeowner is not given notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_262"><akn:num>411.262</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of KRS 411.250 to 411.266.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_264"><akn:num>411.264</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of notice of claim on statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_266"><akn:num>411.266</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title for KRS 411.250 to 411.266.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_250"><akn:num>411.250</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislative intent.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The General Assembly finds that limited changes in the law are necessary and appropriate concerning actions claiming damages, indemnity, or contribution in connection with alleged residential construction defects. It is the intent of the General Assembly that KRS 411.250 to 411.266 apply to these types of civil actions while preserving adequate rights and remedies for homeowners who bring and maintain such actions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_252"><akn:num>411.252</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.250 to 411.266.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 411.250 to 411.266, unless the context otherwise requires:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_252__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Action” means any civil lawsuit or action in contract or tort for damages or indemnity brought against a construction professional to assert a claim, whether by complaint, counterclaim, or cross-claim, for damage or the loss of use of real or personal property caused by a defect in the construction of a residence. “Action” does not include any civil action in tort alleging personal injury or wrongful death to a person or persons resulting from a construction defect;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_252__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Claimant” means a homeowner who asserts a claim against a construction professional concerning a defect in the construction of a residence;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_252__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Construction professional” means a builder;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_252__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Homeowner” means any person, company, firm, partnership, corporation, association, or other entity that contracts with a construction professional for the construction of a residence. “Homeowner” includes but is not limited to a subsequent purchaser of a residence from any homeowner;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_252__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Residence” means a single-family house, duplex, triplex, or quadraplex, or a unit in a multiunit residential structure in which title to each individual unit is transferred to the owner under a condominium regime as established in KRS 381.815 and shall include general common elements and limited common elements as defined in KRS 381.810; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_252__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Serve” or “service” means personal service or delivery by certified mail to the last known address of the addressee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_254"><akn:num>411.254</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of KRS 411.250 to 411.266.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.250 to 411.266 shall:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_254__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Apply to any claim that arises before, on, or after July 15, 2003, as the result of a construction defect, except a claim for personal injury or wrongful death, if the claim is the subject of an action commenced on or after July 15, 2003;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_254__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Prevail over any conflicting law otherwise applicable to the claim or cause of action;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_254__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Not bar or limit any claim or defense otherwise available except as otherwise provided in KRS 411.250 to 411.266; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_254__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Not create a new theory upon which liability may be based.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_256"><akn:num>411.256</akn:num><akn:heading>Circumstances under which construction professional is liable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In a claim to recover damages resulting from a construction defect, a construction professional is liable for his or her acts or omissions or the acts or omissions of his or her agents, employees, or subcontractors and is not liable for any damages caused by:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_256__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The acts or omissions of a person other than the construction professional or his or her agent, employee, or subcontractor;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_256__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The failure of a person other than the construction professional or his or her agent, employee, or subcontractor to take reasonable action to reduce the damages or maintain the residence;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_256__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Normal wear, tear, or deterioration;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_256__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Normal shrinkage, swelling, expansion, or settlement; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_256__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any construction defect disclosed to a claimant before his or her purchase of the residence, if the disclosure was provided in writing and in language that is understandable and was signed by the claimant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_258"><akn:num>411.258</akn:num><akn:heading>Written notice of claim to be served on construction professional in construction defect action — Offer to remedy or settle — Acceptance or rejection of offer — Commencement of action — Notice of claim tolls statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_258__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In every construction defect action brought against a construction professional, the claimant shall serve written notice of claim on the construction professional. The notice of claim shall state that the claimant asserts a construction defect claim against the construction professional and shall describe the claim in reasonable detail sufficient to determine the general nature of the defect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_258__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Within twenty-one (21) days after service of the notice of claim, the construction professional shall serve a written response on the claimant by registered mail or personal service. The written response shall:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Propose to inspect the residence that is the subject of the claim and to complete the inspection within a specified time frame. The proposal shall include the statement that the construction professional shall, based on the inspection, offer to remedy the defect, compromise by payment, or dispute the claim; (b)Offer to compromise and settle the claim by monetary payment without inspection. A construction professional’s offer under this paragraph to compromise and settle a homeowner’s claim may include but is not limited to an express offer to purchase the claimant’s residence that is the subject of the claim, and to pay the claimant’s reasonable relocation costs; or (c)State that the construction professional disputes the claim and will neither remedy the construction defect nor compromise and settle the claim.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_258__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)If the construction professional disputes the claim or does not respond to the claimant’s notice of claim within the time stated in subsection (2) of this section, then the claimant may bring an action against the construction professional for the claim described in the notice of claim without further notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)If the claimant rejects the inspection proposal or the settlement offer made by the construction professional pursuant to subsection (2) of this section, then the claimant shall serve written notice of the claimant’s rejection on the construction professional. After service of the rejection, the claimant may bring an action against the construction professional for the construction defect claim described in the notice of claim. If the construction professional has not received from the claimant, within thirty (30) days after the claimant’s receipt of the construction professional’s response, either an acceptance or a rejection of the inspection proposal or settlement offer, then at any time thereafter the construction professional may terminate the proposal or offer by serving written notice to the claimant, and the claimant may thereafter bring an action against the construction professional for the construction defect claim described in the notice of claim.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_258__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)If the claimant elects to allow the construction professional to inspect in accordance with the construction professional’s proposal pursuant to subsection (2)(a) of this section, then the claimant shall provide the construction professional and its contractors or other agents reasonable access to the claimant’s residence during normal working hours to inspect the premises and the claimed defect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)Within fourteen (14) days following completion of the inspection, the construction professional shall serve on the claimant: 1.A written offer to remedy the construction defect at no cost to the claimant, including a report of the scope of the inspection, the findings and results of the inspection, a description of the additional construction necessary to remedy the defect described in the claim, and a timetable for the completion of this construction; or 2.A written offer to compromise and settle the claim by monetary payment pursuant to subsection (2)(b) of this section; or 3.A written statement that the construction professional will not proceed further to remedy the defect. The claimant shall have the right to accept or reject the proposed construction defect correction, or the monetary offer to settle the claim. (c)If the construction professional does not proceed further to remedy the construction defect within the agreed timetable, or if the construction professional fails to comply with the provisions of paragraph (b) of this subsection, then the claimant may bring an action against the construction professional for the claim described in the notice of claim without further notice. (d)If the claimant rejects the offer made by the construction professional pursuant to paragraph (b)1. or 2. of this subsection to either remedy the construction defect or to compromise and settle the claim by monetary payment, then the claimant shall serve written notice of the claimant’s rejection on the construction professional. After service of the rejection notice, the claimant may bring an action against the construction professional for the construction defect claim described in the notice of claim. If the construction professional has not received from the claimant, within thirty (30) days after the claimant’s receipt of the construction professional’s response, either an acceptance or a rejection of the offer made pursuant to paragraph (b)1. or 2. of this subsection, then at any time thereafter the construction professional may terminate the offer by serving written notice to the claimant.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_258__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)Any claimant accepting the offer of a construction professional to remedy the construction defect pursuant to subsection (4)(b)1. of this section shall do so by serving the construction professional with a written notice of acceptance within a reasonable time period after receipt of the offer, and no later than thirty (30) days after receipt of the offer. The claimant shall provide the construction professional and its contractors or other agents reasonable access to the claimant’s residence during normal working hours to perform and complete the construction by the timetable stated in the offer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)The claimant and construction professional may, by written mutual agreement, alter the extent of construction or the timetable for completion of construction stated in the offer, including but not limited to repair of additional defects.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_258__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a claimant files a complaint, counterclaim, or cross-claim prior to meeting the requirements of this section, then the court may issue an order holding the action in abeyance until the parties comply with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_258__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section may be construed to prevent a claimant from commencing an action on the construction defect claim described in the notice of claim if the construction professional fails to perform the construction agreed upon, fails to remedy the defect, or fails to perform by the timetable agreed upon pursuant to subsection (2)(a) or (5) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_258__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The service of an amended notice of claim shall relate back to the original notice of claim for purposes of tolling statutes of limitations and repose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_260"><akn:num>411.260</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of construction professional’s right to offer to cure defects before commencement of litigation — Action not barred if homeowner is not given notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_260__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The construction professional shall provide notice to each homeowner, upon entering into a contract for the construction of a residence, of the construction professional’s right to offer to cure construction defects before a homeowner may commence litigation against the construction professional. The notice shall be conspicuous and may be included as part of the underlying contract signed by the homeowner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_260__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The notice required by this section shall be in substantially the following form: “SECTIONS 411.250 TO 411.260 OF THE KENTUCKY REVISED STATUTES CONTAIN IMPORTANT REQUIREMENTS YOU MUST FOLLOW BEFORE YOU MAY FILE A LAWSUIT FOR DEFECTIVE CONSTRUCTION AGAINST THE BUILDER OF YOUR HOME. YOU MUST DELIVER TO THE BUILDER A WRITTEN NOTICE OF ANY CONSTRUCTION CONDITIONS YOU ALLEGE ARE DEFECTIVE AND PROVIDE YOUR BUILDER THE OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE AN OFFER TO REPAIR OR PAY FOR THE DEFECTS. YOU ARE NOT OBLIGATED TO ACCEPT ANY OFFER MADE BY THE BUILDER. THERE ARE STRICT DEADLINES AND PROCEDURES UNDER STATE LAW, AND FAILURE TO FOLLOW THEM MAY AFFECT YOUR ABILITY TO FILE A LAWSUIT.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_260__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.250 to 411.266 shall not preclude or bar any action if notice is not given to the homeowner as required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_262"><akn:num>411.262</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of KRS 411.250 to 411.266.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_262__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in KRS 411.250 to 411.266 shall be construed to hinder or otherwise affect the employment, agency, or contractual relationship between and among homeowners and construction professionals during the process of construction and nothing in KRS 411.250 to 411.266 precludes the termination of those relationships as allowed under other law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_262__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in KRS 411.250 to 411.266 shall negate or otherwise restrict a construction professional’s right to access or inspection provided by law, covenant, easement, or contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_262__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Noncompliance by the homeowner with KRS 411.258 shall not operate as an affirmative defense in an action against a construction professional by the homeowner or another construction professional for emergency repairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_264"><akn:num>411.264</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of notice of claim on statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If a written notice of claim is served under KRS 411.258, then the statute of limitation for the underlying action is tolled until seventy-five (75) days after the expiration of the time frame agreed to by the parties as permitted in KRS 411.258(2), or the date established for inspection pursuant to KRS 411.258(2)(a), or the expiration of the time frame contained in KRS 411.258(4)(b), whichever occurs later.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_266"><akn:num>411.266</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title for KRS 411.250 to 411.266.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.250 to 411.266 shall be known as the Notice and Opportunity to Repair Act. Home Inspectors’ Opportunity to Cure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_270"><akn:num>411.270</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.270 to 411.282.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_272"><akn:num>411.272</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of KRS 411.270 to 411.282.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_274"><akn:num>411.274</akn:num><akn:heading>Circumstances under which home inspector liable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_276"><akn:num>411.276</akn:num><akn:heading>Written notice of claim required — Offer to remedy or settle — Acceptance or rejection of offer — Tolling of statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_278"><akn:num>411.278</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of home inspector’s right to cure before commencement of litigation — Action not barred if home inspector fails to give notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_280"><akn:num>411.280</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of KRS 411.270 to 411.282.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_282"><akn:num>411.282</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of notice of claim on statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_270"><akn:num>411.270</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.270 to 411.282.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 411.270 to 411.282, unless the context otherwise requires:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_270__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Action” means any civil lawsuit or action in contract or tort for damages or indemnity brought against a home inspector to assert a claim, whether by complaint, counterclaim, or cross-claim, for damages or the loss of use of real or personal property caused by a deficient home inspection or home inspection report regarding the inspection of a home. “Action” does not include any civil action in tort alleging personal injury or wrongful death to a person or persons resulting from a deficient home inspection or home inspection report;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_270__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Claimant” means a client who asserts a claim against a home inspector concerning a deficient home inspection or home inspection report regarding the inspection of a home;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_270__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Home” means a structure consisting of at least one (1) but not more than four (4) units, each designed for occupancy by a single family, whether the units are occupied or unoccupied;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_270__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Home inspector” means a person licensed in accordance with KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_270__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Serve” or “service” means personal service or delivery by certified mail to the last known address of the addressee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_272"><akn:num>411.272</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of KRS 411.270 to 411.282.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.270 to 411.282 shall:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_272__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Apply to any claim that arises before, on, or after July 15, 2004, as the result of a deficient home inspection or home inspection report regarding the inspection of a home, except a claim for personal injury or wrongful death, if the claim is the subject of an action commenced on or after July 15, 2004;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_272__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Prevail over any conflicting law otherwise applicable to the claim or cause of action;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_272__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Not bar or limit any claim or defense otherwise available except as otherwise provided in KRS 411.270 to 411.282; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_272__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Not create a new theory upon which liability may be based.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_274"><akn:num>411.274</akn:num><akn:heading>Circumstances under which home inspector liable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In a claim to recover damages resulting from a deficient home inspection or home inspection report regarding the inspection of a home, a home inspector is liable for his or her acts or omissions or the acts or omissions of his or her agents or employees and is not liable for any damages caused by:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_274__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The acts or omissions of a person other than the home inspector or his or her agent or employee; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_274__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any construction defect disclosed to a claimant before his or her purchase of the home, if the disclosure was provided in writing and in language that is understandable and was signed by the claimant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_276"><akn:num>411.276</akn:num><akn:heading>Written notice of claim required — Offer to remedy or settle — Acceptance or rejection of offer — Tolling of statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_276__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In every deficient home inspection or home inspection report action brought against a home inspector, the claimant shall serve written notice of claim on the home inspector. The notice of claim shall state that the claimant asserts a deficient home inspection or home inspection report claim against the home inspector and shall describe the claim in reasonable detail sufficient to determine the general nature of the deficiency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_276__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Within twenty-one (21) days after service of the notice of claim, the home inspector shall serve a written response on the claimant by registered mail or personal service. The written response shall:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Propose to inspect the residence that is the subject of the claim and to complete the inspection within a specified time frame. The proposal shall include the statement that the home inspector shall, based on the inspection, offer to remedy the defect, compromise by payment, or dispute the claim; (b)Offer to compromise and settle the claim by monetary payment without inspection; or (c)State that the home inspector disputes the claim.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_276__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)If the home inspector disputes the claim or does not respond to the claimant’s notice of claim within the time stated in subsection (2) of this section, then the claimant may bring an action against the home inspector for the claim described in the notice of claim without further notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)If the claimant rejects the inspection proposal or the settlement offer made by the home inspector pursuant to subsection (2) of this section, then the claimant shall serve written notice of the claimant’s rejection on the home inspector. After service of the rejection, the claimant may bring an action against the home inspector for the deficient home inspection or home inspection report claim described in the notice of claim. If the home inspector has not received from the claimant, within thirty (30) days after the claimant’s receipt of the home inspector’s response, either an acceptance or a rejection of the inspection proposal or settlement offer, then at any time thereafter the home inspector may terminate the proposal or offer by serving written notice to the claimant, and the claimant may thereafter bring an action against the home inspector for the deficient home inspection or home inspection report claim described in the notice of claim.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_276__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)If the claimant elects to allow the home inspector to inspect in accordance with the home inspector’s proposal pursuant to subsection (2)(a) of this section, then the claimant shall provide the home inspector reasonable access to the claimant’s home during normal working hours to inspect the premises.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)Within fourteen (14) days following completion of the inspection, the home inspector shall serve on the claimant: 1.A written offer to remedy the defect at no cost to the claimant, including a report of the scope of the inspection, the findings and results of the inspection, a description of the remedy necessary to cure the defect described in the claim, and a timetable for the completion of this remedy; 2.A written offer to compromise and settle the claim by monetary payment pursuant to subsection (2)(b) of this section; or 3.A written statement that the home inspector will not proceed further to remedy the defect. The claimant shall have the right to accept or reject the proposed remedy, or the monetary offer to settle the claim. (c)If the home inspector does not proceed further to remedy the defect within the agreed timetable, or if the home inspector fails to comply with the provisions of paragraph (b) of this subsection, then the claimant may bring an action against the home inspector for the claim described in the notice of claim without further notice. (d)If the claimant rejects the offer made by the home inspector pursuant to paragraph (b)1. or 2. of this subsection to either remedy the defect or to compromise and settle the claim by monetary payment, then the claimant shall serve written notice of the claimant’s rejection on the home inspector. After service of the rejection notice, the claimant may bring an action against the home inspector for the deficient home inspection or home inspection report claim described in the notice of claim. If the home inspector has not received from the claimant, within thirty (30) days after the claimant’s receipt of the home inspector’s response, either an acceptance or a rejection of the offer made pursuant to paragraph (b)1. or 2. of this subsection, then at any time thereafter the home inspector may terminate the offer by serving written notice to the claimant.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_276__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)Any claimant accepting the offer of a home inspector to remedy the defect pursuant to subsection (4)(b)1. of this section shall do so by serving the home inspector with a written notice of acceptance within a reasonable time period after receipt of the offer, and no later than thirty (30) days after receipt of the offer. The claimant shall provide the home inspector reasonable access to the claimant’s home during normal working hours to perform and complete the remedy by the timetable stated in the offer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)The claimant and home inspector may, by written mutual agreement, alter the extent of remedy or the timetable, including but not limited to repair of additional defects.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_276__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a claimant files a complaint, counterclaim, or cross-claim prior to meeting the requirements of this section, then the court may issue an order holding the action in abeyance until the parties comply with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_276__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section may be construed to prevent a claimant from commencing an action on the deficient home inspection or home inspection report claim described in the notice of claim if the home inspector fails to perform the remedy agreed upon or fails to perform by the timetable agreed upon pursuant to subsection (2)(a) or (5) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_276__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The service of an amended notice of claim shall relate back to the original notice of claim for purposes of tolling statutes of limitations and repose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_278"><akn:num>411.278</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of home inspector’s right to cure before commencement of litigation — Action not barred if home inspector fails to give notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_278__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The home inspector shall, upon entering into a contract for the inspection of a building or residence, provide notice to each client of the home inspector’s right to offer to cure a deficient home inspection or home inspection report before a client may commence litigation against the home inspector. The notice shall be conspicuous and may be included as part of the underlying contract signed by the client.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_278__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The notice required by this section shall be in substantially the following form: “CHAPTER 411 OF THE KENTUCKY REVISED STATUTES CONTAINS IMPORTANT REQUIREMENTS YOU MUST FOLLOW BEFORE YOU MAY FILE A LAWSUIT FOR DEFECTIVE CONSTRUCTION AGAINST THE HOME INSPECTOR OF YOUR RESIDENCE. YOU MUST DELIVER TO YOUR HOME INSPECTOR A WRITTEN NOTICE OF ANY CONDITIONS YOU ALLEGE THAT YOUR HOME INSPECTOR FAILED TO INCLUDE IN THE HOME INSPECTION REPORT AND PROVIDE YOUR HOME INSPECTOR THE OPPORTUNITY TO MAKE AN OFFER TO REPAIR OR PAY FOR THE DEFECTS. YOU ARE NOT OBLIGATED TO ACCEPT ANY OFFER MADE BY THE HOME INSPECTOR. THERE ARE STRICT DEADLINES AND PROCEDURES UNDER STATE LAW, AND FAILURE TO FOLLOW THEM MAY AFFECT YOUR ABILITY TO FILE A LAWSUIT.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_278__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.270 to 411.282 shall not preclude or bar any action if notice is not given to the client as required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_280"><akn:num>411.280</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of KRS 411.270 to 411.282.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_280__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in KRS 411.270 to 411.282 shall be construed to hinder or otherwise affect the employment, agency, or contractual relationship between and among homeowners and home inspectors during the process of inspection, and nothing in KRS 411.270 to 411.282 precludes the termination of those relationships as allowed under other law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_280__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Noncompliance by the client with KRS 411.276 shall not operate as an affirmative defense in an action against a home inspector by the client for emergency repairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_282"><akn:num>411.282</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of notice of claim on statute of limitations.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If a written notice of claim is served under KRS 411.276, then the statute of limitation for the underlying action is tolled until seventy-five (75) days after the expiration of the time frame agreed to by the parties under KRS 411.276(2), or the date established for inspection pursuant to KRS 411.276(2)(a), or the expiration of the time frame contained in KRS 411.276(4)(b), whichever occurs later. Product Liability Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_300"><akn:num>411.300</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_310"><akn:num>411.310</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumptions in product liability actions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_320"><akn:num>411.320</akn:num><akn:heading>Circumstances under which defendant is liable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_330"><akn:num>411.330</akn:num><akn:heading>Admissibility of certain evidence.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_340"><akn:num>411.340</akn:num><akn:heading>When wholesaler, distributor or retailer to be held liable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_350"><akn:num>411.350</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_300"><akn:num>411.300</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_300__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 411.310 to 411.340, a “product liability action” shall include any action brought for or on account of personal injury, death or property damage caused by or resulting from the manufacture, construction, design, formulation, development of standards, preparation, processing, assembly, testing, listing, certifying, warning, instructing, marketing, advertising, packaging or labeling of any product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_300__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 411.310 to 411.340, a “plaintiff” shall mean a person asserting a claim and, if said claim is asserted on behalf of an estate, “plaintiff” shall include plaintiff’s decedent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_310"><akn:num>411.310</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumptions in product liability actions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_310__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any product liability action, it shall be presumed, until rebutted by a preponderance of the evidence to the contrary, that the subject product was not defective if the injury, death or property damage occurred either more than five (5) years after the date of sale to the first consumer or more than eight (8) years after the date of manufacture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_310__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any product liability action, it shall be presumed, until rebutted by a preponderance of the evidence to the contrary, that the product was not defective if the design, methods of manufacture, and testing conformed to the generally recognized and prevailing standards or the state of the art in existence at the time the design was prepared, and the product was manufactured.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_320"><akn:num>411.320</akn:num><akn:heading>Circumstances under which defendant is liable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_320__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any product liability action, a manufacturer shall be liable only for the personal injury, death or property damage that would have occurred if the product had been used in its original, unaltered and unmodified condition. For the purpose of this section, product alteration or modification shall include failure to observe routine care and maintenance, but shall not include ordinary wear and tear. This section shall apply to alterations or modifications made by any person or entity, except those made in accordance with specifications or instructions furnished by the manufacturer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_320__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any product liability action, if the plaintiff performed an unauthorized alteration or an unauthorized modification, and such alteration or modification was a substantial cause of the occurrence that caused injury or damage to the plaintiff, the defendant shall not be liable whether or not said defendant was at fault or the product was defective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_320__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any product liability action, if the plaintiff failed to exercise ordinary care in the circumstances in his use of the product, and such failure was a substantial cause of the occurrence that caused injury or damage to the plaintiff, the defendant shall not be liable whether or not said defendant was at fault or the product was defective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_330"><akn:num>411.330</akn:num><akn:heading>Admissibility of certain evidence.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_340"><akn:num>411.340</akn:num><akn:heading>When wholesaler, distributor or retailer to be held liable.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In any product liability action, if the manufacturer is identified and subject to the jurisdiction of the court, a wholesaler, distributor, or retailer who distributes or sells a product, upon his showing by a preponderance of the evidence that said product was sold by him in its original manufactured condition or package, or in the same condition such product was in when received by said wholesaler, distributor or retailer, shall not be liable to the plaintiff for damages arising solely from the distribution or sale of such product, unless such wholesaler, distributor or retailer, breached an express warranty or knew or should have known at the time of distribution or sale of such product that the product was in a defective condition, unreasonably dangerous to the user or consumer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_350"><akn:num>411.350</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.300 to 411.340 shall be known as the “Product Liability Act of Kentucky.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_400"><akn:num>411.400</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.400 to 411.406.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_402"><akn:num>411.402</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil liability for theft of motor fuel — Penalties — Notice of nonpayment.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_404"><akn:num>411.404</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability under KRS 411.402 not a bar to other liability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_406"><akn:num>411.406</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative regulations to implement vehicle owner identification system.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_400"><akn:num>411.400</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.400 to 411.406.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 411.400 to 411.406, unless the context clearly requires otherwise:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_400__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Motor fuel” has the same meaning as in KRS 363.900;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_400__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Retailer” means any person, firm, or corporation who sells or offers for sale motor fuel from a retail facility;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_400__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Retail facility” has the same meaning as in KRS 363.900; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_400__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Vehicle” means a “motor vehicle” as defined by KRS 138.210 or a “motorboat” as defined by KRS 235.010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_402"><akn:num>411.402</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil liability for theft of motor fuel — Penalties — Notice of nonpayment.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_402__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The owner of a vehicle that receives motor fuel from a retail facility without making proper payment is liable to the retailer for the price of the motor fuel received, in addition to a service charge of thirty dollars ($30). This service charge may be imposed when notice is mailed under subsection (3) of this section, if the notice of the service charge was conspicuously displayed on the premises from which the motor fuel was received. The notice shall include a statement that civil penalties will be imposed if payment is not received within thirty (30) days. Only one (1) service charge may be imposed under this section for each incident.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_402__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the price of the motor fuel received and the service charge are not paid within thirty (30) days after the retailer has mailed the notice under subsection (3) of this section, the owner is liable to the retailer for:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The price of the motor fuel received; (b)The service charge as provided in subsection (1) of this section; and (c)A civil penalty in the amount of the greater of: 1.The price of the motor fuel received; or 2.One hundred dollars ($100).</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_402__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notice of nonpayment that includes a copy of KRS 411.400 to 411.406 and a description of its penalties shall be sent by the retailer to the owner by certified mail, to the address indicated by records obtained under KRS 411.406. The notice shall include a signed statement by the retailer or the employee of the retailer who reported the act, surveillance video photographs or other photographic evidence, the date and time of the occurrence, and the license plate number of the vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_402__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If within the thirty (30) day period referred to in subsection (2) of this section the owner sends written notice to the retailer disputing the retailer’s claim that the owner received motor fuel from the retailer without making proper payment, the retailer may collect the price of the motor fuel in accordance with KRS 411.404. Upon receipt of this notice from the owner, the retailer shall cease all collection efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_404"><akn:num>411.404</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability under KRS 411.402 not a bar to other liability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Civil liability under KRS 411.402 does not preclude civil liability under KRS 411.095, criminal liability under KRS 514.030, or liability under any other applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_406"><akn:num>411.406</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative regulations to implement vehicle owner identification system.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_406__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The Transportation Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement a system by which a retailer or association of retailers may obtain the name and mailing address of any owner who has been identified as committing an offense under KRS 411.402. The cabinet may enter into an agreement with a retailer or association of retailers to establish a set fee or other negotiated terms for the release of owner records.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_406__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any information released by the cabinet under this section shall be consistent with its authority under KRS 187.310 and shall be in compliance with 18 U.S.C. secs. 2721 et seq. The cabinet may integrate any system established under KRS 411.400 to 411.406 with its existing programs for the release of information pursuant to KRS Chapter 187.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>Hazardous Materials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_450"><akn:num>411.450</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.460 and 411.470.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_460"><akn:num>411.460</akn:num><akn:heading>Person who assists or advises in effort to mitigate effects of hazardous waste disposal or discharge immune from civil or criminal liability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_470"><akn:num>411.470</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity does not extend to gross negligence or reckless, wanton or intentional misconduct.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_450"><akn:num>411.450</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.460 and 411.470.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 411.460 and 411.470 unless the context indicates otherwise:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_450__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Discharge or disposal” means the discharge, deposit, injection, dumping, spilling, leaking or placing of any hazardous materials into or on any land or water so that such materials or any constituent thereof may enter the environment or be discharged into any waters, including ground waters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_450__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Hazardous material” means a substance or material in a quantity and form which may pose an unreasonable risk to health and safety or property when transported and which has been designated as a hazardous material under the Federal Hazardous Materials Transportation Law (49 U.S.C. sec. 5101 et seq.) or by any state law or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_450__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Person” means any individual, trust, firm, joint stock company, corporation (including a government corporation), partnership, association, federal agency, state agency, city, commission, political subdivision of the Commonwealth, or any interstate body.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_460"><akn:num>411.460</akn:num><akn:heading>Person who assists or advises in effort to mitigate effects of hazardous waste disposal or discharge immune from civil or criminal liability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No person who provides assistance or advice in mitigating or attempting to mitigate the effects of an actual or threatened discharge or disposal of hazardous materials, or in preventing, cleaning up, or disposing of or in attempting to prevent, clean up or dispose of any such discharge, shall be subject to any civil or criminal liabilities or penalties. This immunity shall not apply to any person whose act or omission caused in whole or in part the actual or threatened discharge or disposal and who would otherwise be liable for the discharge or disposal. Also this immunity shall not apply to any person who provides assistance or advice for remuneration or with the expectation of remuneration, except that actual expenses directly incurred due to giving the assistance or advice may be recovered without losing the immunity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_470"><akn:num>411.470</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity does not extend to gross negligence or reckless, wanton or intentional misconduct.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in KRS 411.460 shall be construed to limit or otherwise affect the liability of any person for damages resulting from such person’s gross negligence, or reckless, wanton, or intentional misconduct. Oil Spills</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_490"><akn:num>411.490</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.490 and 411.493.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_493"><akn:num>411.493</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonliability for removal costs or damages from actions under national contingency plan for oil spills.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_490"><akn:num>411.490</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.490 and 411.493.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section and KRS 411.493, unless the context otherwise requires:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_490__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Damages” means damages of any kind for which liability may exist under the laws of the Commonwealth resulting from, arising out of, or related to the discharge or threatened discharge of oil.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_490__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Discharge” means any emission, other than natural seepage, whether the emission is intentional or unintentional, which includes, but is not limited to, spilling, leaking, pumping, pouring, emitting, emptying, or dumping.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_490__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Federal on-scene coordinator” means the federal official designated by the lead federal agency or predesignated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency or the United States Coast Guard to coordinate and direct responses under the National Contingency Plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_490__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“National contingency plan” means the national contingency plan prepared and published under section 311(d) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. sec. 1321(d)), as amended by the Oil Pollution Act of 1990, Pub. L. No. 101-380, 104 Stat. 484 (1990) or revised under Section 105 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (42 U.S.C. sec. 9605).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_490__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Oil” means oil of any kind or in any form, including, but not limited to, petroleum, fuel oil, sludge, oil refuse, and oil mixed with wastes other than dredged spoil but does not include petroleum, including crude oil or any fraction thereof, which is specifically listed or designated as a hazardous substance under subparagraph (A) through (F) of Section 101(14) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (42 U.S.C. sec. 9601).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_490__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Removal” means containment and removal of oil or a hazardous substance from water and shorelines or the taking of other actions as may be necessary to minimize or mitigate damage to the public health or welfare, including, but not limited to, actions to minimize or mitigate damage to fish, shellfish, wildlife, and public or private property, shorelines, and beaches.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_490__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Removal costs” means the costs of removal that are incurred after a discharge of oil has occurred, or, when there is a substantial threat of a discharge of oil, the costs to prevent, minimize, or mitigate the threat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_490__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Responsible party” means a responsible party as defined under Section 1001 of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990, Pub. L. No. 101-380, 104 Stat. 484 (1990).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_493"><akn:num>411.493</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonliability for removal costs or damages from actions under national contingency plan for oil spills.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_493__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, a person is not liable for removal costs or damages which result from actions taken, or not taken, in the course of rendering care, assistance, or advice consistent with the national contingency plan or as otherwise directed by the federal on-scene coordinator or by the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, or his designee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_493__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Subsection (1) of this section does not apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)To a responsible party; (b)To any person who is grossly negligent or who engages in willful misconduct; or (c)With respect to personal injury or wrongful death.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_493__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A responsible party is liable for any removal costs and damages that another person is relieved of under subsection (1) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_493__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section affects the liability of a responsible party for oil spill response under Kentucky law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>Nuisances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_500"><akn:num>411.500</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislative intent.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_510"><akn:num>411.510</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.500 to 411.570.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_520"><akn:num>411.520</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of KRS 411.500 to 411.570 — Character of private nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_530"><akn:num>411.530</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_540"><akn:num>411.540</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_550"><akn:num>411.550</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of private nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_560"><akn:num>411.560</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages for private nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_570"><akn:num>411.570</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of KRS 411.500 to 411.570.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_500"><akn:num>411.500</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislative intent.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>It is the intent of the General Assembly to restate and codify in KRS 411.500 to 411.570 the common law of nuisance as existing in the Commonwealth on May 24, 1991. As a codification, the common law shall be continued by KRS 411.500 to 411.570 which shall apply to all actions whether now pending or subsequently brought. Matters not specifically addressed in KRS 411.500 to 411.570 shall be governed by common law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_510"><akn:num>411.510</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions for KRS 411.500 to 411.570.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 411.500 to 411.570:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_510__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Claimant” means a person who asserts a claim of private nuisance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_510__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Fair market value” means the price that a person who is willing but not compelled to buy would pay and a seller who is willing but not compelled to sell would accept for property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_510__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Fair rental value” means the price a lessee who is willing but not compelled to lease would pay and a lessor who is willing but not compelled to lease would accept.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_510__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Ownership interest” means holding legal or equitable title to property in fee or in a life tenancy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_510__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Defendant” means a person against whom a claim of private nuisance is asserted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_510__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Possessory interest” means lawfully possessing property but does not include mere occupancy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_510__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Property” means real property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_510__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Value of use” means the value to a person of using property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_520"><akn:num>411.520</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of KRS 411.500 to 411.570 — Character of private nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_520__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any and all proceedings in the nature of actions for private nuisance as heretofore arising at common law shall be governed by KRS 411.500 to 411.570.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_520__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A private nuisance shall be either a permanent nuisance or a temporary nuisance, but shall not be both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_530"><akn:num>411.530</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_530__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A permanent nuisance shall be any private nuisance that:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Cannot be corrected or abated at reasonable expense to the owner; and (b)Is relatively enduring and not likely to be abated voluntarily or by court order.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_530__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A permanent nuisance shall exist if and only if a defendant’s use of property causes unreasonable and substantial annoyance to the occupants of the claimant’s property or unreasonably interferes with the use and enjoyment of such property, and thereby causes the fair market value of the claimant’s property to be materially reduced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_540"><akn:num>411.540</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_540__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any private nuisance that is not a permanent nuisance shall be a temporary nuisance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_540__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A temporary nuisance shall exist if and only if a defendant’s use of property causes unreasonable and substantial annoyance to the occupants of the claimant’s property or unreasonably interferes with the use and enjoyment of such property, and thereby causes the value of use or the rental value of the claimant’s property to be reduced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_550"><akn:num>411.550</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of private nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_550__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In determining whether a defendant’s use of property constitutes a private nuisance, the judge or jury, whichever is the trier of fact, shall consider all relevant facts and circumstances including the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The lawful nature of the defendant’s use of the property; (b)The manner in which the defendant has used the property; (c)The importance of the defendant’s use of the property to the community; (d)The influence of the defendant’s use of property to the growth and prosperity of the community; (e)The kind, volume, and duration of the annoyance or interference with the use and enjoyment of claimant’s property caused by the defendant’s use of property; (f)The respective situations of the defendant and claimant; and (g)The character of the area in which the defendant’s property is located, including, but not limited to, all applicable statutes, laws, or regulations.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_550__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A defendant’s use of property shall be considered as a substantial annoyance or interference with the use and enjoyment of a claimant’s property if it would substantially annoy or interfere with the use and enjoyment of property by a person of ordinary health and normal sensitivities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_560"><akn:num>411.560</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages for private nuisance.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_560__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Damages allowable for a private nuisance shall be as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)If the nuisance is a permanent nuisance, compensatory damages shall be measured by the reduction in the fair market value of the claimant’s property caused by the nuisance, but not to exceed the fair market value of the property; (b)If the nuisance is a temporary nuisance and: 1.The claimant occupied the property during the continuance of the nuisance, compensatory damages shall be measured by the diminution in the value of the use of the property which resulted from the nuisance; or 2.The claimant did not occupy the property during the continuance of the nuisance, compensatory damages shall be measured by the diminution in the fair rental value of the property which resulted from the nuisance.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_560__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A defendant who contributes to a nuisance is responsible for damages as provided in this section only to the extent of such defendant’s proportionate contribution to the nuisance as provided in the provisions of KRS 411.182.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_560__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No damages shall be awarded for annoyance, discomfort, sickness, emotional distress, or similar claims for a private nuisance. In the event a claim for injury or damage to a person is asserted in the same proceeding as a claim for damage to the claimant’s property caused by a private nuisance, liability for such personal injury or damage shall be determined on the basis of applicable principles of tort law independent of whether the defendant’s use of property is found to constitute a nuisance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_560__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A claimant may recover punitive damages for a private nuisance if the claimant recovers damages pursuant to this section and the defendant’s conduct in engaging in the specific activity which is alleged to be the nuisance meets or exceeds the standards set forth in KRS 411.184. All provisions of KRS 411.184 and 411.186 shall apply to claims for punitive damages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_560__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No person shall have standing to bring an action for private nuisance unless the person has an ownership interest or possessory interest in the property alleged to be affected by the nuisance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_570"><akn:num>411.570</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of KRS 411.500 to 411.570.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>KRS 411.500 to 411.570 shall not be construed as repealing any of the statutes or common law of the Commonwealth relating to nuisance, nor shall be construed to abridge any other rights or remedies available for personal or property damage, but shall be held and construed as ancillary and supplemental thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_600"><akn:num>411.600</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_610"><akn:num>411.610</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability for condition arising due to long-term consumption of food — Exceptions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_620"><akn:num>411.620</akn:num><akn:heading>Required contents of complaint — Substantive status of pleadings.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_630"><akn:num>411.630</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of discovery and other proceedings during pendancy of motion to dismiss — Exceptions — Treatment of documents and other tangible objects during pendency of stay of discovery.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_640"><akn:num>411.640</akn:num><akn:heading>Affected claims.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_600"><akn:num>411.600</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>For purposes of KRS 411.600 to 411.640:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_600__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Claim” means any claim by or on behalf of a natural person, as well as any derivative or other claim arising therefrom asserted by or on behalf of any other person;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_600__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Food establishment” means:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Any entity required to hold a permit pursuant to KRS 217.125; or (b)Any other manufacturer, packer, distributor, carrier, holder, seller, marketer, or advertiser of food as defined in KRS 217.015(18) or 21 U.S.C. sec. 321(f);</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_600__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Generally known condition allegedly caused by or allegedly likely to result from long-term consumption” means a condition generally known to result or to likely result from the cumulative effect of consumption, and not from a single instance of consumption; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_600__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>“Knowing and willful violation” means that the conduct constituting the violation was committed with the intent to deceive or injure consumers or with actual knowledge that the conduct was injurious to consumers, and the conduct constituting the violation was not required by regulations, orders, rules, or other pronouncements of, or any statutes administered by, a federal, state, or local government agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_610"><akn:num>411.610</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability for condition arising due to long-term consumption of food — Exceptions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A food establishment, or an association of one (1) or more food establishments, shall not be subject to civil liability for any claim arising out of weight gain, obesity, a health condition associated with weight gain or obesity, or other generally known condition allegedly caused by or allegedly likely to result from long-term consumption of food, except where the claim:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_610__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Includes as an element of the cause of action a material violation of an adulteration or misbranding requirement prescribed by federal or state statute or regulation, and the claimed injury was proximately caused by the violation. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to create new or expand existing private rights, if any, under adulteration or misbranding statutes or regulations, nor shall this subsection be construed to interfere with any agency’s exclusive or primary jurisdiction to find or declare violations of those statutes or regulations; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_610__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Is based on any other material violation of federal or state law applicable to the manufacturing, marketing, distribution, advertising, labeling, or sale of food, if the violation was a knowing and willful violation, and the claimed injury was proximately caused by the violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_620"><akn:num>411.620</akn:num><akn:heading>Required contents of complaint — Substantive status of pleadings.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_411_620__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any action exempted under KRS 411.610(1), the complaint initiating the action shall state with particularity:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The federal or state statute, regulation, or other law that was allegedly violated; (b)The facts that allegedly constitute a material violation of the statute, regulation, or other law; and (c)The facts that allegedly demonstrate that the violation proximately caused actual injury to the plaintiff.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_411_620__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In any action exempted under KRS 411.610(2), in addition to the pleading requirements of subsection (1) of this section, the complaint initiating the action shall state with particularity facts sufficient to support a reasonable inference that the violation was a knowing and willful violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_411_620__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of applying KRS 411.600 to 411.640, the pleading requirements in this section are deemed part of the substantive law of this Commonwealth and not merely in the nature of procedural provisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_630"><akn:num>411.630</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of discovery and other proceedings during pendancy of motion to dismiss — Exceptions — Treatment of documents and other tangible objects during pendency of stay of discovery.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In any action exempted under KRS 411.610, all discovery and other proceedings shall be stayed during the pendency of any motion to dismiss unless the court finds upon the motion of any party that particularized discovery is necessary to preserve evidence or to prevent undue prejudice to that party. During the pendency of any stay of discovery pursuant to this section, unless otherwise ordered by the court, any party to the action with actual notice of the allegations contained in the complaint shall treat all documents, data, compilations, including electronically recorded or stored data, and tangible objects that are in the custody or control of that party and that are relevant to the allegations, as if they were the subject of a continuing request for production of documents from an opposing party under the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_411_640"><akn:num>411.640</akn:num><akn:heading>Affected claims.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of KRS 411.600 to 411.640 shall apply to all covered claims pending on the June 20, 2005, and all claims filed thereafter, regardless of when the claim arose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter><akn:chapter eId="chap_412"><akn:num>Chapter 412</akn:num><akn:heading>Suretyship, Joint Obligations and Contribution</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_412_010"><akn:num>412.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Survival of liability of joint obligor — Right of contribution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_020"><akn:num>412.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Extent of recovery in contribution is the same at law as in equity.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_030"><akn:num>412.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Contribution among negligent wrongdoers.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_040"><akn:num>412.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of insolvency or nonresidence on right of contribution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_050"><akn:num>412.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Contribution among persons in trust or official capacity.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_060"><akn:num>412.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_070"><akn:num>412.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of party pressing claims in common interest for others — Notice to interested persons.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_080"><akn:num>412.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by surety who pays, against principal — Against cosurety.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_090"><akn:num>412.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of right of action to surety paying judgment.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_100"><akn:num>412.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of co-obligors and cocontractors.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_110"><akn:num>412.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Person jointly liable may require suit or execution issued — Notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_120"><akn:num>412.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of surety on bond for delay in execution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_130"><akn:num>412.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of surety on lost or destroyed judgment or bond.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_140"><akn:num>412.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by surety against principal or cosurety after maturity of debt.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_150"><akn:num>412.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Creditor to be made defendant — Provisional remedies allowed.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_160"><akn:num>412.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings against surety after bankruptcy of principal.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_010"><akn:num>412.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Survival of liability of joint obligor — Right of contribution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_412_010__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If any person jointly bound with another in any contract, or by judgment, dies in the lifetime of the other obligor, his heir, devisee, or representative may be charged in the same manner as if the contract or judgment had been separate as against the decedent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_412_010__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The same rights and responsibilities shall continue in favor of, and against, the representatives of a person entitled to or bound to make contribution who dies as if he were living when contribution is demanded. The same principle shall apply when more than one (1) dies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_020"><akn:num>412.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Extent of recovery in contribution is the same at law as in equity.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The extent of recovery, in cases of contribution, shall be the same in a court of law that it is in a court of equity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_030"><akn:num>412.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Contribution among negligent wrongdoers.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Contribution among wrongdoers may be enforced where the wrong is a mere act of negligence and involves no moral turpitude.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_040"><akn:num>412.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of insolvency or nonresidence on right of contribution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The insolvency or nonresidence of any person liable to contribution shall affect the rights of the others in like manner as the insolvency of one (1) obligor affects the others.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_050"><akn:num>412.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Contribution among persons in trust or official capacity.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Contribution shall take place between all persons jointly liable, by civil action, for any act or omission in a trust or official capacity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_060"><akn:num>412.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In all cases of contribution, interest shall be allowed from the time the right accrues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_070"><akn:num>412.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of party pressing claims in common interest for others — Notice to interested persons.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_412_070__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In actions for the settlement of estates, or for the recovery of money or property held in joint tenancy, coparcenary, or as tenants in common, or for the recovery of money or property which has been illegally or improperly collected, withheld or converted, if one (1) or more of the legatees, devisees, distributees or parties in interest has prosecuted for the benefit of others interested with him, and has been to trouble and expense in that connection, the court shall allow him his necessary expenses, and his attorney reasonable compensation for his services, in addition to the costs. This allowance shall be paid out of the funds recovered before distribution. The persons interested shall be given notice of the application for the allowance, provided, however, that if the court before whom the action is pending should determine that it is impracticable and too expensive to notify all of the parties individually, then by order of said court, personal notice may be dispensed with and in lieu thereof, notice of the application shall be given by an advertisement pursuant to KRS Chapter 424.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_412_070__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The compensation herein provided for shall be authorized in actions now pending as well as actions hereafter instituted; provided, that in actions now pending final orders and judgments have not been ordered and the fund has not come into actual being.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_080"><akn:num>412.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by surety who pays, against principal — Against cosurety.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If a surety pays any part of a debt or liability for which he is bound as surety, he may recover the amount, with interest from time of payment, from the principal by action at law or by motion, after ten (10) days’ notice in writing. He may also sue a cosurety, separately or as a joint defendant with the principal, in such proceeding, and in like manner recover judgment against him, separately or jointly, at the same time, for his proper part of the debt or liability so paid, as if the sureties were the sole obligors. If one (1) or more of several cosureties is insolvent, or resides out of the state, the recovery against the solvent and resident sureties shall also be for a proper part of the share of liability pertaining to the insolvent or nonresident surety. If the surety afterwards makes further payment on the debt or liability, he may again have like remedy therefor. But nothing in this section shall preclude the party sued from making any defense that might have been made against the original demand, unless the payment was made after and in consequence of a judgment in an action of which he had notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_090"><akn:num>412.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of right of action to surety paying judgment.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the surety pays any part of a judgment he shall have a right to an assignment of the judgment from the plaintiff or the plaintiff’s attorney, in whole or in part. When the plaintiff has been fully satisfied, the assignment shall give the surety the right to sue out or use any existing execution or otherwise control the judgment for his own benefit, against the other defendants, so far as to obtain satisfaction from the principal for the whole amount so paid by him, with interest, or from any cosurety his proper part of such payment, according to KRS 412.080. This assignment shall also transfer to the sureties so paying the benefit of any lien existing under or by virtue of the judgment, and the right of assignment shall exist, though the money was made or secured by sale of the property of the surety under execution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_100"><akn:num>412.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of co-obligors and cocontractors.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Co-obligors and cocontractors shall, as between each other, have the full benefit of KRS 412.080 and 412.090 as if they were cosureties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_110"><akn:num>412.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Person jointly liable may require suit or execution issued — Notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A surety, co-obligor, or cocontractor, or one (1) of several defendants to a judgment may, by notice in writing served in person within the state on the creditor or plaintiff, or, if the plaintiff is a nonresident or absent from the place of his residence for the period of thirty (30) days consecutively, upon his agent or his attorney, require him to sue or issue execution. If the creditor does not in good faith prosecute the suit with reasonable diligence, or if the plaintiff does not, within ten (10) days after judgment, sue out execution and in good faith prosecute the collection, the cosurety, co-obligor, cocontractor, or defendant shall be discharged from all liability, except for his proper share according to the then existing condition of the several obligors, contractors, or defendants. In any joint suit against the whole, or separate suit against him, judgment shall be rendered against him separately, and only for such proper share. The written notice required in this section shall not be waived, unless the waiver is in writing. No waiver of the notice shall be pleaded as a defense or given in evidence, unless it is in writing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_120"><akn:num>412.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of surety on bond for delay in execution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the plaintiff in any bond having the force of a judgment fails, at any time for the space of a year during which he is entitled to have execution, to issue execution and in good faith prosecute the collection, the surety in the bond shall be released from all liability. Any execution thereafter issuing on the bond shall be so endorsed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_130"><akn:num>412.130</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of surety on lost or destroyed judgment or bond.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No surety shall be released from his obligation on any lost or destroyed judgment, or bond having the force of a judgment, because of any failure to sue out execution thereon for twelve (12) months, unless the failure was for twelve (12) months after the reentry of judgment or order of execution. However, this section shall not apply to a surety who was released by law at the time of the destruction or loss of the record or bond, nor unless proceedings to have a reentry of the judgment or order of execution had been commenced as provided in KRS 422.210 and 422.220.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_140"><akn:num>412.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by surety against principal or cosurety after maturity of debt.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>After the maturity of a debt or liability, an equitable action may be brought by a surety against his principal to compel payment of it, or by one who is jointly liable therefor with another to compel him to pay so much of it as he may be equitably liable for as between him and the plaintiff.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_150"><akn:num>412.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Creditor to be made defendant — Provisional remedies allowed.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_412_150__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The creditor must be made defendant to an action brought pursuant to KRS 412.140, but shall not be liable for costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_412_150__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of KRS 425.301 to 425.316 and KRS 425.501 to 425.526 shall apply to such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_412_160"><akn:num>412.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings against surety after bankruptcy of principal.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>In an action for the recovery of money in which the defendant may have given bond with sureties, or for whom sureties may have given bond, pursuant to the provisions of subsection (1) of KRS 425.116; or in which an appellant may have given bond with sureties, or for whom sureties may have given bond, for the purpose of appeal from an inferior court to a circuit court or for the purpose of a supersedeas pending an appeal to the Court of Appeals — if such defendant or appellant have thereafter become a bankrupt under the laws of the United States, upon notice thereof from his adversary being served on the sureties, by summons, the court shall decide whether or not anything, and, if anything, how much, should have been adjudged against the defendant or appellant, but for the bankruptcy; and such decision shall be conclusive as to the liability of the sureties; but they shall not be liable upon a bond given pursuant to subsection (1) of KRS 425.116, if property released from an attachment by reason thereof, or its proceeds, have lawfully come to the defendant’s or appellant’s assignee in bankruptcy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter><akn:chapter eId="chap_413"><akn:num>Chapter 413</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of Actions</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_413_010"><akn:num>413.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for recovery of real property — Fifteen year limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_020"><akn:num>413.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for recovery of real property — Plaintiff under disability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_030"><akn:num>413.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for recovery of real property — Extension for disability limited — No extension past thirty years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_040"><akn:num>413.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Claim not to preserve right of action.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_050"><akn:num>413.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on action by city on public easement — On action for possession of public road — Effect of notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_060"><akn:num>413.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Person holding land under adverse title for seven years — Extension for disability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_070"><akn:num>413.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Action upon equity of redemption in real property.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_072"><akn:num>413.072</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship of agricultural and silvicultural operations to law of nuisance and trespass — Preemption of local ordinances — Sustainable agriculture and best management practices.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_075"><akn:num>413.075</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to foreclose liens securing street improvement bonds; five year limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_010"><akn:num>413.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for recovery of real property — Fifteen year limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Subject to KRS 411.190(8), an action for the recovery of real property may be brought only within fifteen (15) years after the right to institute it first accrued to the plaintiff, or to the person through whom he claims.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_020"><akn:num>413.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for recovery of real property — Plaintiff under disability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If, at the time the right of any person to bring an action for the recovery of real property first accrued, he was an infant or of unsound mind, he or the person claiming through him may, though the period of fifteen (15) years has expired, bring the action within three (3) years after the time the disability is removed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_030"><akn:num>413.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for recovery of real property — Extension for disability limited — No extension past thirty years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_030__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The time within which an action for the recovery of real property may be brought shall not be extended by reason of any disability that did not exist when the right to bring the action first accrued, nor by reason of any disability of the heirs of the person to whom the right first accrued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_030__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The period within which an action for the recovery of real property may be brought shall not, in any case, be extended beyond thirty (30) years from the time when the right to bring the action first accrued to the plaintiff or the person through whom he claims.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_040"><akn:num>413.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Claim not to preserve right of action.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No continual claim upon or near real property shall preserve a right to bring an action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_050"><akn:num>413.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on action by city on public easement — On action for possession of public road — Effect of notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_050__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The limitations mentioned in KRS 413.010 to 413.040 shall not begin to run in respect to actions by a city for the recovery of any part of any street, alley or other public easement or the use thereof in the city, until the legislative body of the city has been notified in writing by the party in possession or about to take possession that his possession will be adverse to the right or title of the city. Until such notice is given, all possession of any part of any street, alley or public easement in any city shall be deemed amicable, and the person in possession the tenant at will of the city.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_050__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Limitation shall not begin to run in favor of any person in the possession of any part of any public road until written notice is given to the county judge/executive of the county in which the road is situated that the possession is adverse to the right of the public to the use of the road.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_060"><akn:num>413.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Person holding land under adverse title for seven years — Extension for disability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_060__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No action shall be brought under or by virtue of an adverse, interfering entry, survey or patent to recover the title or possession of land from an occupant if he, or the person under whom he claims, has a connected title thereto in law or equity, deducible of record from the Commonwealth, and has an actual occupancy of it by settlement thereon, under such title, for seven (7) years before the commencement of the action. This possession of land shall bar the right of entry into it by any person, under an adverse title or claim, and sufficient possession to bar the right to recover it shall vest the title in the occupant or his vendee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_060__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to a person who is an infant, of unsound mind or out of the United States in the employment of the United States or of this state at the time the cause of action accrued, until seven (7) years after the removal of such disability. The disability of one (1) of several claimants shall save only his own right, and not that of another.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_070"><akn:num>413.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Action upon equity of redemption in real property.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>After a mortgagee of real property or any person claiming under him has had fifteen (15) years’ continued adverse possession, no action shall be brought by the mortgagor or anyone claiming under him to redeem the property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_072"><akn:num>413.072</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship of agricultural and silvicultural operations to law of nuisance and trespass — Preemption of local ordinances — Sustainable agriculture and best management practices.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_072__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>It is the declared policy of the Commonwealth to conserve, protect, and encourage the development and improvement of its agricultural land and silvicultural land for the production of food, timber, and other agricultural and silvicultural products. When nonagricultural land uses extend into agricultural and silvicultural areas, agricultural and silvicultural operations often become the subject of nuisance suits or legal actions restricting agricultural or silvicultural operations. As a result, agricultural and silvicultural operations are sometimes either curtailed or forced to cease operations. Investments in farm and timber improvements may be discouraged. It is the purpose of this section to reduce the loss to the state of its agricultural and silvicultural resources by clarifying the circumstances under which agricultural and silvicultural operations may be deemed to be a nuisance or interfered with by local ordinances or legal actions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_072__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No agricultural or silvicultural operation or any of its appurtenances shall be or become a nuisance or trespass, private or public, or be in violation of any zoning ordinance, or be subject to any ordinance that would restrict the right of the operator of the agricultural or silvicultural operation to utilize normal and accepted practices, by any changed conditions in or about the locality thereof after the same has been in operation for more than one (1) year, when the operation was not a nuisance at the time the operation began. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply whenever a nuisance, trespass, or zoning violation results from the negligent operation of an agricultural or silvicultural operation or its appurtenances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_072__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)For the purposes of this section, “agricultural operation” includes, but is not limited to, any facility for the production of crops, livestock, equine, poultry, livestock products, poultry products, horticultural products, and any generally accepted, reasonable, and prudent method for the operation of a farm to obtain a monetary profit that complies with applicable laws and administrative regulations, and is performed in a reasonable and prudent manner customary among farm operators. Agricultural practices protected by this section shall include, but not be limited to, fertilizer application, the application of pesticides or herbicides that have been approved by public authority, planting, cultivating, mowing, harvesting, land clearing, and constructing farm buildings, roads, lakes, and ponds associated with a farming operation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b) 1.An agricultural operation may include the practice of sustainable agriculture. 2.For purposes of this section, “sustainable agriculture” includes science-based practices that: a.Are supported by research and the use of technology; b.Are demonstrated to lead to broad outcomes-based performance improvements that meet the needs of the present, and c.Improve the ability of future generations to meet their needs while advancing progress toward environmental, social, and economic goals and the well-being of agricultural producers and rural communities. 3.Sustainable agriculture may use continuous improvement principles, with goals that include: a.Increasing agricultural productivity; b.Improving human health through access to safe, nutritious, and affordable food, and c.Enhancing agricultural and surrounding environments, including water, soil, and air quality, biodiversity, and habitat preservation.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_072__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>For the purposes of this section, “silvicultural operation” includes timber harvest, site preparation, slash disposal including controlled burning, tree planting, precommercial thinning, release, fertilization, animal damage control, reasonable water resource management, insect and disease control in forest land, and any other generally accepted, reasonable, and prudent practice normally employed in the management of the timber resource for monetary profit. A silvicultural operation inherently includes lengthy periods between harvests and shall be deemed continuously operating so long as the property supports an actual or developing forest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_072__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An agricultural or silvicultural operation shall not lose its status by reason of a change of ownership or a cessation of operation of no more than five (5) years or one (1) year after the expiration of a state or national program contract, either in whole or in part, nor shall it lose its status by reason of changes of crops or methods of production due to the introduction and use of new and generally accepted technologies which allow the operator to continue an existing agricultural or silvicultural corporation, unless the operation is substantially changed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_072__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The provisions of this section shall not affect the right of any person, firm, or corporation to recover damages for any injuries or damages sustained by them on account of pollution of the waters of any stream or ground water of the person, firm, or corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_072__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any and all ordinances of any unit of local government now in effect or hereafter adopted that would make an agricultural or silvicultural operation or its appurtenances a nuisance per se, or providing for abatement thereof as a nuisance, a trespass, or a zoning violation in the circumstance set forth in this section shall be void. However, the provisions of this subsection shall not apply whenever a nuisance results from the negligent operation of any such agricultural operation or any of its appurtenances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_072__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any administrative regulation promulgated by any agency that establishes standards for harvesting or producing agricultural crops in a sustainable manner shall be based on the principles outlined in this section and shall allow the use of best management practices developed under KRS 224.71-100 to 224.71-140.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_075"><akn:num>413.075</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to foreclose liens securing street improvement bonds; five year limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_080"><akn:num>413.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Action upon equity of redemption in personal property.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_090"><akn:num>413.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Action upon judgment, contract, or bond — Fifteen-year limitation — Action for child support arrearages — Time to commence action tolled until obligations cease as to last child on order.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_100"><akn:num>413.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Lienee not to extend limitation as against purchasers or creditors — Exception.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_110"><akn:num>413.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against county on bonded obligation — Three year limitation — Action on state warrant — Two year limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_120"><akn:num>413.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to be brought within five years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_125"><akn:num>413.125</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions relating to personal property to be brought within two years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_130"><akn:num>413.130</akn:num><akn:heading>When certain actions in KRS 413.120 accrue.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_135"><akn:num>413.135</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages arising out of injury.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_137"><akn:num>413.137</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages for injury or illness suffered as a result of female genital mutilation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_140"><akn:num>413.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to be brought within one year.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_150"><akn:num>413.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by the Commonwealth.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_160"><akn:num>413.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions upon written contract or not provided for by statute — Ten-year limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_170"><akn:num>413.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations of actions in KRS 413.090 to 413.160 do not run until removal of disability or death.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_180"><akn:num>413.180</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by or against personal representative under KRS 413.090 to 413.160.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_190"><akn:num>413.190</akn:num><akn:heading>Result of absence from the state or obstruction of action under KRS 413.090 to 413.160.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_200"><akn:num>413.200</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against personal representative who has settled accounts.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_210"><akn:num>413.210</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against heirs and personal representative when estate divided.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_220"><akn:num>413.220</akn:num><akn:heading>Sureties who are discharged after seven years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_230"><akn:num>413.230</akn:num><akn:heading>Sureties who are discharged after five years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_240"><akn:num>413.240</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against surety — When limitation does not run.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_241"><akn:num>413.241</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislative finding — Limitation on liability of licensed sellers or servers of intoxicating beverages — Liability of intoxicated person.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_242"><akn:num>413.242</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisite to action against purchaser or selling agent of equine interest.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_243"><akn:num>413.243</akn:num><akn:heading>“Professional services” defined.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_245"><akn:num>413.245</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions arising out of the rendering, or failure to render, professional services to others.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_246"><akn:num>413.246</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages based on professional services rendered by licensed home inspector.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_247"><akn:num>413.247</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_248"><akn:num>413.248</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of donor for damages resulting from condition of donated food.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_2485"><akn:num>413.2485</akn:num><akn:heading>Action relating to injury to or illness of an adult as a result of a sexual offense.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_249"><akn:num>413.249</akn:num><akn:heading>Action relating to childhood sexual abuse or childhood sexual assault.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_080"><akn:num>413.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Action upon equity of redemption in personal property.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>After a mortgagee of personal property or any person claiming under him has had five (5) years’ continued adverse possession, no action shall be brought by the mortgagor or any person claiming under him to redeem the property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_090"><akn:num>413.090</akn:num><akn:heading>Action upon judgment, contract, or bond — Fifteen-year limitation — Action for child support arrearages — Time to commence action tolled until obligations cease as to last child on order.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Except as provided in KRS 396.205, 413.110, 413.220, 413.230 and 413.240, the following actions shall be commenced within fifteen (15) years after the cause of action first accrued:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_090__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon a judgment or decree of any court of this state or of the United States, or of any state or territory thereof, the period to be computed from the date of the last execution thereon;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_090__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon a recognizance, bond, or written contract , except that actions upon written contracts executed after July 15, 2014, shall be governed by KRS 413.160;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_090__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon the official bond of a sheriff, marshal, clerk, constable, or any other public officer, or any commissioner, receiver, curator, personal representative, guardian, conservator, or trustee appointed by a court or authority of law;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_090__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon an appeal bond or bond given on a supersedeas, attachment, injunction, order of arrest or for the delivery of property or for the forthcoming of property, or to obey or perform an order or judgment of court in an action, or upon a bond for costs, or any other bond taken by a court or judge or by an officer pursuant to the directions of a court or judge, in an action or after judgment or decree, or upon a replevin, sale, or delivery bond taken under execution or decree, upon an indemnifying bond taken under a statute, or upon a bond to suspend a proceeding, or upon a bond or obligation for the payment of money or property or for the performance of any undertaking; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_090__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action to recover unpaid child support arrearages, which may be initiated as one (1) cumulative action for all child support arrearages owed under a court order, with the time to commence an action under this subsection being tolled until all current child support obligations cease as to the last child covered by that order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_100"><akn:num>413.100</akn:num><akn:heading>Lienee not to extend limitation as against purchasers or creditors — Exception.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>No promise, acknowledgment or payment of money by any person bound on any bond or obligation for the payment of money secured by a lien shall operate as a prolongation or extension of the time within which the lien may be enforced as against purchasers or creditors, unless the promisor and the holder of the lien, before fifteen (15) years after the maturity of the debt, enters a memorandum on the margin of the record of the deed or mortgage, attested by the clerk, showing that the debt is extended, for what time it is extended and the amount still due thereon. The payee shall pay the clerk a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012 for his services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_110"><akn:num>413.110</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against county on bonded obligation — Three year limitation — Action on state warrant — Two year limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_110__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A cause of action existing against a county by virtue of its bonded obligation for the payment of money, after the county has in good faith offered to redeem the obligations that have matured by the payment in full of all principal and interest due, expires and becomes ineffective at the end of three (3) years after the offer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_110__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A cause of action for payment of any warrant of the Commonwealth expires and becomes noneffective unless brought within two (2) years after the Commonwealth has in good faith offered to redeem the warrant by payment in full of all interest and principal due.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_120"><akn:num>413.120</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to be brought within five years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The following actions shall be commenced within five (5) years after the cause of action accrued:</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon a contract not in writing, express or implied.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon a liability created by statute, when no other time is fixed by the statute creating the liability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action for a penalty or forfeiture when no time is fixed by the statute prescribing it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action for trespass on real or personal property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action for the profits of or damages for withholding real or personal property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action for an injury to the rights of the plaintiff, not arising on contract and not otherwise enumerated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon a bill of exchange, check, draft or order, or any endorsement thereof, or upon a promissory note, placed upon the footing of a bill of exchange.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action to enforce the liability of a steamboat or other vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon a merchant’s account for goods sold and delivered, or any article charged in such store account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon an account concerning the trade of merchandise, between merchant and merchant or their agents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_11"><akn:num>(11)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action for relief or damages on the ground of fraud or mistake.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_12"><akn:num>(12)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action to enforce the liability of bail.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_120__point_13"><akn:num>(13)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action for personal injuries suffered by any person against the builder of a home or other improvements. This cause of action shall be deemed to accrue at the time of original occupancy of the improvements which the builder caused to be erected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_125"><akn:num>413.125</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions relating to personal property to be brought within two years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>An action for the taking, detaining or injuring of personal property, including an action for specific recovery shall be commenced within two (2) years from the time the cause of action accrued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_130"><akn:num>413.130</akn:num><akn:heading>When certain actions in KRS 413.120 accrue.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_130__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In every action upon a merchants’ account as described in subsection (9) of KRS 413.120, the limitation shall be computed from January 1 next succeeding the respective dates of the delivery of the several articles charged in the account. Judgment shall be rendered for no more than the amount of articles actually charged or delivered within five (5) years preceding that in which the action was brought. If any merchant willfully postdates any article charged in such account, or the receipt for the delivery of it, he shall forfeit ten (10) times the amount of the article postdated, to be credited against the account. This credit shall be allowed in an action on the account, without any written pleadings setting it up.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_130__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In an action to recover a balance due upon a mutual open and current account concerning the trade of merchandise between merchant and merchant or their agents, as described in subsection (10) of KRS 413.120, where there have been reciprocal demands between the parties, the cause of action is deemed to have accrued from the time of the last item proved in the account claimed, or proved to be chargeable on the adverse side.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_130__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In an action for relief or damages for fraud or mistake, referred to in subsection (11) of KRS 413.120, the cause of action shall not be deemed to have accrued until the discovery of the fraud or mistake. However, the action shall be commenced within ten (10) years after the time of making the contract or the perpetration of the fraud.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_135"><akn:num>413.135</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages arising out of injury.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_135__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No action to recover damages, whether based upon contract or sounding in tort, resulting from or arising out of any deficiency in the construction components, design, planning, supervision, inspection, or construction of any improvement to real property, or for any injury to property, either real or personal, arising out of such deficiency, or for injury to the person or for wrongful death arising out of any such deficiency, shall be brought against any person after the expiration of seven (7) years following the substantial completion of such improvement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_135__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, in the case of such an injury to property or the person or wrongful death resulting from such injury, which injury occurred during the seventh year following substantial completion of such improvement, an action to recover damages for such injury or wrongful death may only be brought within one (1) year from the date upon which such injury occurred (irrespective of the date of death), but in no event may such an action be brought more than eight (8) years after the substantial completion of construction of such improvement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_135__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section shall be construed as extending the period prescribed by statute for the bringing of any action for damages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_135__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section, the term “person” shall mean an individual, corporation, partnership, business trust, unincorporated association, or joint stock company; the term “substantial completion” shall be construed to mean the date upon which the owner of the structure, project, or facility first entered upon the occupancy or commenced the use thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_137"><akn:num>413.137</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages for injury or illness suffered as a result of female genital mutilation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_137__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A civil action for recovery of damages for injury or illness suffered as a result of female genital mutilation as defined in KRS 508.125 shall be brought within ten (10) years:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Of the procedure being performed; or (b)After the victim attains the age of eighteen (18) years.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_137__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The court may award actual, compensatory, and punitive damages, and any other appropriate relief.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_137__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Treble damages may be awarded if the plaintiff proves the defendant’s acts were willful and malicious.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_140"><akn:num>413.140</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to be brought within one year.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_140__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The following actions shall be commenced within one (1) year after the cause of action accrued:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)An action for an injury to the person of the plaintiff, or of her husband, his wife, child, ward, apprentice, or servant; (b)An action for injuries to persons, cattle, or other livestock by railroads or other corporations, with the exception of hospitals licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 216; (c)An action for malicious prosecution, conspiracy, arrest, seduction, criminal conversation, or breach of promise of marriage; (d)An action for libel or slander; (e)An action against a physician, surgeon, dentist, or hospital licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 216, for negligence or malpractice; (f)A civil action, arising out of any act or omission in rendering, or failing to render, professional services for others, whether brought in tort or contract, against a real estate appraiser holding a certificate or license issued under KRS Chapter 324A or a real estate broker or sales associate holding a license issued under KRS Chapter 324; (g)An action for the escape of a prisoner, arrested or imprisoned on civil process; (h)An action for the recovery of usury paid for the loan or forbearance of money or other thing, against the loaner or forbearer or assignee of either; (i)An action for the recovery of stolen property, by the owner thereof against any person having the same in his possession; (j)An action for the recovery of damages or the value of stolen property, against the thief or any accessory; (k)An action arising out of a detention facility disciplinary proceeding, whether based upon state or federal law; (l)An action for damages arising out of a deficiency, defect, omission, error, or miscalculation in any survey or plat, whether brought in tort or contract, against a licensed professional land surveyor holding a license under KRS Chapter 322; (m)An action for violating KRS 311.782; and (n)An action for violating KRS 311.731.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_140__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In respect to the action referred to in paragraph (e) of subsection (1) of this section, the cause of action shall be deemed to accrue at the time the injury is first discovered or in the exercise of reasonable care should have been discovered; provided that such action shall be commenced within five (5) years from the date on which the alleged negligent act or omission is said to have occurred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_140__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In respect to the action referred to in paragraph (f) or (l) of subsection (1) of this section, the cause of action shall be deemed to accrue within one (1) year from the date of the occurrence or from the date when the cause of action was, or reasonably should have been, discovered by the party injured.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_140__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In respect to the action referred to in paragraph (h) of subsection (1) of this section, the cause of action shall be deemed to accrue at the time of payment. This limitation shall apply to all payments made on all demands, whether evidenced by writing or existing only in parol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_140__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In respect to the action referred to in paragraph (i) of subsection (1) of this section, the cause of action shall be deemed to accrue at the time the property is found by its owner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_140__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In respect to the action referred to in paragraph (j) of subsection (1) of this section, the cause of action shall be deemed to accrue at the time of discovery of the liability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_140__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In respect to the action referred to in paragraph (k) of subsection (1) of this section, the cause of action shall be deemed to accrue on the date an appeal of the disciplinary proceeding is decided by the institutional warden.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_140__point_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>In respect to the action referred to in subsection (1)(m) and (n) of this section, the cause of action shall be deemed to accrue after the performance or inducement or attempt to perform or induce the abortion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_150"><akn:num>413.150</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by the Commonwealth.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The limitations prescribed in this chapter shall apply to actions brought by or in the name of the Commonwealth the same as to actions by private persons, except where a different time is prescribed by statute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_160"><akn:num>413.160</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions upon written contract or not provided for by statute — Ten-year limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>An action upon a written contract executed after July 15, 2014, unless otherwise provided by statute, and an action for relief not provided for by statute can only be commenced within ten (10) years after the cause of action accrued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_170"><akn:num>413.170</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations of actions in KRS 413.090 to 413.160 do not run until removal of disability or death.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_170__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a person entitled to bring any action mentioned in KRS 413.090 to 413.160, except for a penalty or forfeiture, was, at the time the cause of action accrued, an infant or of unsound mind, the action may be brought within the same number of years after the removal of the disability or death of the person, whichever happens first, allowed to a person without the disability to bring the action after the right accrued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_170__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The right of action upon the official bond of a guardian, personal representative, curator, of the sheriff, or the officer acting as personal representative, or of any other person receiving and holding money to be distributed to a ward, distributee or devisee, under the order of court or by authority of law, of a ward, distributee, devisee or other person entitled, who was an infant when the bond was executed, shall not be deemed to have accrued, unless otherwise expressed in the bond, before the plaintiff attained the age of twenty-one (21) years. Where there are several wards, or several distributees or devisees or other beneficiaries secured by the same bond, who, or some of whom, were infants when the bond was given, the right of action of each one (1) of such infants shall not be deemed to have accrued before he attained the age of twenty-one (21) years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_180"><akn:num>413.180</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by or against personal representative under KRS 413.090 to 413.160.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_180__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a person entitled to bring any action mentioned in KRS 413.090 to 413.160 dies before the expiration of the time limited for its commencement and the cause of action survives, the action may be brought by his personal representative after the expiration of that time, if commenced within one (1) year after the qualification of the representative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_180__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a person dies before the time at which the right to bring any action mentioned in KRS 413.090 to 413.160 would have accrued to him if he had continued alive, and there is an interval of more than one (1) year between his death and the qualification of his personal representative, that representative, for purposes of this chapter, shall be deemed to have qualified on the last day of the one-year period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_190"><akn:num>413.190</akn:num><akn:heading>Result of absence from the state or obstruction of action under KRS 413.090 to 413.160.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_190__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If, at the time any cause of action mentioned in KRS 413.090 to 413.160 accrues against a resident of this state, he is absent from it, the period limited for the commencement of the action against him shall be computed from the time of his return to this state.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_190__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>When a cause of action mentioned in KRS 413.090 to 413.160 accrues against a resident of this state, and he by absconding or concealing himself or by any other indirect means obstructs the prosecution of the action, the time of the continuance of the absence from the state or obstruction shall not be computed as any part of the period within which the action shall be commenced. But this saving shall not prevent the limitation from operating in favor of any other person not so acting, whether he is a necessary party to the action or not.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_200"><akn:num>413.200</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against personal representative who has settled accounts.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_210"><akn:num>413.210</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against heirs and personal representative when estate divided.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_220"><akn:num>413.220</akn:num><akn:heading>Sureties who are discharged after seven years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_220__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A surety shall be discharged from all liability under any judgment or decree, after the lapse of seven (7) years without the issue of execution and prosecution in good faith for collection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_220__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A surety in any bond given in the course of any judicial proceeding shall be discharged from all liability on it unless suit is brought on it within seven (7) years after the cause of action accrues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_220__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A surety in any obligation or contract, other than those provided for in KRS 413.230, shall be discharged from all liability on it unless suit is brought on it within seven (7) years after the cause of action accrues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_230"><akn:num>413.230</akn:num><akn:heading>Sureties who are discharged after five years.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A surety for an executor, administrator, guardian or curator, or for a sheriff to whom a decedent’s estate has been transferred, shall be discharged from all liability to a distributee, devisee or ward when five (5) years have elapsed without suit after the cause of action accrued, and after the devisee, distributee or ward attained full age. But the failure of one to commence action in time shall not affect the right of another.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_240"><akn:num>413.240</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against surety — When limitation does not run.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The limitations given in KRS 413.220 and 413.230 shall not apply to the time elapsed when there was no executor, administrator or other person authorized to commence an action, nor to the six (6) months during which an action cannot be brought against a personal representative, nor to any delay assented to by the surety in writing. If judgment is rendered for the plaintiff in any case provided for in those sections and it is afterwards reversed or arrested so that the plaintiff takes nothing by it, he may commence another action within one (1) year thereafter. If the surety absconds, conceals himself or by removal from the state or otherwise, obstructs or hinders his being sued the time of such obstruction shall not be counted as part of the time of limitation allowed by those sections. If the judgment is obstructed by appeal, supersedeas or injunction the time of such obstruction shall also be disallowed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_241"><akn:num>413.241</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislative finding — Limitation on liability of licensed sellers or servers of intoxicating beverages — Liability of intoxicated person.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_241__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The General Assembly finds and declares that the consumption of intoxicating beverages, rather than the serving, furnishing, or sale of such beverages, is the proximate cause of any injury, including death and property damage, inflicted by an intoxicated person upon himself or another person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_241__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Any other law to the contrary notwithstanding, no person holding a permit under KRS Chapters 241 to 244, nor any agent, servant, or employee of the person, who sells or serves intoxicating beverages to a person over the age for the lawful purchase thereof, shall be liable to that person or to any other person or to the estate, successors, or survivors of either for any injury suffered off the premises including but not limited to wrongful death and property damage, because of the intoxication of the person to whom the intoxicating beverages were sold or served, unless a reasonable person under the same or similar circumstances should know that the person served is already intoxicated at the time of serving.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_241__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The intoxicated person shall be primarily liable with respect to injuries suffered by third persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_241__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The limitation of liability provided by this section shall not apply to any person who causes or contributes to the consumption of alcoholic beverages by force or by falsely representing that a beverage contains no alcohol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_241__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>This section shall not apply to civil actions filed prior to July 15, 1988.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_242"><akn:num>413.242</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisite to action against purchaser or selling agent of equine interest.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Before a party possessing a security interest or lien against an equine interest that has been sold without the debt to the party being discharged may bring an action against the purchaser or selling agent of the equine interest, the secured party shall pursue a remedy against the debtor to the point where a judgment is rendered on the merits or the suit is dismissed with prejudice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_243"><akn:num>413.243</akn:num><akn:heading>“Professional services” defined.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>As used in KRS 413.245, “professional services” means any service rendered in a profession required to be licensed, administered and regulated as professions in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, except those professions governed by KRS 413.140.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_245"><akn:num>413.245</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions arising out of the rendering, or failure to render, professional services to others.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Notwithstanding any other prescribed limitation of actions which might otherwise appear applicable, except those provided in KRS 413.140, a civil action, whether brought in tort or contract, arising out of any act or omission in rendering, or failing to render, professional services for others shall be brought within one (1) year from the date of the occurrence or from the date when the cause of action was, or reasonably should have been, discovered by the party injured. Time shall not commence against a party under legal disability until removal of the disability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_246"><akn:num>413.246</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for damages based on professional services rendered by licensed home inspector.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_246__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>An action for damages, whether brought in contract or tort, or on any other basis, based on professional services that were rendered or that should have been rendered by a licensed home inspector under KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738 shall not be brought, commenced, or maintained unless the action is filed within one (1) year of the time that the claimant knew or should have known of a deficient inspection and damages and injuries resulting therefrom.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_246__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>Nothing in this section creates any duty to a third party that is not available under common law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_247"><akn:num>413.247</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_248"><akn:num>413.248</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of donor for damages resulting from condition of donated food.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_2485"><akn:num>413.2485</akn:num><akn:heading>Action relating to injury to or illness of an adult as a result of a sexual offense.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_2485__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section, “injury or illness” means either a physical or psychological injury or illness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_2485__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A civil action for recovery of damages for an injury or illness suffered as a result of an act or series of acts against a person eighteen (18) years old or older that meets the criteria of KRS 510.040, 510.050, 510.060, 510.070, 510.080, 510.090, 510.110, 510.120, 510.130, 510.140, 510.150, 529.100 where the offense involves commercial sexual activity, 529.110 where the offense involves commercial sexual activity, 530.020, 531.090, or 531.100, shall be brought before whichever of the following periods last expires:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Within five (5) years of the act or the last of a series of acts by the same perpetrator; (b)Within five (5) years of the date the victim knew, or should have known, of the act; (c)Within five (5) years upon knowledge or identity of the perpetrator; or (d)Within five (5) years of the conviction of a civil defendant for KRS 510.040, 510.050, 510.060, 510.070, 510.080, 510.090, 510.110, 510.120, 510.130, 510.140, 510.150, 529.100 where the offense involves commercial sexual activity, 529.110 where the offense involves commercial sexual activity, 530.020, 531.090, or 531.100.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_2485__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>No prior criminal prosecution or conviction of the civil defendant for the act or series of acts shall be required to bring a civil action under this section for redress of an injury or illness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_249"><akn:num>413.249</akn:num><akn:heading>Action relating to childhood sexual abuse or childhood sexual assault.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_249__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)“Childhood sexual assault or abuse” means an act or series of acts against a person less than eighteen (18) years old and which meets the criteria defining a misdemeanor or felony in: 1.KRS Chapter 510; 2.KRS 529.040 when the defendant advances or profits from the prostitution of a minor; 3.KRS 529.100 when the offense involves commercial sexual activity; 4.KRS 529.110 when the offense involves commercial sexual activity; 5.KRS 530.020 or 530.064(1)(a); 6.KRS Chapter 531 involving a minor or depiction of a minor; or 7.KRS 506.010 or 506.030 for attempt to commit or solicitation to commit any of the offenses described in subparagraphs 1. to 6. of this paragraph. No prior criminal prosecution or conviction of the civil defendant for the act or series of acts shall be required to bring a civil action for redress of childhood sexual assault or abuse; (b)“Entity” means a firm, partnership, company, corporation, trustee, association, or any private or public entity, including the Commonwealth, a city, county, urban-county, consolidated local government, unified local government, or charter county government, or any of their agencies, departments, or any KRS 58.180 nonprofit nonstock corporation; and (c)“Injury or illness” means either a physical or psychological injury or illness.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_249__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A civil action for recovery of damages for injury or illness suffered as a result of childhood sexual assault or abuse shall be brought before whichever of the following periods last expires:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)Within ten (10) years of the commission of the act or the last of a series of acts by the same perpetrator; (b)Within ten (10) years of the date the victim knew, or should have known, of the act; (c)Within ten (10) years after the victim attains the age of eighteen (18) years; or (d)Within ten (10) years of the conviction of a civil defendant for an offense included in the definition of childhood sexual assault or abuse.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_249__point_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>The time periods set forth in subsection (2) of this section shall apply to a civil action for recovery of damages for injury or illness against;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)A person alleged to have committed the act of childhood sexual assault or abuse; or (b)An entity that owed a duty of care to the plaintiff, where a wrongful or negligent act by an employee, officer, director, official, volunteer, representative, or agent of the entity was a legal cause of the childhood sexual assault or abuse that resulted in the injury to the plaintiff.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_249__point_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If a complaint is filed alleging that an act of childhood sexual assault or abuse occurred more than ten (10) years prior to the date that the action is commenced, the complaint shall be accompanied by a motion to seal the record and the complaint shall immediately be sealed by the clerk of the court. The complaint shall remain sealed until:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(a)The court rules upon the motion to seal; (b)Any motion to dismiss under CR 12.02 is ruled upon, and if the complaint is dismissed, the complaint and any related papers or pleadings shall remain sealed unless opened by a higher court; or (c)The defendant files an answer and a motion to seal the record upon grounds that a valid factual defense exists, to be raised in a motion for summary judgment pursuant to CR 56. The record shall remain sealed by the clerk until the court rules upon the defendant’s motion to close the record. If the court grants the motion to close, the record shall remain sealed until the defendant’s motion for summary judgment is granted. The complaint, motions, and other related papers or pleadings shall remain sealed unless opened by a higher court.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_249__point_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>A victim of childhood sexual assault or abuse shall not have a cause of action against a third party, unless the third party failed to act as a reasonable person or entity in complying with their duties to the victim. If a victim of childhood sexual assault or abuse has a cause of action under this section, the cause of action shall be commenced within the time period set forth in subsection (2) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_249__point_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)Neither the husband-wife nor any professional-client/patient privilege, except the attorney-client and clergy-penitent privilege, shall be a ground for excluding evidence regarding childhood sexual assault or abuse or the cause thereof when an exception to the Kentucky Rules of Evidence is met, in any judicial proceeding. This subsection shall also apply in any criminal proceeding in District or Circuit Court regarding childhood sexual assault or abuse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)As used in paragraph (a) of this subsection, the clergy-penitent privilege is limited to information received solely through confidential communications with a clergy member, privately or in a confessional setting, when in the course of the discipline or practice of the clergy member’s church, denomination, or organization, he or she is authorized or accustomed to hearing those communications, and under the discipline, tenets, customs, or practices of his or her church, denomination, or organization, has a duty to keep those communications secret.</akn:p><akn:point eId="sec_413_249__point_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)As was its intention with the passage of 2017 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 2, the General Assembly hereby states that the amendments enacted in 2017 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 2 shall be applied retroactively to actions accruing before its effective date of June 29, 2017. This section is a remedial statute which is to be given the most liberal interpretation to provide remedies for victims of childhood sexual assault or abuse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:p>(b)Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, any claim for childhood sexual assault or abuse that was barred as of March 23, 2021 because the applicable statute of limitations had expired is hereby revived, and the action may be brought if commenced within five (5) years of the date on which the applicable statute of limitations expired.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_250"><akn:num>413.250</akn:num><akn:heading>When action commences.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_260"><akn:num>413.260</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of injunction or other restraint on limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_265"><akn:num>413.265</akn:num><akn:heading>Validity of agreements extending limitations periods.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_270"><akn:num>413.270</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of judgment of no jurisdiction — Application to administrative agencies.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_280"><akn:num>413.280</akn:num><akn:heading>Person under more than one disability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_290"><akn:num>413.290</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations only to residents — Notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_300"><akn:num>413.300</akn:num><akn:heading>Plaintiff a citizen of enemy country.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_310"><akn:num>413.310</akn:num><akn:heading>Plaintiff’s confinement in penitentiary.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_320"><akn:num>413.320</akn:num><akn:heading>Cause of action barred here if barred where it accrued.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_330"><akn:num>413.330</akn:num><akn:heading>Action on judgment barred here if barred where rendered — Exception.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_340"><akn:num>413.340</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions as to chapter.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_250"><akn:num>413.250</akn:num><akn:heading>When action commences.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>An action shall be deemed to commence on the date of the first summons or process issued in good faith from the court having jurisdiction of the cause of action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_260"><akn:num>413.260</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of injunction or other restraint on limitation.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_260__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If the doing of an act necessary to save any right or benefit is restrained or suspended by injunction or other lawful restraint, vacancy in office, absence of an officer or his refusal to act, the time covered by the injunction, restraint, vacancy, absence or refusal to act shall not be counted in the application of any statute of limitations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_260__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>When the collection of a judgment or the commencement of an action is stayed by injunction, the time of continuance of the injunction shall not be counted as part of the period limited for the collection of the judgment or the commencement of the action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_265"><akn:num>413.265</akn:num><akn:heading>Validity of agreements extending limitations periods.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Written agreements entered into in good faith and at arms length to extend limitations periods for the filing of civil actions, including agreements entered into prior to July 15, 1988, shall be valid and enforceable according to their terms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_270"><akn:num>413.270</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of judgment of no jurisdiction — Application to administrative agencies.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:point eId="sec_413_270__point_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>If an action is commenced in due time and in good faith in any court of this state and the defendants or any of them make defense, and it is adjudged that the court has no jurisdiction of the action, the plaintiff or his representative may, within ninety (90) days from the time of that judgment, commence a new action in the proper court. The time between the commencement of the first and last action shall not be counted in applying any statute of limitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point><akn:point eId="sec_413_270__point_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>As used in this section, “court” means all courts, commissions, and boards which are judicial or quasi-judicial tribunals authorized by the Constitution or statutes of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or of the United States of America.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:point></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_280"><akn:num>413.280</akn:num><akn:heading>Person under more than one disability.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>When two (2) or more disabilities exist in the same person at the time the cause of action accrues, the limitation does not attach until they are all removed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_290"><akn:num>413.290</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations only to residents — Notice.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Limitations shall not begin to run in favor of persons coming temporarily into this state, but shall attach only in favor of actual residents in good faith, and after notice to the person to be affected thereby.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_300"><akn:num>413.300</akn:num><akn:heading>Plaintiff a citizen of enemy country.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the plaintiff is an alien and a subject or citizen of a country at war with the United States, the time of the continuance of the war shall not be counted as part of the period limited for the commencement of an action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_310"><akn:num>413.310</akn:num><akn:heading>Plaintiff’s confinement in penitentiary.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_320"><akn:num>413.320</akn:num><akn:heading>Cause of action barred here if barred where it accrued.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>When a cause of action has arisen in another state or country, and by the laws of this state or country where the cause of action accrued the time for the commencement of an action thereon is limited to a shorter period of time than the period of limitation prescribed by the laws of this state for a like cause of action, then said action shall be barred in this state at the expiration of said shorter period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_330"><akn:num>413.330</akn:num><akn:heading>Action on judgment barred here if barred where rendered — Exception.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If, by the laws of any other state or country, an action upon a judgment or decree rendered in that state or country cannot be maintained there by reason of the lapse of time, and the judgment or decree is incapable of being otherwise enforced there, an action upon it may not be maintained in this state, except in favor of a resident thereof who has had the cause of action from the time it accrued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_413_340"><akn:num>413.340</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions as to chapter.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter><akn:chapter eId="chap_415"><akn:num>Chapter 415</akn:num><akn:heading>Repeal or Vacation of Charters — Usurpation</akn:heading><akn:section eId="sec_415_010"><akn:num>415.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Style of action to repeal charter — Prosecution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_020"><akn:num>415.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of Legislature needed to repeal or vacate certain charters.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_030"><akn:num>415.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to prevent usurpation of office or franchise.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_040"><akn:num>415.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Commonwealth’s attorneys.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_050"><akn:num>415.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of the Attorney General.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_060"><akn:num>415.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings for usurpation against person holding office.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_070"><akn:num>415.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Judgment against usurper — Enforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_080"><akn:num>415.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of fees and emoluments from usurper.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p /></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_010"><akn:num>415.010</akn:num><akn:heading>Style of action to repeal charter — Prosecution.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>The action to repeal or vacate a charter shall be in the name of the Commonwealth, and be brought and prosecuted by the Attorney General, or under his sanction and direction by an attorney for the Commonwealth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_020"><akn:num>415.020</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of Legislature needed to repeal or vacate certain charters.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>Actions to repeal or vacate the charters of municipal corporations; banks, railroad, turnpike road and internal improvement companies, shall only be instituted by order of the Legislature, unless otherwise expressly provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_030"><akn:num>415.030</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to prevent usurpation of office or franchise.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If a person usurp an office or franchise, the person entitled thereto, or the Commonwealth, may prevent the usurpation by an ordinary action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_040"><akn:num>415.040</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Commonwealth’s attorneys.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>It shall be the duty of the several Commonwealth attorneys to institute the actions mentioned in this chapter against usurpers of county offices or franchises, if no other person be entitled thereto, or if the person entitled fail to institute the same during three (3) months after the usurpation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_050"><akn:num>415.050</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of the Attorney General.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>For usurpation of other than county offices or franchises, the action by the Commonwealth shall be instituted and prosecuted by the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_060"><akn:num>415.060</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings for usurpation against person holding office.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A person who continues to exercise an office after having committed an act, or omitted to do an act, the commission or omission of which, by law, creates a forfeiture of his office, may be proceeded against for usurpation thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_070"><akn:num>415.070</akn:num><akn:heading>Judgment against usurper — Enforcement.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>A person adjudged to have usurped an office or franchise shall be deprived thereof by the judgment of the court, and the person adjudged entitled thereto shall be placed in possession thereof; but no one shall be adjudged entitled thereto, unless the action be instituted by him. And the court shall have power to enforce its judgment by causing the books and papers, and all other things pertaining to the office or franchise, to be surrendered by the usurper; and by preventing him from further exercising or using the same; and may enforce its orders by fine and imprisonment until obeyed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section><akn:section eId="sec_415_080"><akn:num>415.080</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of fees and emoluments from usurper.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>If the usurper has received fees and emoluments arising from the office or franchise, he shall be liable therefor to the person entitled thereto, who may claim the same in the action brought to deprive him of the office or franchise; or in a separate action. If no one is entitled to them, they may be recovered by the Commonwealth, and shall be paid into the public Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:chapter></akn:title></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>