<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/403.353"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/403.353"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/403.353/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/403.353/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/403.353/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/403.353/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_403_353">
        <num>403.353</num>
        <content>
          <p>Power of Attorney for Temporary Delegation of Parental or Legal Custody and Care 1. I certify that I am the parent or legal guardian of: (Full name of minor child) (Date of birth) (Full name of minor child) (Date of birth) (Full name of minor child) (Date of birth) 2. I designate , (Full name of Attorney-in-fact) (Street address, city, state, and zip code of Attorney-in-fact) (Home phone of Attorney-in-fact) as the Attorney-in-fact of each minor child named above. (Work phone of Attorney-in-fact) 3. I delegate to the Attorney-in-fact all of my power and authority regarding the care, custody, and property of each minor child named above, including but not limited to the right to enroll the child in school, inspect and obtain copies of education records and other records concerning the child, the right to attend school activities and other functions concerning the child, and the right to give or withhold any consent or waiver with respect to school activities, medical and dental treatment, and any other activity, function, or treatment that may concern the child. This delegation shall not include the power or authority to consent to marriage or adoption of the child, the performance or inducement of an abortion on or for the child, or the termination of parental rights to the child. OR In the event that Section 4 is completed, Section 3 does not apply. 4. I delegate to the Attorney-in-fact the following specific powers and responsibilities (write in): 5. This power of attorney is effective for a period not to exceed one (1) year, , , beginning 20 and , . ending 20 I reserve the right to revoke this authority at any time. OR In the event Section 6 is completed and valid, Section 5 does not apply. 6. I am a parent or legal guardian on active duty as governed by KRS .My active duty service is scheduled to, , and is estimated to , . I acknowledge that in no event may this delegation of power last more than one (1) year or the term of my active duty plus thirty (30) days, whichever is longer. begin on 20 end on 20 7. BY: (Parent/Legal Guardian signature) 8. I hereby accept my designation as Attorney-in-fact for the minor child or children specified in this power of attorney. (Attorney-in-fact signature) County of ACKNOWLEDGMENT Before me, the undersigned, a Notary Public, in and for said County and State on this ,, personally appeared day of 20 (Name of Parent/Legal Guardian) , (Name of Attorney-in-fact) to me known to be the identical persons who executed this instrument and acknowledged to me that each executed the same as his or her free and voluntary act and deed for the uses and purposes set forth in the instrument. Witness my hand and official seal the day and year above written. (Signature of notary public) .” My commission expires:</p>
          <p>Click to view</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
