<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/200.501"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/200.501"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/200.501/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/200.501/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/200.501/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/200.501/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_200_501">
        <num>200.501</num>
        <content>
          <p>The Kentucky General Assembly finds that services to children and transition-age youth are provided by various departments and agencies at both the state and local level, often without appropriate policy collaboration and service coordination. The General Assembly declares that the purpose of  to is to establish a structure for coordinated policy development, comprehensive planning, and collaborative budgeting for services and supports to children and transition-age youth with or at risk of developing behavioral health needs and their families. It is further the intention of the General Assembly to build on the existing resources and to design and implement a system of care for children and transition-age youth with or at risk of developing behavioral health needs that is community-based, family- and youth-driven, and culturally and linguistically competent. Children and transition-age youth who meet criteria for a serious emotional disability, including a co-occurring substance use disorder, and who are placed outside their homes to address unmet behavioral health needs shall be given priority for services and supports pursuant to  to</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
