<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/238.500"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/238.500"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/238.500/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/238.500/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/238.500/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/238.500/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_238_500">
        <num>238.500</num>
        <content>
          <p>The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky hereby declares that charitable gaming conducted by charitable organizations is an important method of raising funds for legitimate charitable purposes and is in the public interest. The purpose of this chapter is to comply with constitutional requirements by establishing an effective and efficient mechanism for regulating charitable gaming which includes defining the scope of charitable gaming activities, setting standards for the conduct of charitable gaming which insure honesty and integrity, providing for means of accounting for all moneys generated through the conduct of charitable gaming, and providing for suitable penalties for violations of laws and administrative regulations. The intent of this chapter is to prevent the commercialization of charitable gaming, to prevent participation in charitable gaming by criminal and other undesirable elements, and to prevent the diversion of funds from legitimate charitable purposes. In order to carry out the purpose and intent, the provisions of this chapter, and any administrative regulations promulgated in accordance with this chapter, shall be construed in the public interest and strictly enforced.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
