<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/386.570"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/386.570"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/386.570/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/386.570/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/386.570/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/386.570/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_386_570">
        <num>386.570</num>
        <content>
          <p>The commissioner of financial institutions shall have authority to adopt and issue reasonable and uniform rules and regulations to govern the conduct and management of all fiduciary investment companies having investment advisers other than national banks. The commissioner of financial institutions may, whenever he may deem it necessary or expedient, examine every fiduciary investment company contemplated by  to having an investment adviser which is not a national bank. In every such examination, the commissioner of financial institutions shall make inquiry as to its financial condition, the policies of its management, whether it is complying with the laws of Kentucky, and such other matters as the commissioner of financial institutions may reasonably prescribe. In the enforcement of  to and the restrictions and limitations imposed by their articles of incorporation and bylaws, the commissioner of financial institutions shall have the same powers and authority with respect to fiduciary investment companies having investment advisers other than a national bank as are conferred upon him by the laws of this state with respect to state banks and trust companies to the same extent and in the same manner as if fiduciary investment companies were expressly named in Subtitle 3 of  of the Kentucky Revised Statutes.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
