<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/610.180"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/610.180"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/610.180/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/610.180/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/610.180/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/610.180/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_610_180">
        <num>610.180</num>
        <content>
          <p>A parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision of a child is charged with the control of such child and shall have the power to exercise parental control and authority over such child. In any case where a child is adjudicated a public offender and placed on probation, if the court finds at the hearing that the person having custody of such child has failed or neglected to subject him to reasonable parental control and authority, and that such failure or neglect is the proximate cause of the act or acts of the child upon which the adjudication is based, the court may require such parent to enter into a recognizance with sufficient surety, in an amount of not more than five hundred dollars ($500), conditioned upon the faithful discharge of the conditions of probation of such child. If the child thereafter commits a second act and is by reason thereof adjudicated a public offender, or violates the conditions of probation, and the court finds at the hearing that the failure or neglect of such parent to subject him to reasonable parental control and authority or to faithfully discharge the conditions of probation of such child on the part of such parent, is the proximate cause of the act of the child upon which such second finding is based, or upon which such child is found to have violated the conditions of his probation, the court may declare all or a part of the recognizance forfeited and the amount of such forfeited recognizance shall be applied in payment of any damages which may have been caused by such child, if there be such damages, otherwise, the proceeds therefrom, or part remaining after the payment of damages as aforesaid, shall be retained by the court to apply to any future damages resulting from the act or acts of said child before he reaches his eighteenth birthday, at which date the remaining proceeds shall be returned to the parent or guardian. The provisions of this section as it relates to failure or neglect of parents to subject a child to reasonable parental control and authority shall be in addition to and not in substitution for any other sections of KRS Chapters 600 to 645 relating to failure or neglect to exercise such parental control or authority. The provisions of this section shall not apply to foster parents.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
