<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.404"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.404"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.404/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.404/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.404/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.404/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142_404">
        <num>142.404</num>
        <content>
          <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the president, vice president, secretary, treasurer, manager, partner, or any other person holding any equivalent office or position in any corporation, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or limited liability limited partnership subject to  and shall be personally and individually liable, both jointly and severally, for the tax imposed under . Dissolution, withdrawal of the corporation, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or limited liability limited partnership from the state, or the cessation of holding any office shall not discharge the liability of any person. The liability shall attach at the time the tax becomes or became due. No person shall be held liable under this section if the person did not have authority to collect, truthfully account for, or pay over the tax at the time it became due. “Taxes” as used in this section shall include interest accrued under  and all applicable penalties imposed under this chapter or , to  and</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
