<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.357"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.357"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.357/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.357/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.357/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/142.357/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_142_357">
        <num>142.357</num>
        <content>
          <p>Notwithstanding any other provisions of  to  the president, vice president, secretary, treasurer, or any other person holding any equivalent corporate office of any corporation subject to the provisions of  to shall be personally and individually liable jointly and severally, for the taxes imposed under ,        and  Neither the corporate dissolution or withdrawal of the corporation from the state nor the cessation of holding any corporate office shall discharge the liability imposed by this section. The personal and individual liability shall apply to each and every person holding a corporate office at the time the taxes become or became due. No person will be personally and individually liable pursuant to this section if that person did not have authority in the management of the business or financial affairs of the corporation at the time the taxes imposed by ,        and  “Taxes” as used in this section shall include interest accrued at the rate provided by  and all applicable penalties and fees imposed under the provisions of  to and ,  and</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
