<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.420"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.420"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.420/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.420/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.420/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.420/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_420">
        <num>21.420</num>
        <content>
          <p>If a retiree, living or deceased, chose either of the optional retirement benefit allowances specified in paragraphs (a) or (b) of this subsection from July 15, 1994, to July 15, 1998, the optional allowance shall be adjusted accordingly, and the new benefit shall commence August 1, 1998. Each recipient of benefits from the plan, who retired from July 15, 1994, to July 15, 1998, shall have a one-time opportunity to select an optional retirement allowance. The election by the recipient shall be prior to August 1, 1998, at which time the new benefit shall commence. The option chosen shall prevail, subsections (1), (2), and (3) of this section notwithstanding.</p>
          <p>In lieu of the benefits provided by this paragraph to the surviving spouse, the member may elect to have the benefits payable under this paragraph paid to an individual dependent child by completing the forms provided prescribed by the Judicial Form Retirement System. If no surviving spouse or dependent children are eligible to receive benefits, then the provisions of subsection (4) of this section shall apply to the member.</p>
          <p>In lieu of the benefits provided by this paragraph to the surviving spouse, the member may elect prior to retirement to have the benefits payable under this paragraph paid to an individual dependent child by completing the forms provided by the Judicial Form Retirement System. If no surviving spouse or dependent children are eligible to receive benefits, then the provisions of subsection (5) of this section shall apply to the member.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
