<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.560"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.560"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.560/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.560/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.560/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/21.560/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_21_560">
        <num>21.560</num>
        <content>
          <p>The members of the board of trustees of the Judicial Form Retirement System who are appointed by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, singly or jointly, together with the members of the board who are appointed by the Governor, shall constitute an investment committee for the Legislators’ Retirement Plan, and as such shall have all the powers and duties with respect to the legislators’ retirement fund as are given by  and to the investment committee of the Judicial Retirement Plan with respect to the judicial retirement fund. The committee provided for by this section may, with the concurrence of the investment committee for the Judicial Retirement Plan, arrange for the legislators’ retirement fund and the judicial retirement fund to constitute a common fund for investment purposes only, to be under the management of the investment committee for the Judicial Retirement Plan, each fund sharing in the common fund in proportion to the value of its assets contributed to the common fund.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
