<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/281.765"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/281.765"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/281.765/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/281.765/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/281.765/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/281.765/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_281_765">
        <num>281.765</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any peace officer, including sheriffs and their deputies, constables and their deputies, city police officers, county police or patrols, and special officers appointed by any agency of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for the enforcement of its laws relating to motor vehicles and boats or boating, now existing or hereafter enacted, shall be authorized and it is hereby made the duty of each of them to enforce the provisions of this chapter and to make arrests for any violation or violations thereof, and for violations of any other law relating to motor vehicles and boating, without warrant if the offense be committed in his presence, and with warrant or summons if he does not observe the commission of the offense. When in pursuit of any offender for any offense committed within his jurisdiction, any such officer may follow and effect an arrest beyond the limits of his jurisdiction. If the arrest be made without warrant, the accused may elect to be immediately taken before the nearest court having jurisdiction, whereupon it shall be the duty of the officer to so take him. If the accused elects not to be so taken, then it shall be the duty of the officer to require of the accused a bail-bond in a sum not less than one hundred dollars ($100), conditioned that the accused binds himself to appear in the court of jurisdiction at the time fixed in the bond, not however in any case later than six (6) days from the day of arrest. In case the arrested person fails to appear on the day fixed, the bond shall be forfeited in the manner as is provided for the forfeiture of bonds in other cases. No officer shall be permitted to take a cash bond. The officer making the arrest and taking the bond shall report the same to the court having jurisdiction within eighteen (18) hours after taking such bond.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
