<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/15.707"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/15.707"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/15.707/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/15.707/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/15.707/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/15.707/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_15_707">
        <num>15.707</num>
        <content>
          <p>The Prosecutors Advisory Council shall have the power to issue subpoenas requiring the attendance of such witnesses and the production of such records, books, papers, and documents as it may deem necessary for investigation of any matter that it is authorized to consider or reasonably necessary therefor. Subpoenas may be signed and oaths administered by any member of the council. Subpoenas so issued shall be served by any sheriff, constable, police officer, or other peace officer at the request of the council, and a return of subpoena shall be made to the council in the same manner as similar process in the Circuit Court. Any person who refuses to testify, testifies falsely, or fails to appear when subpoenaed, or fails or refuses to produce documents, records, or other such material when subpoenaed, or fails or refuses to serve a subpoena or execute a return thereon, upon citation by the Franklin Circuit Court and after hearing by the court, shall be subject to the same order and penalties to which persons before that court are subject. Any Circuit Court, upon application of the council or the Attorney General, may compel the attendance of witnesses, the production of documents, records, or other such material, and the giving of testimony before the council.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
