<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/353.060"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/353.060"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/353.060/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/353.060/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/353.060/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/353.060/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_353_060">
        <num>353.060</num>
        <content>
          <p>2. (a)
      At the hearing, the well operator and the coal operator or owner, in person or by a representative, shall consider the objections and either agree upon the location as proposed or change it so as to satisfy all objections and meet the approval of the department.</p>
          <p>3.
      If no objections are filed within the fifteen (15) day period, the department shall immediately issue to the well operator a drilling permit approving the location and authorizing the well operator to proceed to drill there.</p>
        </content>
        <subsection eId="sec_353_060__subsec_b">
          <num>(b)</num>
          <content>
            <p>Any new location thus selected and agreed upon shall be indicated on a plat in accordance with  and thereupon the department shall issue to the well operator a drilling permit approving the location and authorizing the well operator to drill at the location.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
        <subsection eId="sec_353_060__subsec_c">
          <num>(c)</num>
          <content>
            <p>If the coal operator and well operator, or the owner and well operator, are unable to agree, the hearing officer shall make a recommendation to the secretary, in view of the purposes and intent of this chapter and in compliance therewith, to fix a location on the tract as near the proposed location as possible and upon final order of the secretary, the department shall issue to the well operator a permit to drill at the new location.</p>
          </content>
        </subsection>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
