<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/268.360"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/268.360"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/268.360/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/268.360/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/268.360/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/268.360/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_268_360">
        <num>268.360</num>
        <content>
          <p>“State of Kentucky. “County of “In the matter of the (drainage), (levee), (reclamation) district. Notice is hereby given to all persons interested that the board of drainage commissioners of County did on the day of , 19, file in my office copies of the drainage assessment record for the above district in which they show the aggregate costs of the improvements to be made according to the plan for reclamation, also the aggregate of all benefits to property and the minimum district assessment and the apportionment thereof to each piece of property, together with the total of such assessments which are to be paid for each separate piece of property. “All persons interested are hereby notified that they may inspect this record at any time, and are given until to file written objections to these final assessments. “Unless you file objections thereto by that date, it will be taken for granted that the assessments are correct, and correctly apportioned to each separate piece of property, and they will be confirmed, and become the fixed assessments upon each piece of property. “Given under my hand as county clerk on this the day of , 19 Clerk.”</p>
          <p>Click to view</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
