<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/269.220"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/269.220"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/269.220/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/269.220/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/269.220/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/269.220/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_269_220">
        <num>269.220</num>
        <content>
          <p>Upon the petition of the corporation desiring an extension or addition to the boundaries of its drainage district, the petition to be accompanied by a map showing the desired extension or addition, the county judge/executive shall cause summons to be issued against the owners of lands within the proposed extension or added territory calling upon them to show cause why the extension or addition should not be made. If a numerical majority of the persons owning land within the proposed extension or addition consent of record to it, the county judge/executive shall enter an order establishing the extension or additional boundary. Appeal shall lie for sixty (60) days to the Circuit Court, and if the order is affirmed or reversed, then to the Court of Appeals. The county judge/executive and Circuit Court shall certify to the county clerk their orders and judgments, which shall be recorded in the book showing the assessment and taxes. The extension or added territory shall be subject to the same provisions as the original district, and an assessment may be initiated by the corporation and by the owners of more than half the land within the extension or addition. The assessment shall be for the remaining years of the ten (10) year term as provided for other property in the district, and steps to perfect the assessment with respect to added or extended territory shall be had in accordance with the provisions for the original district.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
