<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/117.175"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/117.175"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/117.175/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/117.175/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/117.175/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/117.175/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_117_175">
        <num>117.175</num>
        <content>
          <p>The county clerk shall, with the county attorney, prepare a sufficient number of instruction cards containing instructions as to the proper method of voting by the use of the voting equipment, and instructions as to the proper method of casting a write-in vote. For federal provisional ballots and supplemental paper ballots, if approved as provided in , the instruction cards shall indicate the offices, candidates, and questions which will appear on the federal provisional or supplemental paper ballots, the offices that will appear on the federal provisional or supplemental ballot, the instructions for marking and depositing the federal provisional or supplemental paper ballots, instructions for filling out the federal provisional or supplemental ballot, and instructions on how to properly execute the voter affirmations. The instruction cards shall be examined and approved by the county board of elections at the time the voting equipment is examined and approved. The instruction cards shall be delivered to each election clerk by the county clerk at the time that other election supplies are delivered and the election clerk shall post the instruction card at the polling place.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
