<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/120.065"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/120.065"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/120.065/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/120.065/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/120.065/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/120.065/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_120_065">
        <num>120.065</num>
        <content>
          <p>Each party to a contest instituted
    under  shall be entitled, in the production of evidence to be used
    on the trial thereof, to all the remedies allowed in cases at law and in equity.
    In trying the contest the court shall hear and determine all questions of
    law and fact without the intervention of a jury, and may examine the witnesses
    orally or require or permit the parties to take the evidence by depositions.
    If the evidence is taken orally either party may require it to be taken by
    the official reporter for the court, to be taken and transcribed and paid
    for as evidence in other civil actions. The court may require the contestant,
    or the person who has the burden of proof under the issue joined, to complete
    his proof in not less than fifteen (15) days after service of summons, and
    the contestee, or the person not having the burden, to complete his proof
    in not less than ten (10) days after filing an answer. Each party may be given
    one (1) day additional for producing evidence in rebuttal and no greater time
    shall be extended, unless the court is satisfied that the ends of justice
    demand it. The court shall, immediately after the evidence is concluded, consider
    the contest and determine it. If it appears from an inspection of the whole
    record that there has been such fraud, intimidation, bribery or violence in
    the conduct of the election that neither contestant nor contestee can be adjudged
    to have been fairly nominated, the court may adjudge that there has been no
    election, in which event the nomination shall be deemed vacant. The judgment
    of the court shall be filed in the office of the Circuit Court clerk.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
