<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/342.435"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/342.435"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/342.435/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/342.435/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/342.435/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/342.435/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_342_435">
        <num>342.435</num>
        <content>
          <p>Annually on or before the fifteenth day of December, the commissioner shall make a report to the Governor for the preceding fiscal year, which shall include a statement of the number of awards made and of claims rejected by the board and each administrative law judge, a general statement of the causes of accident leading to the injuries for which awards were made or rejected claims based, together with any other information which the commissioner deems proper to call to the attention of the Governor, including any recommendations he may have to make, and it shall be the duty of the commissioner to publish and distribute among employers and employees any general information as to the business transacted by the department as may be useful and necessary. The annual report shall not exceed ten thousand (10,000) copies. All printing of the department shall be done by the contractor or contractors for public printing, subject to the provisions of the general laws governing public printing applicable thereto.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
