<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/344.340"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/344.340"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/344.340/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/344.340/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/344.340/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/344.340/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_344_340">
        <num>344.340</num>
        <content>
          <p>The proceeding for enforcement of a local commission order is initiated by filing a complaint in the Circuit Court. Copies of the complaint shall be served upon all parties of record. Within thirty (30) days after the filing of the complaint by the local commission, or within such further time as the court may allow, the local commission shall transmit to the court the original or a certified copy of the entire record upon which the order is based, including a transcript of testimony, which need not be printed. By stipulation of all parties to the proceeding, the record may be shortened. The findings of fact of the local commission shall be conclusive unless clearly erroneous in view of the probative and substantial evidence on the whole record. The court shall have power to grant such temporary relief or restraining order as it deems just, and to enter an order enforcing, modifying and enforcing as modified, or setting aside in whole or in part the order of the local commission, or remanding the case to the local commission for further proceedings.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
