<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/100.311"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/100.311"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/100.311/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/100.311/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/100.311/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/100.311/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_100_311">
        <num>100.311</num>
        <content>
          <p>Any city or county may prepare and adopt a program and budget for capital improvements which the planning commission may recommend. The long-term capital improvements program shall list, in priority order of need, all of the public facility improvements proposed on the comprehensive plans for the entire time period covered thereby. The short-term capital improvements budget shall include those capital improvements which are programmed for the first five (5) or six (6) years, shall show estimates of cost, where applicable, for land acquisition, planning and design, construction and equipment, and all other necessary capital outlays, and shall relate such capital improvements costs to over-all city or county governmental costs by projecting revenues and expenditures for the five (5) or six (6) year period on a year by year basis. The resulting short-term capital improvements budget will assure the ability of the city or county to meet its capital needs without impairment to its operating needs. The first year of the short-term capital improvements budget shall automatically become part of that year’s current operating budget, at which time the short-term capital improvements budget shall be revised and another year added. For purpose of year to year budget revision and updating, the long-term capital improvements program may be reviewed and revised at any time in keeping with the review and revision of the comprehensive plans. Nothing herein shall prevent any city or county from preparing and adopting a public facility improvement program in the absence of a proposed public improvements map regulation.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
