<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/70.540"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/70.540"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/70.540/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/70.540/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/70.540/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/70.540/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_70_540">
        <num>70.540</num>
        <content>
          <p>The county judges/executive of the respective counties shall have and are hereby given the power, jurisdiction and authority to establish, appoint and maintain a county police force within their respective counties, all of the members and officers of which shall have and are hereby given jurisdiction coextensive with the whole county for which they are appointed. Such police force may consist of a chief and such member, rank and grade subordinate to the chief, and such clerical and skilled employees as the county judge/executive shall deem proper. All of the members and employees of the county police force shall be appointed by the county judge/executive and shall serve for a term of one (1) year from the date of their respective appointments, unless sooner removed by the county judge/executive for neglect of duty or improper conduct. All members of the force shall be citizens of the United States not less than twenty-one (21) years of age and residents of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. None but discreet and sober persons shall be appointed to any position on said county police force. Each of the members of the said county police force shall take an oath, before the county judge/executive of their county, to faithfully, impartially and diligently perform the duties of their respective offices. Provided, however, that the chief officer of the county police force of any county may be designated, in the discretion of the county judge/executive of said county, as captain or any other appropriate title, and such county police force in any county may consist of one (1) or more commanding officers, as the county judge/executive of such county may deem proper or adequate.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
