<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/74.460"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/74.460"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/74.460/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/74.460/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/74.460/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/74.460/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_74_460">
        <num>74.460</num>
        <content>
          <p>The commission shall organize by appointing a chairman from its own members and a secretary and a treasurer, who need not be commissioners. The secretary shall keep a record of all proceedings of the commission which shall be available for inspection as other public records. The treasurer shall be the lawful custodian of all funds of the commission and shall pay same out on orders authorized or approved by the commission. The secretary and treasurer shall perform other duties appertaining to the affairs of the commission and shall receive the salaries prescribed by the commission, and either or both may be required to furnish bonds in sums to be fixed by the commission for the use and benefit of the commission. The commission shall adopt its own rules of procedure and provide for its meetings. The commission shall have full and complete supervision, management, and control of the sources of supply of water as provided in the ordinances or resolutions for acquiring and operating them, and in their maintenance, operation, and extension. The commission may contract with cities, water associations, water districts, or federal agencies which are represented by the commission for furnishing a supply of water to the parties for a period not exceeding fifty (50) years and the governing bodies of the cities, water associations, water districts, or federal agencies may enter into the contracts with the commission. For the purpose of acquiring all or any part of its sources of supply of water, the commission may purchase from cities, water associations, water districts, or federal agencies which are represented by the commission for mutually agreed terms without regard to actual value any sources of supply of water separate and apart from the water distribution systems of the parties; and the cities, water associations, water districts, or federal agencies may convey the sources of supply of water to the commission without any election or voter approval notwithstanding any provision of any other law to the contrary. If any city, water association, or water district has outstanding any obligations which by their terms are in any manner payable from the revenues of their waterworks distribution system, the proceeds received from any conveyance shall be sufficient to retire all of the outstanding obligations, including all interest accrued and to accrue thereon to the date of retirement thereof; and the proceeds when received shall be set aside in a special fund and used for that purpose. The commission may appoint or contract for the services of officers, agents, and employees, including engineers, attorneys, accountants, fiscal agents, and other professional persons, prescribe their duties, and fix their compensation.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
