<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/76.175"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/76.175"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/76.175/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/76.175/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/76.175/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/76.175/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_76_175">
        <num>76.175</num>
        <content>
          <p>The board of the district may annex any unincorporated area in the county, or any area of the county containing all or any part of a city with a population of less than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census located within a county containing a consolidated local government, whether contiguous or noncontiguous, to the district by making a preliminary order describing the area to be annexed and causing said order to be published pursuant to KRS . The notice so published shall state that objections in writing to the proposed annexation may be filed with the district within thirty (30) days of the date of said notice. The district shall examine and hear all such complaints. It may modify or amend the areas proposed to be annexed; and it shall make a final order, within sixty (60) days of the date of publication of said notice, describing the area or areas to be annexed and shall cause the same to be published pursuant to KRS . Within sixty (60) days after final publication of an order made pursuant to this section, any freeholder of land within the area or areas proposed to be annexed may appeal such final order to the Circuit Court for the county in which the district is located. All matters appealed shall be tried as an equitable action. Decisions of the Circuit Court may be appealed to the Court of Appeals.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
