<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/78.460"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/78.460"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/78.460/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/78.460/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/78.460/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/78.460/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_78_460">
        <num>78.460</num>
        <content>
          <p>Procedural due process shall be afforded to all police officers by the board. The board shall inform any officer, promptly and in writing, of any charges brought against the officer by the board. The officer shall be given a prompt hearing by the board, have an opportunity to confront his accusers, and have the privilege of presenting the board with evidence. The board shall have the power to issue subpoenas attested in the name of its chairman, to compel the attendance of witnesses, to compel the production of documents and other documentary evidence, and so far as practicable, conduct the hearing within the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure. Upon a showing of proper need, the board shall issue subpoenas to compel the attendance of witnesses, or to compel the production of documents and other documentary evidence for the benefit of the officer or the chief at the request of the officer or the chief. Any officer who is not given a hearing within sixty (60) days of any charge placed shall be reinstated in full.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
