<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.570"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.570"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.570/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.570/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.570/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.570/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_83_570">
        <num>83.570</num>
        <content>
          <p>The board of aldermen may establish such executive departments by ordinance as it deems necessary and proper for the efficient administration of governmental matters of the city. The board of aldermen shall designate the duties and powers of departments so established by ordinance and may transfer to any such department duties and powers which it may have previously assigned to another department. Each department shall be under the supervision and direction of a director appointed by the mayor and said directors of any departments so appointed shall be removable at any time at the pleasure of the mayor so appointing them, or any of his successors in office, but not by any officer who may merely for the time be filling the office of mayor in the absence or during the temporary disability of the regularly elected or appointed mayor. The directors of said departments shall have the same qualifications as members of the legislative body of the city and shall be selected for their special fitness for the work of the departments, and shall devote their entire time to the discharge of their duties and shall receive adequate compensation fixed by ordinance. No member of the legislative body shall be eligible to appointment as director of any department. Directors shall hold office until they resign or are removed as herein provided.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
