<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.520"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.520"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.520/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.520/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.520/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/83.520/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_83_520">
        <num>83.520</num>
        <content>
          <p>The legislative body of a city of the first class shall have the power to exercise all of the rights, privileges, powers, franchises, including the power to levy all taxes, not in conflict with the Constitution and so as to provide for the health, education, safety and welfare of the inhabitants of the city, to the same extent and with the same force and effect as if the General Assembly had granted and delegated to the legislative body of the city all of the authority and powers that are within its powers to grant to a municipal corporation as if expressly enumerated herein. Nothing therein contained to the contrary, the provisions of KRS Chapters 65, 66, 76, 77, 79, 80, 91, 95, 96, 97, 98, 99, 103, 104, 106, 107, 108 and 109 shall be considered permissive rather than mandatory and the powers, rights and duties therein delineated may be modified or delegated by the legislative body to different departments and agencies of city government and any restrictions therein set forth shall not be considered abridging in any manner the complete grant of home rule set forth in this grant of power except no right heretofore vested by operation of statute shall in any way be affected.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
