<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/95.764"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/95.764"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/95.764/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/95.764/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/95.764/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/95.764/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_95_764">
        <num>95.764</num>
        <content>
          <p>The civil service commission shall conduct an examination of persons for appointment as members of the police and fire departments each time a vacancy shall occur in said departments. The mayor shall notify the commissioners each time a vacancy occurs in either of said departments and the commissioners shall within the two (2) weeks following the receipt of such notice hold an examination for persons seeking appointment to such vacancy after giving notice by publication pursuant to KRS . Within one (1) week following the holding of said examination, said commissioners shall certify to the legislative body the names of the three (3) persons receiving the highest grades. The legislative body may appoint any one (1) of said three (3) persons to said department. In the event a vacancy thereafter occurs in said department, or additions thereto of regular or substitute policemen or firefighters are made, within one (1) year following the certification of said names, the legislative body shall fill said vacancy or make such additions from the list of names certified. The commissioners shall make all rules and regulations for the proper conduct of their office. The civil service commissioners shall receive a salary each of one dollar ($1) per annum, paid out of the city’s general fund, and for their services and the expense of holding any one (1) examination by the commissioners after due notice by the mayor has been given to the chairman of the said commission that a vacancy occurs in either of said departments and after the eligible list has been exhausted, shall be paid by the legislative body out of the city’s general fund, not to exceed ten dollars ($10).</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
