<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.174"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.174"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.174/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.174/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.174/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.174/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_174">
        <num>96.174</num>
        <content>
          <p>A majority of the board shall constitute a quorum and the board shall act by vote of a majority present at any meeting attended by a quorum. Vacancies in the board shall not affect its power or authority so long as a quorum remains. Within ten (10) days after appointment and qualification of members, the board shall hold a meeting and elect a chairman. The board shall at the same time elect a secretary-treasurer, and shall fix his compensation, which, together with his compensation as a member of the board, shall not exceed one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500) per annum. The secretary may be removed by the board for cause. The board shall hold public meetings at least once each month, at such regular time and place as the board may determine. Any special meeting of the board may be called by the chairman or by two (2) members; but if such special meeting is called, written notice shall be sent to all members by the secretary. Except as otherwise expressly provided in  to  the board shall establish its own bylaws and rules of procedure.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
