<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.250"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.250"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.250/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.250/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.250/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.250/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_250">
        <num>96.250</num>
        <content>
          <p>The board of waterworks shall annually elect a president, treasurer, secretary and chief engineer, who shall hold their offices for one (1) year, or until their successors have been elected and qualified, and devote all their time to the duties of their respective offices. The member elected president shall have had at least five (5) years executive or major administrative experience in public utility operation or administration. The offices of secretary and treasurer may at the election of the board, be combined in one (1) person. No member of the board except the president shall receive a salary, but the board may allow reasonable compensation to each member other than the president for attendance upon the meetings of the board. The president shall be elected from the members of the board. The president, secretary and treasurer, or the secretary-treasurer if the offices are combined in one (1) person, shall each give bond, with approved surety, in an amount fixed by the board, payable to the board and conditioned that the makers will faithfully perform the duties of their several offices. The board may appoint such other employees as it deems necessary or proper and may fix the compensation of its officers and employees, provided, however, the board shall not be bound in fixing the compensation or providing for retirement benefits by the provisions of  and</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
