<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.320"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.320"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.320/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.320/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.320/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/96.320/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_96_320">
        <num>96.320</num>
        <content>
          <p>Cities that own a waterworks may operate such waterworks as a department of the city, or may appoint a commission to operate such waterworks. If such a commission is appointed, it may be styled “Commissioners of Waterworks,” and shall be composed of from three (3) to six (6) members to be appointed by the mayor, subject to the approval of the city legislative body. If a commission is composed of six (6) members, the mayor shall appoint, in addition to the six (6) members, a member of the legislative body of the city who shall be an ex officio member of the commission. All commissioners shall reside in the area served by the waterworks and be registered voters in the county. A majority of the commissioners shall be residents of the city. The terms of the members shall be fixed by the city legislative body, or they may be appointed for indefinite terms, subject to removal by the city legislative body for cause. The commissioners shall give bond for the faithful performance of their duties in the sum of five thousand dollars ($5,000). The commissioners shall manage the water system of the city. They may appoint a superintendent, secretary, treasurer and other necessary employees and fix their salaries. They shall make full monthly reports to the city legislative body of the operation and condition of the water system, including all receipts and expenditures. A majority of the members of the board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
