<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/98.310"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/98.310"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/98.310/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/98.310/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/98.310/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/98.310/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_98_310">
        <num>98.310</num>
        <content>
          <p>The director shall be appointed by the fiscal court except in those counties containing a consolidated local government, in which case the director shall be appointed by the mayor. The director shall be trained and experienced in public welfare administration. Subject to rules and regulations approved by the fiscal court or the consolidated local government, respectively, the director shall have full charge of the department, with power to employ and dismiss employees subject to the limitations of . The director shall prepare for submission to and approval of the fiscal court or the consolidated local government, respectively, an annual budget, authorize expenditures in conformity with the budget, and prepare an annual report of the activities and expenditures of the department for submission to the fiscal court or the consolidated local government, respectively. Before entering upon the discharge of his or her duties, the director shall give a bond approved by the fiscal court or the consolidated local government, respectively, and the fiscal court or the consolidated local government, respectively, may, in its discretion, require bonds for other employees within the department.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
