<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.230"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.230"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.230/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.230/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.230/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.230/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_99_230">
        <num>99.230</num>
        <content>
          <p>Before condemnation proceedings for a redevelopment corporation shall be instituted the redevelopment corporation shall make written request to the mayor of the city to cause the city to institute proceedings to acquire for the redevelopment corporation any real property in the development area. Such request shall be granted or rejected by the city through action of its local legislative body, and the ordinance granting such request shall contain a requirement that the redevelopment corporation shall pay to the city all sums expended or required to be expended by the city in the acquisition of such real property, and the time of payment and manner of securing payment thereof, and may require that the city shall receive, before proceeding with the acquisition of such real property, such assurances as to payment or reimbursement thereof by the redevelopment corporation, or otherwise, as the city may deem advisable. Upon the passage of such ordinance by the local legislative body, granting the petition, the redevelopment corporation shall cause to be made three (3) copies of surveys or maps of the real property described in the petition, one (1) of which shall be filed in the office of the redevelopment corporation, one (1) in the office of the chief law officer of the city, and one (1) in the office in which instruments affecting real property in the county are recorded. The filing of such copies of surveys or maps shall constitute the acceptance by the redevelopment corporation of the terms and conditions contained in such ordinance. Proceedings for such condemnation shall be conducted in the Circuit Court of the county in which the property lies, and shall be conducted in the name of such city by the city attorney, and the judgment of the court shall vest fee simple title to the property condemned in the city. In all other respects and except as herein specifically provided, the form and manner of the proceedings shall be the same as that provided for the condemnation of property for park purposes in such city. When title to the real property shall have vested in the city, it shall for use in such redevelopment convey the same to the redevelopment corporation upon payment by the redevelopment corporation of the sums and the giving of the security required by the ordinance granting the request. As soon as title shall have vested in the city, the redevelopment corporation may, upon the authorization of the local legislative body, enter upon the real property taken, take over and dispose of existing improvements, and carry out the terms of the development plan with respect thereto.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
