<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.625"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.625"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.625/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.625/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.625/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/99.625/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_99_625">
        <num>99.625</num>
        <content>
          <p>Upon the date of the creation of the development authority, or within a reasonable time thereafter, the mayor shall appoint, with the approval of a majority of the governing board as aforesaid, seven (7) citizens of the city as members of the agency, each of whom shall bear the title of commissioner and shall constitute, with the other commissioners, a board of commissioners of said agency. The commissioners initially designated shall serve one (1) for a term of one (1) year, two (2) for a term of two (2) years, two (2) for a term of three (3) years, and two (2) for a term of four (4) years, from January 1, 1974, the length of said terms to be noted by the mayor in the written document making each of said appointments. Thereafter members shall be appointed as aforesaid for a term of office of four (4) years, except that all vacancies occurring during a term shall be filled for the unexpired term. A commissioner shall hold office until his successor has been appointed and qualified. The mayor or his designee shall be an ex officio nonvoting member of the agency. Commissioners shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for any actual and necessary expenses incurred by them in the conduct of the affairs of the agency.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
