<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/212.470"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/212.470"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/212.470/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/212.470/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/212.470/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/212.470/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_212_470">
        <num>212.470</num>
        <content>
          <p>In order to provide sufficient funds for carrying out the purposes of  to  the fiscal court of the county shall annually appropriate money from the general fund of the county and the legislative body of the city shall annually appropriate money from the general fund of the city. The appropriations shall be made by the county and the city in such amounts, in such proportion and upon such terms as the fiscal court and the legislative body may agree and provide. Moneys so appropriated may be paid over to the board in regular monthly installments. In the event the sums derived from said appropriations, together with funds otherwise available from any other source to the board during any fiscal year, for its necessary expenditures in the maintenance and operation of said board, exceed its need for such expenditures during such fiscal year, any such unexpended funds at the end of such fiscal year shall be carried forward by the board to be used in paying for its operating costs and expenses for the ensuing year. The board of education in the city and the board of education in the county may make payments to the board for school health services provided by the board for children of school age, resident in the city and the county respectively, which shall not be in excess of the cost thereof.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
