<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/219.350"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/219.350"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/219.350/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/219.350/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/219.350/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/219.350/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_219_350">
        <num>219.350</num>
        <content>
          <p>No community shall be constructed or altered without a permit as provided in  to  An application for a permit to construct or alter a community shall be made to the cabinet upon forms provided by it. The application shall include plans for construction or alteration of the community and shall contain such information in regard to the proposed community as the cabinet may reasonably require, which may include affirmative evidence of ability to comply with requirements of  to and regulations adopted by the secretary. All plans for the construction, installation, or alteration of buildings shall be forwarded by the cabinet to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction. Only the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction shall review such plans for conformance with the Uniform State Building Code. The Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction shall expedite the review of such plans and return them to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for completion of the application process. Each application for a permit to construct or alter a community shall be accompanied by a permit fee of forty-seven dollars ($47). The cabinet may, by administrative regulation, increase this fee by no more than five percent (5%) per year, not to exceed a maximum fee of seventy dollars ($70). Each permit to construct shall be issued only for the person and premises, including the number of spaces named in the application and shall not be transferable. Each permit to construct shall expire one (1) year from date of issuance.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
