<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/42.545"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/42.545"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/42.545/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/42.545/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/42.545/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/42.545/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_42_545">
        <num>42.545</num>
        <content>
          <p>Each agency authorized to issue bonds listed in this section shall make a report according to generally accepted accounting principles of all money received and disbursed during each fiscal year, on or before the fifteenth of July, showing the receipts, expenditures, trustees, depositories, rates of interest paid by depositories, investments, and rates of return on investments by each agency to the Office of the Controller. The agencies required to report under this section are Eastern Kentucky University; Kentucky State University; Morehead State University; Murray State University; Northern Kentucky University; University of Kentucky; University of Louisville; Western Kentucky University; Kentucky Community and Technical College System; Kentucky Housing Corporation; Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation; Kentucky School Building Authority; the Turnpike Authority of Kentucky; the State Property and Buildings Commission; Churchill Downs Authority; State Fair Board; Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources; Water Resources Authority of Kentucky; and any other agency or instrumentality authorized to issue bonds.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
