<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/45.816"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/45.816"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/45.816/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/45.816/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/45.816/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/45.816/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_45_816">
        <num>45.816</num>
        <content>
          <p>Prior to the issuance of the revenue bonds or notes, the agency authorized to issue the bonds or notes shall furnish to the Capital Projects and Bond Oversight Committee and the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue, and make available to the public, a listing of all costs associated, either directly or indirectly, with the issuance of the revenue bonds or notes. The costs shall be itemized as to amount and name of payee, and shall include fees or commissions paid to, or anticipated to be paid to, issuers, underwriters, placement agents and advisors, financial advisors, remarketing agents, credit enhancers, trustees, accountants, and the counsel of all such persons, bond counsel and special tax counsel, and shall include the economic benefits received or anticipated to be received by any other persons from any source in return for services performed relating to the issuance of the bonds or notes. Changes in amounts or names of payees or recipients, or additions of amounts or names of payees or recipients, to the listing furnished and made available pursuant to this section, shall be furnished to the Capital Projects and Bond Oversight Committee and the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue and made available to the public within three (3) days following the change.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
