<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.883"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.883"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.883/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.883/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.883/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.883/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_381_883">
        <num>381.883</num>
        <content>
          <p>All sums assessed by the council of co-owners but unpaid for the unit’s share of the common expenses constitute a lien on such unit prior to all other liens, except only (1) liens for taxes and assessments lawfully imposed by governmental authority against such unit, and (2) all sums unpaid on first mortgages of record. Such lien may be enforced by suit by the administrator or board of administration, acting on behalf of the unit owners, in like manner as a mortgage of real property. In any such enforcement action the unit owner shall be required to pay a reasonable rental for the unit, if so provided in the bylaws, and the plaintiff in such enforcement action shall be entitled to the appointment of a receiver to collect the same. The administrator or board of administration, acting on behalf of the unit owners, shall have power, unless prohibited by the declaration, to bid in the unit at court sale, and to acquire and hold, lease, mortgage and convey the same. Suit to recover a money judgment for unpaid common expenses of an owner shall be maintainable without lien enforcement or waiving the lien securing the same.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
