<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.740"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.740"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.740/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.740/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.740/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/381.740/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_381_740">
        <num>381.740</num>
        <content>
          <p>Within thirty (30) days after the last advertisement, any party having a claim to the cemetery or any lot therein or to the mortal remains of a person interred therein, may file his claim in the said proceeding for damages as compensation for the value of his interest in the cemetery or lot to which he has claim. Upon the filing of the aforesaid claim the circuit court shall appoint as commissioners three (3) impartial housekeepers who are owners of land. They shall be sworn to faithfully and impartially discharge their duties. The commissioners shall view the land involved and they may hear evidence or make any inquiry they desire touching the value thereof and award to the claimants who are owners thereof the value of the property taken. They shall return a written report to the office of the clerk of the circuit court describing separately the property which is the subject of each claim. Either the claimant or the complainant may file exceptions to this report and demand a jury trial. The commissioners shall be allowed a reasonable fee which shall be taxed as cost.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
