<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/146.290"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/146.290"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/146.290/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/146.290/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/146.290/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/146.290/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_146_290">
        <num>146.290</num>
        <content>
          <p>New roads, structures or buildings may be constructed only where necessary to effect a use permitted under the other provisions of  to  Utility lines or pipelines may be constructed as approved by the office in writing and under provision that the affected land be restored as nearly as possible to its former state. This provision, however, shall in no way affect the rights between a landowner and a utility company or pipeline company. There shall be no strip mining as defined in , and select cutting of timber or other resource removal and agricultural use, may be allowed pursuant to regulations promulgated by the secretary upon the granting of a permit under the other provisions of  to  All instream disturbances such as dredging, shall be prohibited. Except for the management agency and any existing uses which do not conform to the purposes and intent of  to  travel upon a wild river or any public lands within the designated boundaries thereof, shall be by foot, horseback, canoe, boat or other nonmechanical modes of transportation. If there are existing agricultural areas within the boundaries of the area, such areas may continue to be used for agricultural purposes.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
