<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/149.160"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/149.160"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/149.160/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/149.160/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/149.160/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/149.160/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_149_160">
        <num>149.160</num>
        <content>
          <p>When the Energy and Environment Cabinet determines that a danger of forest fire exists in a county in which the statewide system of forest fire protection has been established under  to  the cabinet shall respond to the forest fire danger and employ those persons and means as, in its judgment, are expedient and necessary to respond to the forest fire danger or to extinguish the fire, within the limits of the expense that it has been authorized to incur in its instructions from the secretary for energy and environment. The cabinet shall keep an itemized account of all expenses thus incurred and immediately send the account verified by affidavit to the secretary for energy and environment for examination. Upon approval by the secretary for energy and environment, the account shall be paid from such fund or funds as are available to the cabinet for such purpose. No such payment shall be made to any person who has intentionally started the fire or to any person whose negligence caused or contributed to the setting of the fire.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
