<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/150.620"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/150.620"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/150.620/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/150.620/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/150.620/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/150.620/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_150_620">
        <num>150.620</num>
        <content>
          <p>For the purpose of encouraging and developing public interest in wildlife and carrying out the policy of the Commonwealth of Kentucky under KRS , the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources Commission, as a state agency, and based upon investigations and recommendations of the commission, is hereby authorized to acquire lands including any improvements thereon by purchase, condemnation or lease from the State Property and Buildings Commission or from others, and partly by any or all of such means, and to thereafter establish, improve, maintain, and operate public shooting and fishing grounds and similar or related recreational facilities thereon, and for the purpose of paying the cost of any such purchase or condemnation and the maintenance and operation expenses may use and apply any funds available for that purpose. The payments under each such lease shall be deemed an administrative and operating expense of the department, and such payments may be secured by a pledge of and made from all or any part of the funds coming under the control of the department including the game and fish fund, as may be provided and specified in the lease. The commissioner, with the approval of the commission may sublease any lands and improvements thereon acquired under the provisions of this chapter for agricultural and for any purpose deemed by the commission to be incidental or beneficial to the maintenance and operation of the balance of said lands and improvements for the purpose herein stated. The commission may impose and enforce special regulations in the maintenance and operation of the facilities and lands acquired under the provisions of this section or lands that are managed by the department under a cooperative agreement and charge such rates as may be deemed fair and reasonable for the use of and participation of the public in the facilities and lands and lease payments aforesaid may be made a first charge on the income and revenues from the maintenance and operation of the facilities and lands and from the sublease of any portion thereof, to be supplemented with any other funds available for that purpose.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
