<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/151.140"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/151.140"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/151.140/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/151.140/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/151.140/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/151.140/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_151_140">
        <num>151.140</num>
        <content>
          <p>No person, business, industry, city, county, water district, or other political subdivision shall have the right to withdraw, divert, or transfer public water from a stream, lake, ground water source or other body of water, unless such person, business, industry, city, county, water district or other political subdivision has been granted a permit by the cabinet for such withdrawal, diversion, or transfer of water. Provided, however, no permit shall be required for and nothing herein shall interfere with the use of water for agricultural and domestic purposes including irrigation; and no permit shall be required if the amount of water withdrawn, diverted or transferred is less than the amount established by regulation and no permit shall be required for water used in the production of steam generating plants of companies whose retail rates are regulated by the Kentucky Public Service Commission or for which plants a certificate of environmental compatibility from such commission is required by law, or water injected underground in conjunction with operations for the production of oil or gas.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
