<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/177.460"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/177.460"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/177.460/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/177.460/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/177.460/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/177.460/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_177_460">
        <num>177.460</num>
        <content>
          <p>In the discretion of the department, any bonds issued under the provisions of  to may be secured by a trust agreement by and between the department and a corporate trustee, which may be any trust company or bank having the powers of a trust company within or without the Commonwealth. Such trust agreement or the proceedings providing for the issuance of such bonds may pledge or assign the tolls and other revenues to be received, but shall not convey or mortgage any turnpike project or any part thereof. Such trust agreement or proceedings providing for the issuance of such bonds may contain such provisions for protecting and enforcing the rights and remedies of the bondholders as may be reasonable and proper and not in violation of law, including covenants setting forth the duties of the department in relation to the acquisition of property and the construction, improvement, maintenance, repair, operation and insurance of the turnpike project or projects in connection with which such bonds shall have been authorized, the rates of toll to be charged, and the custody, safeguarding and application of all moneys. It shall be lawful for any bank or trust company incorporated under the laws of the Commonwealth which may act as depository of the proceeds of bonds or of revenues to furnish such indemnifying bonds or to pledge such securities as may be required by the department. Any such trust agreement may set forth the rights and remedies of the bondholders and of the trustee, and may restrict the individual right of action by bondholders. In addition to the foregoing, any such trust agreement or proceedings may contain such other provisions as the department may deem reasonable and proper for the security of the bondholders. All expenses incurred in carrying out the provisions of such trust agreement or proceedings may be treated as a part of the cost of the operation of the turnpike project or projects.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
