<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/183.740"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/183.740"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/183.740/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/183.740/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/183.740/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/183.740/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_183_740">
        <num>183.740</num>
        <content>
          <p>to shall constitute a method for the acquisition, construction, maintenance, expansion, financing or improvement of air navigation facilities or airport facilities or any part thereof or interest therein, or contract for services therefrom, by governmental units or the Commonwealth in addition or as an alternate, to any other method authorized by statute. It is intended to authorize the acquisition, construction, maintenance, expansion, financing, or improvement of additional facilities for an airport acquired under authority of  or interest therein, or contract for services therefrom, as well as the original acquisition, construction, maintenance, expansion, financing, or improvement of land and other facilities for an airport. Governmental units shall have all authority conferred by  for the acquisition, construction, maintenance, expansion, financing or improvement of air navigation facilities or airport facilities, or any part thereof or interest therein, or contract for services therefrom. Except as otherwise provided in  to  the provisions of  to shall apply to the operation of airport facilities acquired under  to</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
