<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/156.076"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/156.076"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/156.076/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/156.076/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/156.076/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/156.076/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_156_076">
        <num>156.076</num>
        <content>
          <p>The chief state school officer shall furnish full information on established price contracts to each district board of education. Any board of education may purchase supplies and equipment from the vendor to whom the contract has been awarded, under the terms of the contract. Any board of education may advertise for its own bids on supplies and equipment which meet the specifications of the contracts awarded by the Office of Material and Procurement Services in the Office of the Controller. Any board of education, after advertising for bids, may award contracts if the chief state school officer certifies that the bid offers supplies and equipment which meet the standards and specifications fixed by the Kentucky Board of Education and that the bid price is lower than that established by the price contract agreement. If supplies and equipment that meet the specifications of the contracts awarded by the Office of Material and Procurement Services or a federal, local, or cooperative agency are available for purchase elsewhere, a board of education may purchase those supplies and equipment without advertising for bids. However, prior to making the purchases, the board of education shall obtain certification from:</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
