<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/159.130"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/159.130"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/159.130/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/159.130/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/159.130/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/159.130/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_159_130">
        <num>159.130</num>
        <content>
          <p>The director of pupil personnel and his assistants shall be vested with the powers of peace officers, provided, however, that they shall not have the authority to serve warrants. They may investigate in their district any case of nonattendance at school of any child of compulsory school age or suspected of being of that age. They may take such action in accordance with law as the superintendent directs. They may under the direction of the superintendent of schools and the board of education or the Kentucky Board of Education, institute proceedings against any person violating any provisions of the laws relating to compulsory attendance and the employment of children. They may enter all places where children are employed and do whatever is necessary to enforce the laws relating to compulsory attendance and employment of children of compulsory school age. No person shall refuse to permit or in any way interfere with the entrance therein of a director of pupil personnel or in any way interfere with any investigation therein.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
