<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/161.048"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/161.048"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/161.048/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/161.048/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/161.048/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/161.048/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_161_048">
        <num>161.048</num>
        <content>
          <p>The candidate shall participate in the teacher internship program under . After successful completion of the internship program, the candidate shall receive a professional certificate and shall be subject to certificate renewal requirements the same as other teachers with a professional certificate.</p>
          <p>Upon meeting the participation requirements as established in this subsection, the candidate shall be issued a one (1) year provisional certificate by the Education Professional Standards Board. The candidate shall participate in the teacher internship program under . After successful completion of the internship program, the candidate shall receive a professional certificate and shall be subject to certificate renewal requirements the same as other teachers with a professional certificate.</p>
          <p>The candidate shall participate in the teacher internship program under . After successful completion of the internship program, the candidate shall receive a professional certificate and shall be subject to certificate renewal requirements the same as other teachers with professional certificates.</p>
          <p>Upon an offer of employment by a school district, the eligible veteran shall receive a one (1) year provisional certificate with approval by the Education Professional Standards Board of a joint application by the veteran and the employing school district. During this year, the veteran shall participate in the teacher internship program under . After successful completion of the internship program, the veteran shall receive a professional certificate.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
