<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#publicresource">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/162.620"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/162.620"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ky-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ky"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/162.620/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/162.620/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#publicresource"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ky/act/krs/162.620/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ky/act/krs/162.620/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ky-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ky/legislature" showAs="Kentucky General Assembly"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="publicresource" href="https://public.resource.org" showAs="Public.Resource.Org"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <section eId="sec_162_620">
        <num>162.620</num>
        <content>
          <p>Bonds of the authority shall be sold only upon the basis of sealed bids or proposals, publicly solicited, received, opened and acted upon. The “publication area,” as that term is used in KRS , shall not be deemed to be the area within which the office of the authority is situated, but shall be deemed to be the “publication area” of the board of education executing the lease. Each sale shall be publicly advertised by means of a notice conforming to the provisions of , and the same shall be published at least one (1) time, at least seven (7) days in advance of the date set forth for opening bids, in a daily newspaper having bona fide general circulation throughout the Commonwealth. If such publication is made, it shall be sufficient for publication in the “publication area” to be made only one (1) time, at least seven (7) days in advance of the date set forth for the opening of bids, notwithstanding provisions for publication more often as provided in KRS . If a copy of the sale notice be delivered or transmitted in good faith to the qualified newspaper of the “publication area” in time for publication in an issue thereof published seven (7) days or more in advance of the date set forth for the opening of bids, and with direction for publication therein, any failure of such newspaper to make publication as directed shall not invalidate the sale of the bonds by the authority on the designated date, nor require postponement or cancellation thereof.</p>
        </content>
      </section>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
